<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0376-en" n="31994D0376" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0376 English</title>
        <title>94/376/EC: Commission Decision of 30 May 1994 amending Decision No 85/377/EEC establishing a Community typology for agricultural holdings</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>48 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0376:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0376:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0376-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/376/EC: Commission Decision of 30 May 1994 amending Decision No 85/377/EEC establishing a Community typology for agricultural holdings</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 30 May 1994 amending Decision No 85/377/EEC establishing a Community typology for agricultural holdings (94/376/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation No 79/65/EEC of 15 June 1965 setting up a network for the collection of accountancy data on the incomes and business operation of agricultural holdings in the European Economic Community (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3577/90 (2), and in particular Article 4 (4) and Article 11 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Community typology of agricultural holdings set up by Commission Decision No 85/377/EEC (3), and in particular the standard gross margins, is the basis for the classification of agricultural holdings by economic size and type of farming both in the farm structure surveys and under the Farm Accountancy Data Network (FADN); whereas the Community typology is also the basis for calculating the European size units (ESU) and the thresholds used to delimit the field of observation and to draw up the plan for selecting the returning holdings included or to be included in the FADN;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the results of the farm structure surveys, classified by ESU and type of farming serve as a decision-making basis for farm structure policy under the common agricultural policy and for defining the field of observation of the FADN, which serves as a basis for selecting and weighting the FADN farm sample; whereas the selection of returning holdings for the field of observation must be representative in terms of the objectives of each of the analyses planned;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Council Regulation (EEC) No 571/88 (4), as last amended by Commission Decision No 93/156/EEC (5), provides for a series of surveys on the structure of agricultural holdings from 1988 to 1997 and lists the characteristics to be surveyed;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Article 11 of Commission Decision No 85/377/EEC states that the Commission, assisted by the Member States, shall review at least every 10 years the experience gained in applying the Decision and any new Community needs arising in the field; whereas after such review, the provisions of the Decision may be amended as required;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the structure and content of the list of survey characteristics for 1988 to 1997 have been amended, so that the characteristics in the new list differ from those recorded in the previous surveys; whereas the Community typology of agricultural holdings depends on that list and it is therefore necessary to adapt Decision No 85/377/EEC to the lists of survey characteristics laid down by Regulation (EEC) No 571/88;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Community Committee for the Farm Accountancy Data Network and with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Annexes II and III to Decision No 85/377/EEC are amended in accordance with Annexes I and II thereto.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Decision applies as from 1988.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 3</p>
      <p n="18">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 30 May 1994.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Henning CHRISTOPHERSEN</p>
      <p n="22">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No 109, 23. 6. 1965, p. 1859/65.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ No L 353, 17. 12. 1990, p. 23.</p>
      <p n="25">(3) OJ No L 220, 17. 8. 1985, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(4) OJ No L 56, 2. 3. 1988, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="27">(5) OJ No L 65, 17. 3. 1993, p. 12.</p>
      <p n="28">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="29">Annex II to Decision No 85/377/EEC is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="30">1. In part B (definition of types),</p>
      <p n="31">- point (a) and the corresponding footnote are replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="32">'(a) The nature of the enterprises concerned</p>
      <p n="33">These enterprises refer to the list of characteristics surveyed in the surveys on the structure of agricultural holdings. They are indicated by the codes set out in Annex I to Regulation (EEC) No 807/89 or by codes covering a number of these characteristics as given in part C of this Annex (1).</p>
      <p n="34">(1) Characteristics D12 (Forage roots and tubers), D18 (Forage plants), D21 (Fallow land), E (Kitchen gardens), F01 (Permanent pasture and meadows, excluding rough grazing), F02 (rough grazing) and J11 (Piglets) are used only under certain conditions (see point 5 of Annex I).'</p>
      <p n="35">- in the column headed 'Code of characteristics and thresholds',</p>
      <p n="36">- the formula 'G01a &gt; 2/3' referring to the definition of the particular type of farming regarding 3211 - Specialist fresh fruit (other than citrus) is replaced by the formula 'G01a + G01b &gt; 2/3'</p>
      <p n="37">and</p>
      <p n="38">- the formula 'G01b &gt; 2/3' referring to the definition of the particular type of farming regarding 3212 - Specialist nuts is replaced by the formula 'G01c &gt; 2/3'.</p>
      <p n="39">2. In part C, section I, (Codes regrouping several characteristics included in the 1985 and 1987 structure surveys),</p>
      <p n="40">- in code P1, the words 'non-fodder' are deleted in the I01 (successive secondary non-fodder crops) characteristics,</p>
      <p n="41">and</p>
      <p n="42">- in code P1, the words '+ I06a (fallow land, with rotation possibilities) + 106b (permanent pasture and meadow used as grazing for extensive livestock farmers) + 106c (lentils, chick pass and vetches)' are added.</p>
      <p n="43">3. In part C, section II, the table is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="44">'II. Correspondence between the headings of the structure surveys and the farm return of the Farm Accountancy Data Network (FADN) "" ID="1.2"&gt;I. Crops" ID="1"&gt;D01 Common wheat and spelt&gt; ID="2"&gt;120. Common wheat and spelt"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D02 Durum wheat&gt; ID="2"&gt;121. Durum wheat"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D03 Rye&gt; ID="2"&gt;122. Rye (including meslin)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D04 Barley&gt; ID="2"&gt;123. Barley"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D05 Oats&gt; ID="2"&gt;124. + 125. Oats"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Summer cereal mixes"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D06 Grain maize&gt; ID="2"&gt;126. Grain maize (including humid grain maize)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D07 Rice&gt; ID="2"&gt;127. Rice"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D08 Other cereals&gt; ID="2"&gt;128. Other cereals "&gt; ID="2"&gt;NoNoNo"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D09 Dried vegetables for the production of grain&gt; ID="2"&gt;129. Dry pulses"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D09a of which as pure crops for fodder:&gt; ID="2"&gt;329. Dry pulses for fodder grown as a single crop:"&gt; ID="1"&gt;peas, broad and field beans, vetches, sweet lupins&gt; ID="2"&gt;peas, field beans, vetches, sweet lupins etc."&gt; ID="1"&gt;D09b Other (as pure or mixed crops)&gt; ID="2"&gt;330. Other protein crops"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D10 Potatoes&gt; ID="2"&gt;130. Potatoes (including early potatoes and seed)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D11 Sugar beet&gt; ID="2"&gt;131. Sugar beet (excluding seed)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D12 Fodder roots and brassicas&gt; ID="2"&gt;144. Fodder roots and brassicas"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D13 Industrial plants (including seeds for herbaceous oil-seed plants; excluding seeds for fibre plants, hops, taobacco and other industrial plants)&gt; ID="2"&gt; "&gt; ID="1"&gt;of which:"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Tobacco&gt; ID="2"&gt;134. Tobacco"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Hops&gt; ID="2"&gt;133. Hops"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(c) Cotton&gt; ID="2"&gt;347. Cotton"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(d) Other oil-seed plants or fibre plants and other industrial plants"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(i) Oil seeds (total) of which:&gt; ID="2"&gt;132. Herbaceous oil seed crops"&gt; ID="1"&gt; Rape and turnip rape&gt; ID="2"&gt;331. Rape"&gt; ID="1"&gt; Sunflower&gt; ID="2"&gt;332. Sunflower"&gt; ID="1"&gt; Soya&gt; ID="2"&gt;333. Soya"&gt; ID="1"&gt; &gt; ID="2"&gt;334. Other"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(ii) Aromatic plants, medicinal and culinary plants&gt; ID="2"&gt;345. Medicinal plants condiments, aromatics and spices, including tea, coffee and coffee chicory"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(iii) Other industrial plants&gt; ID="2"&gt;346. + 348. (Sugar cane"&gt; ID="2"&gt;other industrial plants)"&gt; ID="1"&gt; Sugar cane&gt; ID="2"&gt;346. Sugar cane"&gt; ID="1"&gt; &gt; ID="2"&gt;348. Other industrial plants"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D14 Fresh vegetables, melons, strawberries, outdoor or under low&gt; ID="2"&gt; "&gt; ID="1"&gt;of which"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D14a Fresh vegetables, melons, strawberries: open field&gt; ID="2"&gt;136. Field scale fresh vegetables, melons and strawberries grown in the open"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D14b Fresh vegetables, melons, strawberries: outdoor - market gardening&gt; ID="2"&gt;137. Fresh vegetables, melons, strawberries grown in market gardens in the open"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D15 Fresh vegetables, melons, strawberries: under glass or other (accessible) protective cover&gt; ID="2"&gt;138. Fresh vegetables, melons and strawberries under shelter"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D16 Flowers and ornamental plants (excluding nurseries): outdoor or under low (not accessible) protective cover&gt; ID="2"&gt;140. Flowers and ornamental plants grown in the open (excluding nurseries)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D17 Flowers and ornamental plants (excluding nurseries): under glass or other (accessible) protective cover&gt; ID="2"&gt;141. Flowers and ornamental plants grown under shelter"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D18 Forage plants"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Temporary grass&gt; ID="2"&gt;147. Temporary grass"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Other&gt; ID="2"&gt;145. Other fodder plants"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D19 Arable land seeds and seedlings&gt; ID="2"&gt;142. + 143. Grass seeds"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Other seeds"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D20 Other arable land crops&gt; ID="2"&gt;148. Other arable crops not included"&gt; ID="2"&gt;in headings 120 to 147"&gt; ID="2"&gt;+"&gt; ID="2"&gt;149. Land leased to others ready for sowing, including land made available to employees as a benefit in kind"&gt; ID="1"&gt;D21 Fallow land&gt; ID="2"&gt;146. Fallows (without "set-aside land")"&gt; ID="1"&gt;F01 Permanent pasture and meadows, excluding rough grazing&gt; ID="2"&gt;150. Meadows and permanent pasture"&gt; ID="1"&gt;F02 Rough grazing&gt; ID="2"&gt;151. Rough grazing"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G01 Fruit and berry plantations&gt; ID="2"&gt;152. Fruit and berry orchards"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Fresh fruit and berry species of temperature climate zones&gt; ID="2"&gt;349. + 350. + 352. Pome fruit"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Stone fruit"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Small fruit and berries"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Fruit and berry species of subtropical climate zones&gt; ID="2"&gt;353. Tropical and subtropical fruit"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(c) Nuts&gt; ID="2"&gt;351. Nuts"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G02 Citrus plantations&gt; ID="2"&gt;153. Citrus fruit orchards"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G03 Olive plantations&gt; ID="2"&gt;154. Olive groves"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Normally producing table olives&gt; ID="2"&gt;281. Table olives"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Normally producing olives for oil production&gt; ID="2"&gt;282. + 283. Olives for oil production"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Olive oil"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G04 Vineyards&gt; ID="2"&gt;155. Vines"&gt; ID="1"&gt;of which normally producing:"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Quality wine&gt; ID="2"&gt;286. + 289. Grapes for quality wine"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Quality wine"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Other wines&gt; ID="2"&gt;287. + 288. + 290. Grapes for table wine and wine other than quality wine"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Miscellaneous products of vines: grape must, juice, brandy, Vinegar and others produced on the farm"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Table wine and wine other than quality wine"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(c) Table grapes&gt; ID="2"&gt;285. Table grapes"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(d) Raisins&gt; ID="2"&gt;291. Raisins"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G05 Nurseries&gt; ID="2"&gt;157. Nurseries"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G06 Other permanent crops&gt; ID="2"&gt;158. Other permanent crops"&gt; ID="1"&gt;G07 Permanent crops under glass&gt; ID="2"&gt;156. Permanent crops grown under shelter"&gt; ID="1"&gt;I01 Successive secondary crops (excluding market-garden crops and crops under glass)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;of which:"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Non-fodder cereals&gt; ID="2"&gt;code culture "3" or "7""&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Non-fodder dried vegetables"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(c) Non-fodder oil-seed plants"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(d) Other successive secondary crops"&gt; ID="1"&gt;I02 Mushrooms&gt; ID="2"&gt;136. Mushrooms"&gt; ID="1"&gt;I06 Land subject to the set-aside incentive scheme for arable land and recorded under:&gt; ID="2"&gt;146. Fallows (part "set-aside land")"&gt; ID="2"&gt;- in accordance with Council Regulation (EEC) No 797/85: land voluntarily set aside"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) fallow land, with rotation possibilities&gt; ID="2"&gt;code 5: fallow land, with rotation possibilities"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) permanent pasture and meadow used as grazing for extensive livestock farming&gt; ID="2"&gt;code 6: permanent pasture and meadow used as grazing for extensive livestock farming"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(c) lentils, chick peas and vetches&gt; ID="2"&gt;code 7: lentils, chick peas and vetches"&gt; ID="2"&gt;- in accordance with Council Regulation (EEC) No 1765/92: area compulsory set aside and not cultivated (code 8)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;E Kitchen gardens&gt; ID="2"&gt; "" ID="1.2"&gt;II. Livestock" ID="1"&gt;J01 Equidae&gt; ID="2"&gt;22. Equidae (all ages)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J02 Bovine animals, under one year old&gt; ID="2"&gt;23. + 24. Calves for fattening"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Other cattle under one year old"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Male&gt; ID="2"&gt; "&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Female&gt; ID="2"&gt; "&gt; ID="1"&gt;J03 Male bovine animals, over one but under two years old&gt; ID="2"&gt;25. Male cattle, over one but under two years old"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J04 female bovine animals, over one but under two years old&gt; ID="2"&gt;26. Female cattle, over one but under two years old"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J05 Male bovine animals, two years old and over&gt; ID="2"&gt;27. Male cattle, two years old and over"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J06 Heifers, two years old and over&gt; ID="2"&gt;28. Breeding heifers"&gt; ID="2"&gt;29. Heifers for fattening"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J07 Dairy cows&gt; ID="2"&gt;30. + 31. Dairy cows"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Cull dairy cows"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J08 Other cows&gt; ID="2"&gt;32. Other cows"&gt; ID="2"&gt;1. Female bovine animals, having calved (including those less than two years old) which are kept exclusively or principally for production + calves"&gt; ID="2"&gt;2. Cows for work"&gt; ID="2"&gt;3. Cull cows"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J09 Sheep (all ages)&gt; ID="2"&gt; "&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Ewes&gt; ID="2"&gt;40. Ewes (one year old or more)"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Other sheep&gt; ID="2"&gt;41. Other sheep"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J10 Goats (all ages)&gt; ID="2"&gt; "&gt; ID="1"&gt;(a) Breeding females&gt; ID="2"&gt;38. Breeding females"&gt; ID="1"&gt;(b) Other goats&gt; ID="2"&gt;39. Other goats"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J11 Piglets less than 20 kilograms live weight&gt; ID="2"&gt;43. Piglets less than 20 kilograms live weight"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J12 Breeding sows weighing 50 kilograms and over&gt; ID="2"&gt;44. Breeding sows of 50 kilograms or more"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J13 Other pigs&gt; ID="2"&gt;45. + 46. Pigs for fattening"&gt; ID="2"&gt;Other pigs"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J14 Broilers&gt; ID="2"&gt;47. Table chickens"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J15 Laying hens&gt; ID="2"&gt;48. Laying hens"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J16 Other poultry&gt; ID="2"&gt;49. Other poultry"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J17 Rabbits, breeding females&gt; ID="2"&gt;34. Rabbits, breeding females"&gt; ID="1"&gt;J18 Bees&gt; ID="2"&gt;33. Bees'.""</p>
      <p n="45">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="46">In Annex III, part A, point 2 of Decision 85/377/EEC is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="47">'For subsequent reference periods for renewing SGMs, the value of ECU 1 000 shall be multiplied by coefficients to take account, in monetary terms, of global agro-economic trends in the Community as a whole.</p>
      <p n="48">These coefficients shall be calculated by the Commission and fixed after consultation with the Member States. Their application shall be decided by the competent Commission departments after the competent departments in the Member States have been consulted.'</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
