<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0085-en" n="31994D0085" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0085 English</title>
        <title>94/85/EC: Commission Decision of 16 February 1994 drawing up a list of third countries from which the Member States authorize imports of fresh poultrymeat</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0085:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0085:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0085-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/85/EC: Commission Decision of 16 February 1994 drawing up a list of third countries from which the Member States authorize imports of fresh poultrymeat</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 16 February 1994 drawing up a list of third countries from which the Member States authorize imports of fresh poultrymeat (94/85/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 91/494/EEC of 26 June 1991 on animal health conditions governing intra-Community trade in and imports from third countries of fresh poultrymeat (1), as amended by Directive 92/116/EEC (2), and in particular Article 9 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the countries listed in the Annex to this Decision which traditionally supply the Member States, have been requested to show, through the provision of written assurances supported by appropriate documentation or as a result of on-the-spot inspections, that they satisfy the requirements of the Community;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas these assurances shall be examined by the Standing Veterinary Committee;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas this list applies without prejudice to Commission Decision 93/342/EEC (3) which laid down the criteria to classify third countries with regard to avian influenza and Newcastle disease;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas it may also be necessary in certain cases to specify the parts of countries from which imports will be authorized;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas this list can be amended at any time to take into account new information or new situations; whereas the listing of any country shall be reviewed at any time when further information, in particular resulting from on-the-spot inspections, indicates that conditions in the third country concerned may have changed or that previously received information was incomplete, inexact or inaccurate;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, although the list of third countries forms the basis of the Community arrangements applicable to imports from third countries laid down in Directive 91/494/EEC, other measures, particularly concerning specific animal health conditions, public health requirements, residue plans and certification will have to be taken into account in order to achieve complete harmonization of the conditions for importation of fresh poultrymeat;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas, pending the adoption by the Commission of the animal health certification for importation of fresh poultrymeat from the countries specified in this list, Member States may continue to apply, on importation, their animal health requirements in force on 1 January 1994;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The Member States shall authorize imports of fresh poultrymeat in accordance with the list in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Decision shall apply from 1 July 1994.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 3</p>
      <p n="20">This Decision is addressed to all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 16 February 1994.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ No L 268, 24. 9. 1991, p. 35.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ No L 62, 15. 3. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="27">(3) OJ No L 137, 8. 6. 1993, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="28">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="29">"" ID="1"&gt;AR&gt; ID="2"&gt;Argentina&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;AT&gt; ID="2"&gt;Austria&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;AU&gt; ID="2"&gt;Australia&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;BG&gt; ID="2"&gt;Bulgaria&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;BR&gt; ID="2"&gt;Brazil&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;CA&gt; ID="2"&gt;Canada&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;CH&gt; ID="2"&gt;Switzerland&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;CL&gt; ID="2"&gt;Chile&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;CY&gt; ID="2"&gt;Cyprus&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;CZ&gt; ID="2"&gt;Czech Republic&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;FI&gt; ID="2"&gt;Finland&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;HU&gt; ID="2"&gt;Hungary&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;IL&gt; ID="2"&gt;Israel&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;MY&gt; ID="2"&gt;Malaysia&gt; ID="3"&gt;×&gt; ID="4"&gt;Peninsular (Western) Malaysia only"&gt; ID="1"&gt;NO&gt; ID="2"&gt;Norway&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;NZ&gt; ID="2"&gt;New Zealand&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;PL&gt; ID="2"&gt;Poland&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;RO&gt; ID="2"&gt;Romania&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;SE&gt; ID="2"&gt;Sweden&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;SK&gt; ID="2"&gt;Slovakia&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;TH&gt; ID="2"&gt;Thailand&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;US&gt; ID="2"&gt;United States of America&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;UY&gt; ID="2"&gt;Uruguay&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;ZA&gt; ID="2"&gt;South Africa&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt; ID="1"&gt;ZW&gt; ID="2"&gt;Zimbabwe&gt; ID="3"&gt;×"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
