<TEI.2 id="jrc31994R3175-en" n="31994R3175" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994R3175 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 3175/94 of 21 December 1994 laying down detailed rules of application for the specific arrangements for the supply of cereal products to the smaller Aegean islands and establishing the forecast supply balance</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R3175:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R3175:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994R3175-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 3175/94 of 21 December 1994 laying down detailed rules of application for the specific arrangements for the supply of cereal products to the smaller Aegean islands and establishing the forecast supply balance</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 3175/94 of 21 December 1994 laying down detailed rules of application for the specific arrangements for the supply of cereal products to the smaller Aegean islands and establishing the forecast supply balance</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2019/93 of 19 July 1993 introducing specific measures for the smaller Aegean islands concerning certain agricultural products (1), as amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 822/94 (2), and in particular</p>
      <p n="6">Article 4</p>
      <p n="7">thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2958/93 (3), lays down common detailed rules for the implementation of the specific arrangements for the supply of certain agricultural products to the smaller Aegean islands;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, in order to take account of commercial practices specific to the cereals sector, detailed rules, additional to or derogating from the provisions of Regulation (EEC) No 2958/93, should be laid down;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, pursuant to Article 2 of Regulation (EEC) No 2019/93, the forecast supply balance for cereal products for the smaller Aegean islands for 1995 should be established; whereas that balance may be revised during the year on the basis of trends in the smaller islands' requirements;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, to ensure effective management of the supply arrangements, a timetable for the submission of licence applications should be established and the period of validity of aid certificates fixed;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Cereals,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Pursuant to Article 2 of Regulation (EEC) No 2019/93, the forecast supply balance for cereal products originating in the Community for the smaller Aegean islands for 1995 shall be as laid down in the Annex hereto.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The validity of aid certificates shall expire on the final day of the second month following their month of issue.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 3</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">It shall apply from 1 January 1995.</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Brussels, 21 December 1994.</p>
      <p n="23">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="25">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">(1) OJ No L 184, 27. 7. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="27">(2) OJ No L 95, 14. 4. 1994, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="28">(3) OJ No L 267, 28. 10. 1993, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="29">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="30">Supply balance for cereals for the smaller Aegean islands for 1995 "(tonnes)"" ID="1"&gt;Grain cereals&gt; ID="2"&gt;1001, 1002, 1003, 1004 and 1005&gt; ID="3"&gt;10 000&gt; ID="4"&gt;30 750"&gt; ID="1"&gt;Wheat flour&gt; ID="2"&gt;1001 and 1002&gt; ID="3"&gt;10 000&gt; ID="4"&gt;30 750"&gt; ID="1"&gt;Food industry residues and waste&gt; ID="2"&gt;2302 to 2308&gt; ID="3"&gt;1 000&gt; ID="4"&gt;16 500"&gt; ID="1"&gt;Preparations of a kind used in animal feeding&gt; ID="2"&gt;2309 90&gt; ID="3"&gt;1 000&gt; ID="4"&gt;6 500"&gt; ID="1"&gt;Total &gt; ID="2"&gt;22 000&gt; ID="3"&gt;84 500"&gt; ID="1"&gt;Grand total &gt; ID="2"&gt;106 500"&gt;</p>
      <p n="31">These groups are defined in Annexes I and II to Regulation (EEC) No 2958/93.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
