<TEI.2 id="jrc31994R0852-en" n="31994R0852" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994R0852 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 852/94 of 15 April 1994 amending Regulation (EEC) No 890/78 laying down detailed rules for the certification of hops</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R0852:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R0852:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994R0852-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 852/94 of 15 April 1994 amending Regulation (EEC) No 890/78 laying down detailed rules for the certification of hops</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 852/94 of 15 April 1994 amending Regulation (EEC) No 890/78 laying down detailed rules for the certification of hops</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1696/71 of 26 July 1971 on the common organization of the market in hops (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3124/92 (2), and in particular Article 2 (5) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Article 8 (1) and (2) of Council Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77 of 19 July 1977 concerning the certification of hops (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1987/93 (4), defines the conditions under which hops may be blended in respect of products in circulation; whereas, however, blending carried out in the brewery for brewers' own use in not covered by that rule because such products are not in circulation; whereas, also, they have been granted a derogation by virtue of Article 1 (1) (e) of Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77, excluding from the compulsory certification procedure in order no to unduly hinder the freedom of action of brewers in their own businesses; whereas, to prevent products obtained from blends of hops from entering the market, mention should be made of that prohibition on the packaging of those products and on the documents accompanying them;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, therefore, Commission Regulation (EEC) No 890/78 (5), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2928/93 (6), should be amended;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Hops,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">In point (c) of Article 10 of Regulation (EEC) No 890/78, the following text is hereby added:</p>
      <p n="12">'In the case of blends of hops, the following additional indication must be included on the document and on the package:</p>
      <p n="13">"Mixture of hops for own use; may not be marketed".'</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 15 April 1994.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="20">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ No L 175, 4. 8. 1971, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) OJ No L 313, 30. 10. 1992, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="23">(3) OJ No L 200, 8. 8. 1977, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="24">(4) OJ No L 182, 24. 7. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="25">(5) OJ No L 117, 29. 4. 1978, p. 43.</p>
      <p n="26">(6) OJ No L 265, 26. 10. 1993, p. 4.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
