<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0077-en" n="31994D0077" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0077 English</title>
        <title>94/77/EC: Commission Decision of 7 February 1994 amending Council Decision 90/424/EEC on expenditure in the veterinary field</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0077:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0077:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0077-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/77/EC: Commission Decision of 7 February 1994 amending Council Decision 90/424/EEC on expenditure in the veterinary field</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 7 February 1994 amending Council Decision 90/424/EEC on expenditure in the veterinary field (94/77/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Decision 90/424/EEC of 26 June 1990 on expenditure in the veterinary field (1), as last amended by Decision 93/439/EEC (2), and in particular Article 24 (1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Article 24 of Decision 90/424/EEC provides for the possibility of a Community financial measure for the eradication and monitoring of the diseases listed in the Annex thereto;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas heartwater, babesiosis and anaplasmosis transmitted by vector insects are present in the French overseas departments;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the specific health situation of the French overseas departments justifies the addition of the abovmentioned diseases to the Annex to Decision 90/424/EEC;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The following indents are hereby added to Group 1 of the disease list in the Annex to Decision 90/424/EEC:</p>
      <p n="13">'- heartwater transmitted by vector insects in the French overseas departments</p>
      <p n="14">- babesiosis transmitted by vector insects in the French overseas departments</p>
      <p n="15">- anaplasmosis transmitted by vector insects in the French overseas departments'.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 7 February 1994.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="21">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">(1) OJ No L 224, 18. 8. 1990, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="23">(2) OJ No L 203, 13. 8. 1993, p. 34.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
