<TEI.2 id="jrc31994R1586-en" n="31994R1586" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994R1586 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1586/94 of 30 June 1994 amending Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1722/93 concerning production refunds in the cereals and rice sectors respectively</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R1586:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R1586:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994R1586-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1586/94 of 30 June 1994 amending Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1722/93 concerning production refunds in the cereals and rice sectors respectively</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 1586/94 of 30 June 1994 amending Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1722/93 concerning production refunds in the cereals and rice sectors respectively</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1766/92 of 21 June 1992 on the common organization of the market in cereals (1), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2193/93 (2), and in particular Article 7 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1418/76 of 21 June 1976 on the common organization of the market in rice (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1544/93 (4), and in particular Article 9 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 5 (1) of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1722/93 laying down detailed rules for the application of Council Regulations (EEC) No 1766/92 and (EEC) No 1418/76 concerning production refunds in the cereals and rice sectors respectively (5) specifies that applications for refund certificates are to be addressed in writing to the competent authority; whereas it is appropriate that the days on which such applications may be made should be specified and that a time limit be set for the submission of applications;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, under the second subparagraph of Article 6 (3), during July and August of the 1993/94, 1994/95 and 1995/96 marketing years, certificates are valid only until the last day of the month during which the certificate was issued; whereas this short period of validity may result in numerous applications for certificates; whereas it is appropriate, therefore, to specify 31 August as the final day of validity for all certificates issued in July and August;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas application of the rate of refund valid on the day of processing in the case of applications for certificates lodged in July of the 1994/95 and 1995/96 marketing years permits closer monitoring of the variation in the refund rate during the period of validity of the certification;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Management Committee for Cereals has not delivered an opinion within the time limit set by its chairman,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">Regulation (EEC) No 1722/93 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="14">1. The following is added to Article 5 (1):</p>
      <p n="15">'The application shall be lodged each working day before 5 p.m., Brussels time'.</p>
      <p n="16">2. The second subparagraph of Article 6 (3) is replaced by:</p>
      <p n="17">'However, during July and August of the 1994/95 and 1995/96 marketing years, certificates applied for during the months in question shall be valid only until 31 August'.</p>
      <p n="18">3. The following is added to the first subparagraph of Article 6 (4):</p>
      <p n="19">'However, in the case of a refund application lodged during July of the 1994/95 and 1995/96 marketing years, the amount of the refund payable shall be the amount applicable on the day of processing of the starch'.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 July 1994.</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Brussels, 30 June 1994.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="26">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="27">(1) OJ No L 181, 1. 7. 1992, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="28">(2) OJ No L 196, 5. 8. 1993, p. 22.</p>
      <p n="29">(3) OJ No L 166, 25. 6. 1976, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="30">(4) OJ No L 154, 25. 6. 1993, p. 5.</p>
      <p n="31">(5) OJ No L 159, 1. 7. 1993, p. 112.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
