<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0964-en" n="31994D0964" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0964 English</title>
        <title>94/964/EC: Commission Decision of 28 December 1994 approving the plan for the approval of establishments for the purposes of intra-Community trade in poultry and hatching eggs submitted by Finland</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>22 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0964:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0964:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0964-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/964/EC: Commission Decision of 28 December 1994 approving the plan for the approval of establishments for the purposes of intra-Community trade in poultry and hatching eggs submitted by Finland</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 28 December 1994 approving the plan for the approval of establishments for the purposes of intra-Community trade in poultry and hatching eggs submitted by Finland (94/964/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 90/539/EEC of 15 October 1990, on animal health conditions governing intra-Community trade in, and imports from third countries of, poultry and hatching eggs (1), as amended by Directive 93/120/EC (2), and in particular Article 3 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas by letter dated 21 October 1994 Finland transmitted a plan to the Commission;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the plan has been examined and found to meet the requirements of Directive 90/539/EEC, and in particular Annex II thereof;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The plan submitted by Finland for the approval of establishments for the purposes of intra-Community trade in poultry and hatching eggs is hereby approved.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">Finland shall bring into force by 1 January 1995 the laws, regulations and administrative provisions for implementation of the plan referred to in Article 1.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">This Decision shall take effect subject to and on the date of the entry into force of the Treaty of Accession of Norway, Austria, Finland and Sweden.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 4</p>
      <p n="17">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 28 December 1994.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="21">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">(1) OJ No L 303, 31. 10. 1990, p. 6.(2) OJ No L 340, 31. 12. 1993, p. 35.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
