<TEI.2 id="jrc31994R0761-en" n="31994R0761" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994R0761 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 761/94 of 6 April 1994 amending Council Regulation (EEC) No 1956/88 adopting provisions for the applicaton of the Scheme of Joint International Inspection and Surveillance adopted by the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R0761:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R0761:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994R0761-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 761/94 of 6 April 1994 amending Council Regulation (EEC) No 1956/88 adopting provisions for the applicaton of the Scheme of Joint International Inspection and Surveillance adopted by the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 761/94 of 6 April 1994 amending Council Regulation (EEC) No 1956/88 adopting provisions for the applicaton of the Scheme of Joint International Inspection and Surveillance adopted by the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2847/93 establishing a Community Control system applicable to the common fisheries policy (1), and in particular Article 5 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Regulation (EEC) No 1956/88 (2), last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 436/92 (3) implements the Scheme of Joint International Inspection and Surveillance adopted by the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO) Fisheries Commission on 10 February 1988;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the NAFO Fisheries Commission adopted on 10 September 1993 a proposal to amend the Scheme;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas pursuant to Article XI of the NAFO Convention the proposal will, in the absence of objections, become a measure binding upon Contracting parties with effect from 16 December 1993;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the modified scheme is acceptable to the Community;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Fisheries and Aquaculture,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">Regulation (EEC) No 1956/88 is modified as follows:</p>
      <p n="14">1. A second subparagraph with the following text shall be inserted in paragraph 5 (ii) of the Annex:</p>
      <p n="15">'When an inspection vessel has signalled that an inspection party is about to commence boarding a fishing vessel which has begun or is about to begin hauling its nets, the master of that fishing vessel shall ensure that the net is not retrieved for a period of 30 minutes after receiving the signal.'</p>
      <p n="16">2. The penultimate line of paragraph 5 (ii) is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="17">'In either case' is replaced by 'In all cases'.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 6 April 1994.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Yannis PALEOKRASSAS</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ No L 261, 20. 10. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ No L 175, 6. 7. 1988, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="27">(3) OJ No L 54, 28. 2. 1992, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
