<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0837-en" n="31994D0837" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0837 English</title>
        <title>94/837/EC: Commission Decision of 16 December 1994 laying down special conditions for the approval of the re-wrapping centres referred to in Council Directive 77/99/EEC and rules for the marketing of the products therefrom</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>28 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0837:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0837:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0837-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/837/EC: Commission Decision of 16 December 1994 laying down special conditions for the approval of the re-wrapping centres referred to in Council Directive 77/99/EEC and rules for the marketing of the products therefrom</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 16 December 1994 laying down special conditions for the approval of the rewrapping centres referred to in Council Directive 77/99/EEC and rules for the marketing of the products therefrom (94/837/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 77/99/EEC of 21 December 1976 on health problems affecting the production and marketing of meat products and certain other products of animal origin (1), as last amended by Directive 92/118/EEC (2), and in particular</p>
      <p n="6">Article 17</p>
      <p n="7">thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the rewrapping centres may carry out handling operations, in addition to rewrapping and/or reassembling, such as cutting or slicing meat products; whereas this can entail the handling of products unprotected by their wrapping or packaging materials;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the hygiene conditions under which these operations are to be carried out should be defined;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas rules for the health marking of the products from these rewrapping centres should also be laid down;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">1. Rewrapping centres which only reassemble products without removing the wrapping must fulfil the relevant conditions set out in Annex B, Chapter VII, point 1 to Directive 77/99/EEC.</p>
      <p n="15">2. Rewrapping centres carrying out unwrapping and rewrapping operations, must fulfil the relevant conditions set out in Annex A, Chapters I and II to Directive 77/99/EEC and the pertinent conditions set out in Annex B, Chapter I, points 1 (a), (b), (d), (e) and (f) and 2 (a), (c), (i) and (j) to the said Directive.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">1. Products from the rewrapping centres referred to in Article 1 (1) must keep the health mark of the production establishment of origin.</p>
      <p n="18">Products from the rewrapping centres referred to in Article 1 (2) must carry a health mark in accordance with the provisions set out in Annex B, Chapter VI to Directive 77/99/EEC. The health mark shall be issued to the rewrapping centres by the competent authority.</p>
      <p n="19">Where products from different sources are reassembled, the health mark of the rewrapping centre must be applied to the last packaging made in the rewrapping centres.</p>
      <p n="20">2. Rewrapping centres must set up a special registration system so as to enable the competent authority to trace a rewrapped product back to the establishment of origin.</p>
      <p n="21">Article 3</p>
      <p n="22">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Brussels, 16 December 1994.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="26">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="27">(1) OJ No L 26, 31. 1. 1977, p. 85.</p>
      <p n="28">(2) OJ No L 62, 15. 3. 1993, p. 49.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
