<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0643-en" n="31994D0643" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0643 English</title>
        <title>94/643/EC: Commission Decision of 12 September 1994 concerning the withdrawal of authorizations for plant protection products containing cyhalothrin as active substance</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0643:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0643:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0643-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/643/EC: Commission Decision of 12 September 1994 concerning the withdrawal of authorizations for plant protection products containing cyhalothrin as active substance</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 12 September 1994 concerning the withdrawal of authorizations for plant protection products containing cyhalothrin as active substance (94/643/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3600/92 of 11 December 1992, laying down the detailed rules for the implementation of the first stage of the programme of work referred to in Article 8 (2) of Directive 91/414/EEC (1) concerning the placing on the market of plant protection products, and in particular Article 4 (5) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas cyhalothrin was one of the 90 active substances covered by the first stage of the work programme provided for in Article 8 (2) of Directive 91/414/EEC (2);</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas for this substance no producer or Member State has notified an interest in obtaining the inclusion of this substance in Annex I to Directive 91/414/EEC;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas it has to be considered that the data required for re-evaluation of this substance will not be submitted in the framework of the work programme and that therefore a decision should be taken with the effect that current authorizations for plant protection products containing this active substance are withdrawn;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas this Decision does not exclude that in future cyhalothrin is evaluated in the framework of the proceedings provided for in Article 6 of Directive 91/414/EEC;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plant Health,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">The Member States shall ensure:</p>
      <p n="14">1. that authorizations for plant protection products containing cyhalothrin are withdrawn within a period of six months from the date of the present Decision;</p>
      <p n="15">2. that from the date of the present Decision no authorizations for plant protection products containing cyhalothrin will be granted or renewed under the derogation provided for in Article 8 (2) of Directive 91/414/EEC.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 12 September 1994.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="21">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">(1) OJ No L 366, 15. 12. 1992, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="23">(2) OJ No L 230, 19. 8. 1991, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
