<TEI.2 id="jrc31994R0501-en" n="31994R0501" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994R0501 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (Euratom) No 501/94 of 2 March 1994 concerning the conclusion by the European Atomic Energy Community of the Protocol of the provisional application of the Agreement establishing an International Science and Technology Center</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R0501:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994R0501:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994R0501-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (Euratom) No 501/94 of 2 March 1994 concerning the conclusion by the European Atomic Energy Community of the Protocol of the provisional application of the Agreement establishing an International Science and Technology Center</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EURATOM) No 501/94 of 2 March 1994 concerning the conclusion by the European Atomic Energy Community of the Protocol of the provisional application of the Agreement establishing an International Science and Technology Center</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular Article 101 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Whereas the Protocol on the provisional application of the Agreement establishing an International Science and Technology Center was signed on 27 December 1993; whereas by Decision of 21 February 1994, the Council approved the said Protocol for the purpose of conclusion by the Commission on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Protocol should be concluded on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community,</p>
      <p n="7">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="8">Article 1</p>
      <p n="9">The Protocol on the provisional application of the Agreement establishing an International Science and Technology Center is hereby approved on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community.</p>
      <p n="10">The text of the Protocol is attached to this Regulation (1).</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">The President of the Commission shall, on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community, give the notification provided for in Article I of the Protocol.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 3</p>
      <p n="14">Articles 3 and 4 of Commission Regulation (Euratom) No 3956/92 (2) shall apply.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 4</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 2 March 1994.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">The President</p>
      <p n="21">Jacques DELORS</p>
      <p n="22">(1) See page 2 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="23">(2) OJ No L 409, 31. 12. 1992, p. 10.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
