<TEI.2 id="jrc31994D0621-en" n="31994D0621" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31994D0621 English</title>
        <title>94/621/EC: Commission Decision of 20 September 1994 concerning certain measures with regard to fishery products and bivalve molluscs originating in and coming from Albania (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0621:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31994D0621:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31994D0621-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/621/EC: Commission Decision of 20 September 1994 concerning certain measures with regard to fishery products and bivalve molluscs originating in and coming from Albania (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 20 September 1994 concerning certain measures with regard to fishery products and bivalve molluscs originating in and coming from Albania (Text with EEA relevance) (94/621/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 91/496/EEC of 15 July 1991 laying down the principles governing the organization of veterinary checks on animals entering the Community from third countries and amending Directives 89/662/EEC, 90/425/EEC and 90/675/EEC (1), as last amended by Decision 92/438/EEC (2), and in particular Article 18 (1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Directive 90/675/EEC of 10 December 1990 laying down the principles governing the organization of veterinary checks on products entering the Community from third countries (3), as last amended by Directive 92/118/EEC (4), and in particular Article 19 (1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas cases of cholera have been found in Albania;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the presence of cholera in Albania is likely to constitute a serious danger to public health; this requires the rapid adoption at Community level of the necessary protection measures with regard to fishery products and bivalve molluscs;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, in the absence of health guarantees from the Albanian authorities, it is necessary to prohibit imports of fishery products and bivalve molluscs originating in or coming from Albania,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">Member States shall prohibit the importation of fishery products and bivalve molluscs originating in or coming from Albania.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">Member States shall alter the measures they apply to imports in order to bring them into line with this Decision. They shall immediately inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">This Decision shall apply until 31 October 1994.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 4</p>
      <p n="18">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 20 September 1994.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="22">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 268, 24. 9. 1991, p. 56.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ No L 243, 25. 8. 1992, p. 27.</p>
      <p n="25">(3) OJ No L 373, 31. 12. 1990, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(4) OJ No L 62, 15. 3. 1993, p. 49.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
