<TEI.2 id="jrc41994D0271-en" n="41994D0271" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 41994D0271 English</title>
        <title>94/271/EC, Euratom: Decision of the representatives of the Governments of the Member States of 24 March 1994 on the consultation and disclosure of archive documents concerning the negotiations for the Treaties of Rome, the negotiations for the European Political Community and the Interim Committee for the Common Market and Euratom</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>10 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41994D0271:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41994D0271:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc41994D0271-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">94/271/EC, Euratom: Decision of the representatives of the Governments of the Member States of 24 March 1994 on the consultation and disclosure of archive documents concerning the negotiations for the Treaties of Rome, the negotiations for the European Political Community and the Interim Committee for the Common Market and Euratom</head>
      <p n="2">DECISION OF THE REPRESENTATIVES OF THE GOVERNMENTS OF THE MEMBER STATES of 24 March 1994 on the consultation and disclosure of archive documents concerning the negotiations for the Treaties of Rome, the negotiations for the European Political Community and the Interim Committee for the Common Market and Euratom (94/271/EC, Euratom)</p>
      <p n="3">Article 1</p>
      <p n="4">The consultation and disclosure of archive documents concerning the negotiations for the Treaties of Rome, the negotiations for the European Political Community and the Interim Committee for the Common Market and Euratom which have been lodged in the Community archives by Member States shall be permitted under the conditions laid down in Council Regulation (EEC, Euratom) No 354/83 of 1 February 1983 (1).</p>
      <p n="5">Article 2</p>
      <p n="6">This Decision shall enter into force as of today's date.</p>
      <p n="7">Done at Brussels, 24 March 1994.</p>
      <p n="8">The President</p>
      <p n="9">A. ZAPHRIOU</p>
      <p n="10">(1) OJ No L 43, 15. 2. 1983, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
