<TEI.2 id="jrc41994D0025-en" n="41994D0025" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 41994D0025 English</title>
        <title>The Schengen acquis - Decision of the Executive Committee of 22 December 1994 on the exchange of statistical information on the issuing of uniform visas (SCH/Com-ex (94) 25)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>18 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41994D0025:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41994D0025:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc41994D0025-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">The Schengen acquis - Decision of the Executive Committee of 22 December 1994 on the exchange of statistical information on the issuing of uniform visas (SCH/Com-ex (94) 25)</head>
      <p n="2">DECISION OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE</p>
      <p n="3">of 22 December 1994</p>
      <p n="4">on the exchange of statistical information on the issuing of uniform visas</p>
      <p n="5">(SCH/Com-ex (94)25)</p>
      <p n="6">THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Article 132 of the Convention implementing the Schengen Agreement,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Article 12(3) of the abovementioned Convention,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="10">1. The Contracting Parties shall exchange statistical information with each other on the issuing of uniform visas. The table attached hereto indicates what information is to be gathered and the intervals at which these exchanges are to take place.</p>
      <p n="11">2. The Contracting Parties shall transmit the statistical information to the Schengen General Secretariat. The Secretariat shall collate this information and compile global tables giving an overview of each period, which it shall make available to the Contracting Parties.</p>
      <p n="12">3. Notwithstanding the above exchanges, statistical information may also be exchanged locally within the framework of consular cooperation in accordance with a procedure agreed on by the Representations concerned.</p>
      <p n="13">Bonn, 22 December 1994.</p>
      <p n="14">The Chairman</p>
      <p n="15">Bernd Schmidbauer</p>
      <p n="16">Exchange of statistics on the issuing of visas</p>
      <p n="17">SCH/II-Visa (94)33 rev.</p>
      <p n="18">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
