<TEI.2 id="jrc31969L0463-en" n="31969L0463" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31969L0463 English</title>
        <title>Third Council Directive 69/463/EEC of 9 December 1969 on the harmonisation of legislation of Member States concerning turnover taxes - introduction of value added tax in Member States</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>30 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31969L0463:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31969L0463:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31969L0463-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Third Council Directive 69/463/EEC of 9 December 1969 on the harmonisation of legislation of Member States concerning turnover taxes - introduction of value added tax in Member States</head>
      <p n="2">THIRD COUNCIL DIRECTIVE of 9 December 1969 on the harmonisation of legislation of Member States concerning turnover taxes - introduction of value added tax in Member States (69/463/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 99 and 100 thereof;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission;</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Opinion of the European Parliament (1);</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (2);</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the Italian Republic and the Kingdom of Belgium made known to the Commission, on 14 July and 12 September 1969 respectively, that they were not in a position to meet the final date of 1 January 1970 for the introduction of value added tax as provided in the second paragraph of Article 1 of the First Council Directive of 11 April 1967 (3) on the harmonisation of legislation of Member States concerning turnover taxes ; whereas, consequently, those Member States have asked for a further period of two years and one year respectively for the introduction of that tax;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Kingdom of Belgium considers that it is not in a position to apply value added tax on the date laid down, mainly for conjunctural and budgetary reasons peculiar to Belgium;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Italian Republic has pointed out that a proposal for the general reform of taxes has now been tabled for consideration and adoption by Parliament, which has not yet considered this problem ; whereas, according to that proposal, the appropriate legislation must be adopted before 31 October 1970 ; whereas, consequently, that Member State is not in a position to apply value added tax on the date laid down;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas an additional period may be granted only if it is kept to a minimum;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas, in these circumstances, introduction of value added tax may not be delayed beyond 1 January 1972;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas one of the main objectives of the First Directive mentioned above is, through the introduction of value added tax on 1 January 1970, to establish conditions making it possible to avoid competition being distorted by turnover taxes;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas that objective cannot be attained by 1 January 1970, in particular as regards trade, since these Member States will continue to apply, by means of turnover taxes, average rates of equalisation of the internal tax burden;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas Member States which are not in a position to introduce value added tax by 1 January 1970 should not increase their average equalisation rates in operation on 1 October 1969;</p>
      <p n="16">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="17">Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">The date of 1 January 1972 shall be substituted for that of 1 January 1970 laid down in Article 1 of the First Directive of 11 April 1967.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">For the purposes of this Directive, "average rates" means the rates of countervailing charges on (1) OJ No C 139, 28.10.1969, p. 32. (2) OJ No C 144, 8.11.1969, p. 13. (3) OJ No 71, 14.4.1967, p. 1301/67.</p>
      <p n="21">importation and of repayments on exportation introduced so as to equalise, as regards national products, the burden resulting from the cumulative multi-stage turnover tax at the various stages of production, excluding the tax on sales by the final producer.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 3</p>
      <p n="23">The average rates in force on 1 October 1969 may not be increased.</p>
      <p n="24">However, the average rates in operation on that date shall be adapted to any later changes in the rates of turnover tax.</p>
      <p n="25">Article 4</p>
      <p n="26">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="27">Done at Brussels, 9 December 1969.</p>
      <p n="28">For the Council</p>
      <p n="29">The President</p>
      <p n="30">H.J. DE KOSTER</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
