<TEI.2 id="jrc31969R1826-en" n="31969R1826" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31969R1826 English</title>
        <title>Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 of the Council of 15 September 1969 laying down the form of the 'laissez passer' to be issued to members and servants of the institutions</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>20 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31969R1826:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31969R1826:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31969R1826-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 of the Council of 15 September 1969 laying down the form of the 'laissez passer' to be issued to members and servants of the institutions</head>
      <p n="2">REGULATION (ECSC, EEC, EURATOM) No 1826/69 OF THE COUNCIL of 15 September 1969 laying down the form of the "laissez passer" to be issued to members and servants of the institutions</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to Article 7 (1) of the Protocol of the Privileges and Immunities of the European Communities annexed to the Treaty establishing a Single Council and a Single Commission of the European Communities;</p>
      <p n="5">Whereas Article 7 (1) of the Protocol on the Privileges and Immunities of the European Communities provides that the Council shall prescribe the form of the laissez passer which may be issued to members and servants of the institutions by the Presidents of those institutions;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas a single form of laissez passer should be prescribed for all the institutions and whereas it is therefore appropriate to repeal Regulation No 2 (1) of the Council of the European Economic Community and of the Council of the European Atomic Energy Community establishing the form of the laissez passer issued to members of the European Parliament;</p>
      <p n="7">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="8">Article 1</p>
      <p n="9">The laissez passer issued to members and servants of the institutions shall be drawn up in the form laid down in the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="10">Article 2</p>
      <p n="11">Regulation No 2 of the Council of the European Economic Community and of the Council of the European Atomic Energy Community of 1 July 1958 is hereby repealed.</p>
      <p n="12">However, the laissez passer issued pursuant to that Regulation shall remain valid until the issue of laissez passer in accordance with this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Brussels, 15 September 1969.</p>
      <p n="15">For the Council</p>
      <p n="16">The President</p>
      <p n="17">H.J. DE KOSTER (1)OJ No 17, 6.10.1958, p. 387/58 and p. 403/58.</p>
      <p n="18">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="19">&gt;PIC FILE= "T9000294"&gt;</p>
      <p n="20">&gt;PIC FILE= "T9000295"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
