<TEI.2 id="jrc31988R1609-en" n="31988R1609" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31988R1609 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1609/88 of 9 June 1988 setting the latest time of entry into storage for butter sold under Regulations (EEC) No 3143/85 and (EEC) No 570/88</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>35 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R1609:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R1609:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31988R1609-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1609/88 of 9 June 1988 setting the latest time of entry into storage for butter sold under Regulations (EEC) No 3143/85 and (EEC) No 570/88</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1609/88</p>
      <p n="4">of 9 June 1988</p>
      <p n="5">setting the latest time of entry into storage for butter sold under Regulations (EEC) No 3143/85 and (EEC) No 570/88</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1109/88 (2), and in particular Article 6 (7) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 985/68 of 15 July 1968 laying down general rules for intervention on the market in butter and cream (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 842/88 (4), and in particular Article 7a thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas under Article 1 of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 of 11 November 1985 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter (5), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 775/88 (6), and under Article 1 of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 570/88 of 16 February 1988 on the sale of butter at reduced prices and the granting of aid for butter and concentrated butter for use in the manufacture of pastry products, ice-cream and other foodstuffs (7), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 949/88 (8), the butter put up for sale must have been taken into storage before a date to be determined; whereas this date is set on the basis of stock trends and available quantities;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas following the entry into force of the abovementioned Regulation (EEC) No 570/88, Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1726/84 of 18 June 1984 determining the time limit for the entry into storage of butter sold under Regulations (EEC) No 262/79 and (EEC) No 3143/85 (9), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 685/88 (10), should be repealed;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The butter referred to in Article 1 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 must have been taken into storage before 1 January 1987.</p>
      <p n="16">The butter referred to in Article 1 of Regulation (EEC) No 570/88 must have been taken into storage before 1 January 1987.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">Regulation (EEC) No 1726/84 is repealed.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 3</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Brussels, 9 June 1988.</p>
      <p n="23">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="25">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="26">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="27">(2) OJ No L 110, 29. 4. 1988, p. 27.</p>
      <p n="28">(3) OJ No L 169, 18. 7. 1968, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="29">(4) OJ No L 87, 31. 3. 1988, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="30">(5) OJ No L 298, 12. 11. 1985, p. 9.</p>
      <p n="31">(6) OJ No L 80, 25. 3. 1988, p. 31.</p>
      <p n="32">(7) OJ No L 55, 1. 3. 1988, p. 31.</p>
      <p n="33">(8) OJ No L 92, 9. 4. 1988, p. 43.</p>
      <p n="34">(9) OJ No L 163, 21. 6. 1984, p. 28.</p>
      <p n="35">(10) OJ No L 71, 17. 3. 1988, p. 26.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
