<TEI.2 id="jrc31988R1494-en" n="31988R1494" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31988R1494 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 1494/88 of 3 May 1988 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Federal Republic of the Comoros on fishing off Comoros</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>20 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R1494:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R1494:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31988R1494-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 1494/88 of 3 May 1988 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Federal Republic of the Comoros on fishing off Comoros</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 1494/88 of 3 May 1988 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Federal Republic of the Comoros on fishing off Comoros</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the Community and the Islamic Federal Republic of the Comoros have negotiated and initialled an Agreement on fishing off Comoros; whereas this provides fishing opportunities for Community fishermen in waters over which Comoros has sovereignty or jurisdiction;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas it is in the Community's interest to approve this Agreement,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1 The Agreement on fishing between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Federal Republic of the Comoros on fishing off Comoros is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="11">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2 The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the persons empowered to sign the Agreement in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 3 This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 3 May 1988.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Council The President M. BANGEMANN (3) OJ No C 73, 19. 3. 1988, p. 6.</p>
      <p n="17">(4) OJ No C 122, 9. 5. 1988.</p>
      <p n="18">EWG:L555UMBE12.96 FF: 5UEN; SETUP: 01; Hoehe: 344 mm; 42 Zeilen; 1687 Zeichen;</p>
      <p n="19">Bediener: MARK Pr.: B;</p>
      <p n="20">Kunde: 41727 Montan England 12</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
