<TEI.2 id="jrc31988D0598-en" n="31988D0598" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31988D0598 English</title>
        <title>88/598/EEC: Council Decision of 21 November 1988 concerning the conclusion of an Additional Protocol to the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Syrian Arab Republic</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988D0598:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988D0598:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31988D0598-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">88/598/EEC: Council Decision of 21 November 1988 concerning the conclusion of an Additional Protocol to the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Syrian Arab Republic</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="3">of 21 November 1988</p>
      <p n="4">concerning the conclusion of an Additional Protocol to the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Syrian Arab Republic</p>
      <p n="5">(88/598/EEC)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 238 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the assent of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Additional Protocol to the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Syrian Arab Republic (2), signed at Brussels on 18 January 1977, should be approved.</p>
      <p n="11">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">The Additional Protocol to the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Syrian Arab Republic is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="14">The text of the Protocol is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">The President of the Council shall give the notification provided for in Article 5 of the Protocol (3).</p>
      <p n="17">Article 3</p>
      <p n="18">This Decision shall take effect on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 21 November 1988.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Council</p>
      <p n="21">The President</p>
      <p n="22">Th. PANGALOS</p>
      <p n="23">EWG:L327UMBE23.96</p>
      <p n="24">FF: 7UEN; SETUP: 01; Hoehe: 450 mm; 39 Zeilen; 1428 Zeichen;</p>
      <p n="25">Bediener: JUTT Pr.: C;</p>
      <p n="26">Kunde:</p>
      <p n="27">(1) OJ N° C 290, 14. 11. 1988.</p>
      <p n="28">(2) OJ N° L 269, 27. 9. 1978, p. 2.</p>
      <p n="29">(3) See p. 64 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
