<TEI.2 id="jrc31988D0646-en" n="31988D0646" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31988D0646 English</title>
        <title>88/646/EEC: Council Decision of 21 December 1988 on the conclusion of the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria on the import into the Community of tomato concentrates originating in Algeria</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>14 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988D0646:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988D0646:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31988D0646-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">88/646/EEC: Council Decision of 21 December 1988 on the conclusion of the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria on the import into the Community of tomato concentrates originating in Algeria</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 21 December 1988 on the conclusion of the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria on the import into the Community of tomato concentrates originating in Algeria (88/646/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria(1) was signed on 26 April 1976 and entered into force on 1 November 1978;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria on the import into the Community of tomato concentrates originating in Algeria should be approved,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1 The Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria on the import into the Community of tomato concentrates originating in Algeria is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="10">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2 The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the Agreement for the purpose of binding the Community.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 3 This Decision shall take effect on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="13">Done at Brussels, 21 December 1988.</p>
      <p n="14">For the CouncilThe PresidentV. PAPANDREOU (1)OJ No L 263, 27. 9. 1978, p. 2.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
