<TEI.2 id="jrc31988R0091-en" n="31988R0091" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31988R0091 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 91/88 of 13 January 1988 laying down provisions for implementing article 28a (2) of the Conditions of Employment of Other Servants</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>56 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R0091:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R0091:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31988R0091-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 91/88 of 13 January 1988 laying down provisions for implementing article 28a (2) of the Conditions of Employment of Other Servants</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="4">1.2.3 // // // // EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES // // FORM // // // EC - FTS (1) // // //</p>
      <p n="5">CERTIFICATE CONCERNING THE REGISTRATION AS A PERSON SEEKING EMPLOYMENT AND CONCERNING THE RIGHT TO UNEMPLOYMENT BENEFITS OF A FORMER MEMBER OF THE TEMPORARY STAFF OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES</p>
      <p n="6">(Council Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 2799/85, Article 33)</p>
      <p n="7">1.2 // // // 1 // Institution of the European Communities to which the form is addressed // // // 1.1 // Name: // 1.2 // Address: // // // // 1.2 // // // 2 // Information concerning the former member of the temporary staff // // // 2.1 // Surname: // 2.2 // Maiden name: // 2.3 // Fornames: // 2.4 // Date of birth: // 2.5 // Residence: // // // 2.6 // Personnel number or file reference number: // //</p>
      <p n="8">Section A - Registration and checks</p>
      <p n="9">3 This is to certify that the above named person:</p>
      <p n="10">3.1 registered as a person seeking employment on</p>
      <p n="11">with the employment services of</p>
      <p n="12">3.2 was registered as seeking employment from to</p>
      <p n="13">3.3 did not subject himself/herself to the obligations under national legislation from</p>
      <p n="14">to because</p>
      <p n="15">1.2 // // // 4 // National institution issuing this certificate (Section A) // // // 4.1 // Name: // 4.2 // Address: // 4.3 // Stamp // // 4.4 Date: // temporary staff.</p>
      <p n="16">Section B - Claim for unemployment benefit</p>
      <p n="17">5 This is to certify that:</p>
      <p n="18">5.1 the person referred to in Box 2 submitted a claim for unemployment benefit on</p>
      <p n="19">5.2 the claim is currently being examined</p>
      <p n="20">5.3 no claim has been made</p>
      <p n="21">6 The person referred to in Box 2:</p>
      <p n="22">6.1 is not entitled to unemployment benefit because</p>
      <p n="23">6.2 has not registered as a person seeking employment</p>
      <p n="24">6.3 has not subjected himself/ herself to the obligations under national legislation</p>
      <p n="25">6.4 does not satisfy the conditions for payment of unemployment benefit</p>
      <p n="26">6.5 (other reasons; please specify)</p>
      <p n="27">7 is entitled to unemployment benefit</p>
      <p n="28">7.1 from (date)</p>
      <p n="29">7.2 gross daily amount</p>
      <p n="30">7.3 gross weekly amount</p>
      <p n="31">7.4 gross monthly amount</p>
      <p n="32">7.5 for days</p>
      <p n="33">7.6 until</p>
      <p n="34">7.7 amount of benefit paid for the month in question</p>
      <p n="35">8 Payment of unemployment benefit was</p>
      <p n="36">8.1 suspended from to</p>
      <p n="37">8.2 withdrawn</p>
      <p n="38">8.3 because</p>
      <p n="39">1.2 // // // 9 // National institution issuing this certificate (Section B) // // // 9.1 // Name // 9.2 // Address: // 9.3 // Stamp // // 9.4 Date: // // 9.5 Signature: // // // // // 4.5 Signature: // // // //</p>
      <p n="40">(1) EC = European Communities. FTS = Former member of the</p>
      <p n="41">INSTRUCTIONS</p>
      <p n="42">(Please complete this form in block letters, writing on the dotted lines only)</p>
      <p n="43">A. Instructions for the administrative services of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="44">1. The appropriate department of the institution of the European Communities for which the former member of the temporary staff worked should complete Boxes 1 and 2.</p>
      <p n="45">2. It should give five copies of the completed form to the former member of the temporary staff.</p>
      <p n="46">B. Instructions for the national administrative services</p>
      <p n="47">1. When the person concerned is registered as a person seeking employment, the competent national institution should at least complete Section 3.1, Box 4 and Section 5 of this form, which the former member of the temporary staff should present to it. He should then send it thus completed to the European Communities institution shown in Box 1.</p>
      <p n="48">2. Next, the national institution should at monthly intervals fill in the other appropriate sections, in addition to Section 3.1, Box 4 and Section 5 referred to above.</p>
      <p n="49">C. Instructions for the former member of the temporary staff</p>
      <p n="50">In order to receive the unemployment benefits provided for in Article 33 of Council Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 2799/85.</p>
      <p n="51">you should,</p>
      <p n="52">1. before the 31st day following the end of your employment as a member of the temporary staff, register as a person looking for work with the employment office of the Member State where you take up residence (or domicile).</p>
      <p n="53">Note: These offices are shown in a list prepared and updated by the Commission which will be provided by the institution to which you belonged.</p>
      <p n="54">2. comply with the obligations regarding unemployment laid down by the legislation of the Member State in which you register as a person looking for work;</p>
      <p n="55">3. present a copy of this form to the national employment office when you register as a person looking for work and subsequently once a month in order to have it filled in (see B above);</p>
      <p n="56">4. send the completed form to the institution shown in Box 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
