<TEI.2 id="jrc31988R3880-en" n="31988R3880" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31988R3880 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 3880/88 of 12 December 1988 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2262/84 laying down special measures in respect of olive oil</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>33 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R3880:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31988R3880:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31988R3880-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 3880/88 of 12 December 1988 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2262/84 laying down special measures in respect of olive oil</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 3880/88</p>
      <p n="4">of 12 December 1988</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 2262/84 laying down special measures in respect of olive oil</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, pursuant to Article 1 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 2262/84 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3462/87 (4), producer Member States must set up agencies for the purpose of carrying out certain checks and duties in connection with the olive oil production aid scheme; whereas, in accordance with Article 1 (5) of the said Regulation, the Council must adopt, before 1 January 1989, the method for financing the agencies' expenditure as from the 1989/90 marketing year;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, taking account of the important role that these bodies can play in ensuring that the production aid arrangements are applied correctly and in a uniform manner, provision should be made for a method of financing their actual expenditure which enables them to operate smoothly and efficiently within the framework of administrative autonomy provided for in the rules concerned; whereas that objective can be achieved via a method which combines Community financing and financing by the Member State;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the agencies in the four producer Member States concerned are not in an identical situation; whereas administrative and legal difficulties have resulted in delays in the setting-up and/or operation of the agencies in certain Member States; whereas those Member States did not make effective use of the maximum amounts which were earmarked for them during the initial phase when expenditure was fully chargeable to the Community; whereas the period covered by the said phase should therefore be extended by one year without increasing the maximum amounts already allocated under the existing rules,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1 (5) of Regulation (EEC) No 2262/84 is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="16">'5. Over a period of five years from 1 November 1984, the following percentages of the agency's actual expenditure shall be chargeable to the general budget of the European Communities:</p>
      <p n="17">- in the case of Italy, 100 % for the first three years, up to a maximum of Ecu 14 million, and 50 % for the fourth and fifth years,</p>
      <p n="18">- in the case of Greece, 100 % up to a maximum of Ecu 7 million.</p>
      <p n="19">Over a period of three years from 1 November 1989, 50 % of the actual expenditure of the Italian and the Greek agencies shall be chargeable to the general budget of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">In the case of Spain and Portugal, 100 % of the agency's actual expenditure during the period from 1 March 1986 to 31 October 1990 shall be covered by the general budget of the European Communities up to a maximum of Ecu 9 300 000 for Spain and Ecu 4 700 000 for Portugal. During the period from 1 November 1990 to 31 October 1992, 50 % of the expenditure in question shall be covered by the said budget.</p>
      <p n="21">Member States may, under conditions to be determined in accordance with the procedure provided for in Article 38 of Regulation No 136/66/EEC, cover part of the expenditure to be borne by them by a deduction from the Community aid granted for olive oil.</p>
      <p n="22">The Council, acting by qualified majority on a proposal from the Commission, shall adopt by 1 January 1992 the method for financing the expenditure in question as from the 1992/93 marketing year.'</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="26">Done at Brussels, 12 December 1988.</p>
      <p n="27">For the Council</p>
      <p n="28">The President</p>
      <p n="29">Y. POTTAKIS</p>
      <p n="30">(1) OJ No C 258, 5. 10. 1988, p. 5.</p>
      <p n="31">(2) Opinion delivered on 18 November 1988 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="32">(3) OJ No L 208, 3. 8. 1984, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="33">(4) OJ No L 329, 20. 11. 1987, p. 2.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
