<TEI.2 id="jrc31974D0578-en" n="31974D0578" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31974D0578 English</title>
        <title>74/578/Euratom: Commission Decision of 13 November 1974 amending the Decision of 13 January 1971 with regard to the place of work of the Director-General of the Joint Nuclear Research Centre (JRC) and its departments</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>15 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31974D0578:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31974D0578:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31974D0578-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">74/578/Euratom: Commission Decision of 13 November 1974 amending the Decision of 13 January 1971 with regard to the place of work of the Director-General of the Joint Nuclear Research Centre (JRC) and its departments</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 13 November 1974 amending the Decision of 13 January 1971 with regard to the place of work of the Director-General of the Joint Nuclear Research Centre (JRC) and its departments (74/578/Euratom)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular Article 8 thereof;</p>
      <p n="5">Whereas the Commission adopted a Decision on the reorganization of the Joint Nuclear Research Centre (JRC) on 13 January 1971 (1);</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the abovementioned Decision should be amended as regards the place of work of the Director General of the JRC,</p>
      <p n="7">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="8">Sole Article</p>
      <p n="9">Article 3 (2) of the Commission Decision of 13 January 1971 shall be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="10">"Brussels is the place of work of the Director-General and the departments directly attached to him."</p>
      <p n="11">Done at Brussels, 13 November 1974.</p>
      <p n="12">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="13">The President</p>
      <p n="14">François-Xavier ORTOLI</p>
      <p n="15">(1)OJ No L 16, 20.1.1971, p. 14.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
