<TEI.2 id="jrc31974D0215-en" n="31974D0215" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31974D0215 English</title>
        <title>74/215/EEC: Council Decision of 20 July 1972 concluding the Additional Agreement to the Agreement concerning products of the clock and watch industry between the European Economic Community and its member states and the Swiss confederation</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>15 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31974D0215:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31974D0215:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31974D0215-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">74/215/EEC: Council Decision of 20 July 1972 concluding the Additional Agreement to the Agreement concerning products of the clock and watch industry between the European Economic Community and its member states and the Swiss confederation</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 20 July 1972 concluding the Additional Agreement to the Agreement concerning products of the clock and watch industry between the European Economic Community and its Member States and the Swiss Confederation (74/215/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas it is necessary, for the proper functioning of the Agreement concerning products of the clock and watch industry between the European Economic Community and its Member States and the Swiss Confederation, signed in Geneva on 30 June 1967, that additional provisions be adopted,</p>
      <p n="7">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="8">Article 1</p>
      <p n="9">The Additional Agreement to the Agreement concerning products of the clock and watch industry between the European Economic Community and its Member States and the Swiss Confederation, is hereby concluded on behalf of the Community and the text thereof appears in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="10">&gt;Article 2</p>
      <p n="11">Mr Th. C. Hijzen, acting Director-General for External Trade of the Commission of the European Communities is hereby authorized to sign, on behalf of the Council, the Agreement specified in Article 1. This Agreement shall be binding on the Community.</p>
      <p n="12">Done at Brussels, 20 July 1972.</p>
      <p n="13">For the Council</p>
      <p n="14">The President</p>
      <p n="15">Th. E. WESTERTERP</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
