<TEI.2 id="jrc31983D0653-en" n="31983D0653" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31983D0653 English</title>
        <title>83/653/EEC: Council Decision of 20 December 1983 on the allocation of the possibilities for catching herring in the North Sea as from 1 January 1984</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31983D0653:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31983D0653:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31983D0653-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">83/653/EEC: Council Decision of 20 December 1983 on the allocation of the possibilities for catching herring in the North Sea as from 1 January 1984</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 20 December 1983 on the allocation of the possibilities for catching herring in the North Sea as from 1 January 1984 (83/653/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 170/83 of 25 January 1983 establishing a Community system for the conservation and management of fishery resources (1), and in particular Articles 4 (1) and 11 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the replenishment of the herring stock in the North Sea makes it possible to begin fishing for this species again;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, in order to enable herring fishermen to organize their fishing on a stable basis, rules for the distribution of this stock should be adopted on the basis of the development thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The possibilities for catching herring in the North Sea shall be allocated in accordance with the table annexed to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Brussels, 20 December 1983.</p>
      <p n="15">For the Council</p>
      <p n="16">The President</p>
      <p n="17">N. AKRITIDIS (1) OJ No L 24, 27.1.1983, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="18">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="19">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0023441"&gt;For Community shares between 155 000 and 251 000 tonnes, allocation would be made in accordance with the points on corresponding straight-line graphs.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
