<TEI.2 id="jrc31991D0370-en" n="31991D0370" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31991D0370 English</title>
        <title>91/370/EEC: Council Decision of 20 June 1991 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Swiss Confederation concerning direct insurance other than life assurance</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31991D0370:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31991D0370:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31991D0370-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">91/370/EEC: Council Decision of 20 June 1991 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Swiss Confederation concerning direct insurance other than life assurance</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 20 June 1991 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Swiss Confederation concerning direct insurance other than life assurance (91/370/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular the last sentence of Article 57 (2) and Article 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="6">In cooperation with the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (3),</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas it is desirable to approve the Agreement with Switzerland concerning direct insurance other than life assurance, signed at Luxembourg on 10 October 1989,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Swiss Confederation concerning direct</p>
      <p n="12">insurance other than life assurance is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="13">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">The President of the Council shall take the measures necessary for the exchange of instruments provided for in Article 44 of the Agreement (4).</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Luxembourg, 20 June 1991.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">R. GOEBBELS</p>
      <p n="20">(1) OJ No C 53, 5. 3. 1990, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="21">(2) OJ No C 72, 18. 3. 1991, p. 175, and Decision of 12 June 1991 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="22">(3) OJ No C 56, 7. 3. 1990, p. 27.</p>
      <p n="23">(4) The date of entry into force of the Agreement will be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities by the General-Secretariat of the Council.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
