<TEI.2 id="jrc32004R0429-en" n="32004R0429" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32004R0429 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 429/2004 of 4 March 2004 fixing the amount of private storage aid for certain fishery products in the 2004 fishing year</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004R0429:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004R0429:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2718</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3003</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4288</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32004R0429-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 429/2004 of 4 March 2004 fixing the amount of private storage aid for certain fishery products in the 2004 fishing year</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 429/2004</p>
      <p n="3">of 4 March 2004</p>
      <p n="4">fixing the amount of private storage aid for certain fishery products in the 2004 fishing year</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 104/2000 of 17 December 1999 on the common organisation of the markets in fishery and aquaculture products(1),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Commission Regulation (EC) No 2813/2000 of 21 December 2000 laying down detailed rules for the application of Council Regulation (EC) No 104/2000 as regards the grant of private storage aid for certain fishery products(2), and in particular Article 1 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) The aid should not exceed the sum of technical and financial costs recorded in the Community during the fishing year preceding the year in question.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) To discourage long-term storage, to shorten payment times and to reduce the burden of controls, private storage aid should be paid in one single instalment.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the Management Committee for Fishery Products,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">For the 2004 fishing year the amount of private storage aid for the products listed in Annex II to Regulation (EC) No 104/2000 shall be as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="19">It shall apply from 1 January 2004.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 4 March 2004.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ L 17, 21.1.2000, p. 22.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ L 326, 22.12.2000, p. 30.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
