<TEI.2 id="jrc32004R0663-en" n="32004R0663" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32004R0663 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 663/2004 of 7 April 2004 amending Regulation (EC) No 2300/97 on detailed rules to implement Council Regulation (EC) No 1221/97 laying down general rules for the application of measures to improve the production and marketing of honey</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004R0663:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004R0663:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">13</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1465</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1907</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32004R0663-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 663/2004 of 7 April 2004 amending Regulation (EC) No 2300/97 on detailed rules to implement Council Regulation (EC) No 1221/97 laying down general rules for the application of measures to improve the production and marketing of honey</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 663/2004</p>
      <p n="3">of 7 April 2004</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 2300/97 on detailed rules to implement Council Regulation (EC) No 1221/97 laying down general rules for the application of measures to improve the production and marketing of honey</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 1221/97 of 25 June 1997 laying down general rules for the application of measures to improve the production and marketing of honey(1), and in particular Article 5 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Commission Regulation (EC) No 2300/97(2) lays down provisions for the implementation of the national annual programmes provided for in Regulation (EC) No 1221/97. Article 2(1) of Regulation (EC) No 2300/97 provides that the Member States are to notify their programmes to the Commission by 15 April each year.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) EU membership should enable the Czech Republic, Estonia, Cyprus, Latvia, Lithuania, Hungary, Malta, Poland, Slovenia and Slovakia to benefit from the national programmes provided for in Regulation (EC) No 1221/97. With a view to being able to examine the programmes in the same way for all Member States, the date for notifying programmes should be postponed, for 2004, to 15 May 2004.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) Regulation (EC) No 2300/97 should be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="12">(4) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Poultrymeat and Eggs,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2(1) of Regulation (EC) No 2300/97, is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="16">"1. Member States shall notify their programmes to the Commission before 15 April of each year. Nevertheless, for 2004, Member States shall notify their programmes by 15 May at the latest."</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="19">It shall apply to the annual programmes for the 2004/2005 marketing year.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 7 April 2004.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ L 173, 1.7.1997, p. 1. Regulation amended by Regulation (EC) No 2070/98 (OJ L 265, 30.9.1998, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ L 319, 21.11.1997, p. 4. Regulation last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1387/2003 (OJ L 196, 2.8.2003, p. 22).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
