<TEI.2 id="jrc32004D0283-en" n="32004D0283" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32004D0283 English</title>
        <title>2004/283/EC: Commission Decision of 26 March 2004 amending Decision 2003/526/EC concerning protection measures relating to classical swine fever in Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2004) 965)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>41 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004D0283:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004D0283:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1085</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1318</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1445</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1712</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2356</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2560</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4839</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5369</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32004D0283-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2004/283/EC: Commission Decision of 26 March 2004 amending Decision 2003/526/EC concerning protection measures relating to classical swine fever in Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2004) 965)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 26 March 2004</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 2003/526/EC concerning protection measures relating to classical swine fever in Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2004) 965)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2004/283/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 90/425/EEC of 26 June 1990 concerning veterinary and zootechnical checks applicable in intra-Community trade in certain live animals and products with a view to the completion of the internal market(1) and in particular Article 10(4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) In response to classical swine fever in certain bordering parts of Belgium, Germany, France and Luxembourg, the Commission has adopted, inter alia, Decision 2003/526/EC(2) which established certain additional disease control measures.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) The classical swine fever situation in Belgium has largely improved and the measures adopted by Decision 2003/526/EC concerning Belgium should no longer apply.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) Classical swine fever has spread further in feral pigs in Bas-Rhin in France.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) In the light of the overall disease situation in Germany, France and Luxembourg it is appropriate to extend the validity of Decision 2003/526/EC.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) Decision 2003/526/EC should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">Decision 2003/526/EC is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="21">1. The title is replaced by the following: "Commission Decision 2003/526/EC concerning protection measures relating to classical swine fever in certain Member States".</p>
      <p n="22">2. In Article 2(1) "Belgium," is deleted.</p>
      <p n="23">3. In Article 4(1) and (2) the words "Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg" are replaced by the words: "certain Member States".</p>
      <p n="24">4. Article 4(3), is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="25">"3. The health certificate provided for in Article 1 of Commission Decision 95/483/EC(3) accompanying embryos and ova of swine dispatched from the Member States concerned shall be completed by the following:'Embryos/ova(4) in accordance with Commission Decision 2003/526/EC of 18 July 2003 concerning certain protection measures relating to classical swine fever in certain Member States(5).'"</p>
      <p n="26">5. In Article 11 "30 April 2004" is replaced by "31 October 2004".</p>
      <p n="27">6. The Annex is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="28">(a) point 1. Belgium is deleted;</p>
      <p n="29">(b) in point 2. France, the second indent is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="30">"- the territory of the Department of Bas-Rhin and Moselle located: Western of the road D 264 from the border with Germany at Wissembourg to Soultz sous forêts; northern of the road D 28 from Soultz sous forêts to Reichshoffen (the whole territory of the Municipality of Reichshoffen is included in in the area); eastern of the road D 62 from Reichshoffen to Bitche and then eastern of the road D 35 from Bitche to the border with Germany (in Ohrenthal); southern of the border with Germany from Ohrenthal to Wissembourg."</p>
      <p n="31">Article 2</p>
      <p n="32">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="33">Done at Brussels, 26 March 2004.</p>
      <p n="34">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="35">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="36">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="37">(1) OJ L 224, 18.8.1990, p. 29. Directive as last amended by Directive 2002/33/EC of the European Parlament and of the Council (OJ L 315, 19.11.2002, p. 14).</p>
      <p n="38">(2) OJ L 183, 22.7.2003, p. 46. Decision as last amended by Decision 2003/851/EC (OJ L 322, 9.12. 2003, p. 30).</p>
      <p n="39">(3) OJ L 275, 18.8.1995, p. 30.</p>
      <p n="40">(4) Delete as appropriate.</p>
      <p n="41">(5) OJ L 183, 22.7.2003, p. 46.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
