<TEI.2 id="jrc32004R0455-en" n="32004R0455" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32004R0455 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 455/2004 of 11 March 2004 amending Regulation (EC) No 466/2001 as regards patulin (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>33 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004R0455:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32004R0455:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1240</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2078</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2531</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">6052</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32004R0455-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 455/2004 of 11 March 2004 amending Regulation (EC) No 466/2001 as regards patulin (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 455/2004</p>
      <p n="3">of 11 March 2004</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 466/2001 as regards patulin</p>
      <p n="5">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 315/93 of 8 February 1993 laying down Community procedures for contaminants in food(1), and in particular Article 2(3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Commission Regulation (EC) No 466/2001(2), sets maximum levels for certain contaminants in foodstuffs. Maximum levels have been established for amongst others patulin.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) A maximum level of 10,0 μg/kg has been established for apple juice and solid apple products, including apple compote and apple puree, for infants and young children and other baby food on the condition that a method of analysis would have been validated by an international collaborative ring trial to be performed before 1 November 2003 in order to demonstrate that the level of 10 μg/kg patulin can be reliably determined. In case there was no evidence by 1 November 2003 that the level of 10 μg/kg could be reliably determined, the level of 25 μg/kg would apply.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) A collaborative trial has been organised to provide the evidence that the level of 10,0 μg/kg can be reliably determined. A report indicating that a method can reliably determine levels of patulin in clear apple juice and fruit puree at 10 μg/kg and lower has been provided on 27 October 2003.</p>
      <p n="13">(4) It is appropriate to adopt transitional arrangements for products manufactured and put on the market before the date of application.</p>
      <p n="14">(5) Regulation (EC) No 466/2001 should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="15">(6) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="16">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="17">Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">Regulation (EC) No 466/2001 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="19">1. In Article 7, the following paragraph is added:"Τhe maximum levels established in point 2.3. Patulin of section 2 (Mycotoxins) of Annex I shall not apply to products which have been lawfully placed on the Community market before 1 November 2003. The burden of proving when the products were placed on the market shall be borne by the food business operator."</p>
      <p n="20">2. Footnote 4 of point 2.3 Patulin of section 2 (Mycotoxins) of Annex I is deleted.</p>
      <p n="21">3. The second indent of the point 2.3.4. of section 2 (Mycotoxins) of Annex I shall read:</p>
      <p n="22">"- other baby foods other than processed cereal-based foods (4)".</p>
      <p n="23">4. Footnote 5 of point 2.3 Patulin of section 2 (Mycotoxins) of Annex I becomes footnote 4 and shall read:</p>
      <p n="24">"(4) Baby foods other than processed cereal-based foods as defined in Commission Directive 96/5/EC of 16 February 1996 on processed cereal based foods and baby foods for infants and young children (OJ L 49, 28.2.1996, p. 17) as last amended by Directive 2003/13/EC (OJ L 41, 14.02.2003, p. 33)".</p>
      <p n="25">Article 2</p>
      <p n="26">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 20th day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 11 March 2004.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="31">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ L 37, 13.2.1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="33">(2) OJ L 77, 16.3.2001, p.1. Regulation as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1425/2003 (OJ L 203, 12.8.2003, p. 1).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
