<TEI.2 id="jrc31990R2698-en" n="31990R2698" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31990R2698 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 2698/90 of 17 September 1990 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3906/89 in order to extend economic aid to other countries of Central and Eastern Europe</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>45 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990R2698:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990R2698:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31990R2698-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 2698/90 of 17 September 1990 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3906/89 in order to extend economic aid to other countries of Central and Eastern Europe</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 2698/90</p>
      <p n="4">of 17 September 1990</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 3906/89 in order to extend economic aid to other countries of Central and Eastern Europe</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Community and its Member States have decided to take concerted action with certain non-member countries in the form of measures intended to support the process of economic and social reform under way in Hungary and Poland; whereas Regulation (EEC) No 3906/89 (3) lays down the conditions for the provision of economic aid to these countries;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the Group of 24 countries and the Community decided at the ministerial meeting on 4 July 1990 that the situation in certain other countries of Central and Eastern Europe warranted an extension of the economic restructuring aid to these countries;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas provision must be made annually in the general budget of the European Communities for appropriate Community financing,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Regulation (EEC) No 3906/89 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. The title is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="17">'Council Regulation (EEC) No 3906/89 of 18 December 1989 on economic aid to certain countries of Central and Eastern Europe.'</p>
      <p n="18">2. Article 1 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="19">'Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">The Community shall make economic aid available to the countries of Central and Eastern Europe listed in the Annex in accordance with the criteria laid down in this Regulation.'</p>
      <p n="21">3. Article 2 is deleted.</p>
      <p n="22">4. In Article 3 (1):</p>
      <p n="23">- 'in Poland and Hungary' and 'in Hungary and Poland' are replaced by 'in the countries referred to in Article 1' and 'of the countries referred to in Article 1' respectively,</p>
      <p n="24">- the following subparagraph is added:</p>
      <p n="25">'The aid may also be used to provide humanitarian assistance'.</p>
      <p n="26">5. In Article 7 (1) and in Article 9 (1), 'of Poland and Hungary' and 'in Poland and Hungary' are replaced by 'of the countries referred to in Article 1' and 'in the countries referred to in Article 1' respectively.</p>
      <p n="27">6. The following Annex is added:</p>
      <p n="28">'ANNEX</p>
      <p n="29">BULGARIA</p>
      <p n="30">CZECHOSLOVAKIA</p>
      <p n="31">GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</p>
      <p n="32">HUNGARY</p>
      <p n="33">POLAND</p>
      <p n="34">ROMANIA</p>
      <p n="35">YUGOSLAVIA'.</p>
      <p n="36">Article 2</p>
      <p n="37">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="38">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="39">Done at Brussels, 17 September 1990.</p>
      <p n="40">For the Council</p>
      <p n="41">The President</p>
      <p n="42">G. DE MICHELIS</p>
      <p n="43">(1) OJ No C 191, 31. 7. 1990, p. 17.</p>
      <p n="44">(2) OJ No C 231, 17. 9. 1990.</p>
      <p n="45">(3) OJ No L 375, 23. 12. 1989, p. 11.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
