<TEI.2 id="jrc31990R1186-en" n="31990R1186" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31990R1186 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 1186/90 of 7 May 1990 extending the scope of the Community scale for the classification of carcases of adult bovine animals</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>46 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990R1186:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990R1186:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31990R1186-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 1186/90 of 7 May 1990 extending the scope of the Community scale for the classification of carcases of adult bovine animals</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) N° 1186/90</p>
      <p n="3">of 7 May 1990</p>
      <p n="4">extending the scope of the Community scale for the classification of carcases of adult bovine animals</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (3),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Regulation (EEC) No 1208/81 (4) determines a Community scale for the classification of carcases of adult bovine animals; whereas Article 6 of that Regulation limits the application of the scale to the establishment of market prices and the application of intervention measures;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas progress made in the application of the scale and experience gained enable its extension to all carcases placed on the market to be contemplated; whereas, to that end, provision should be made for those products to be classified by approved slaughterhouses, which alone may market the latter throughout the Community in accordance with Council Directive 64/433/EEC of 26 June 1964 on health problems affecting intra-community trade in fresh meat (5), as last amended by Directive 88/657/EEC (6);</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the natural or legal person who has the slaughtering carried out should be informed of the result of the classification of the animals delivered for slaughter; whereas such a classification on the one hand permits the price to</p>
      <p n="13">be justified and, on the other hand, is likely to lead to</p>
      <p n="14">an improvement in quality and better upgrading of production,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">1. From 1 January 1991, slaughterhouses approved under Article 8 of Directive 64/433/EEC shall be obliged to take measures to ensure that by 1 January 1992 at the</p>
      <p n="18">latest all carcases or half-carcases from animals slaughtered in slaughterhouses approved under Article 8 of Directive 64/433/EEC and bearing a health mark as provided for in Article 3 of that Directive are classified and identified in accordance with the Community scale for the classification of carcases of adult bovine animals introduced by Regulation (EEC) No 1208/81.</p>
      <p n="19">2. From the date on which the provisions of paragraph 1 are implemented, the results of the classification carried</p>
      <p n="20">out in accordance with Article 4 of Regulation (EEC)</p>
      <p n="21">N° 1208/81 shall be communicated in writing to the natural or legal person who has the slaughtering carried out.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 2</p>
      <p n="23">In accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 27 of Regulation (EEC) N° 805/68 (7), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) N° 571/89 (8), the Commission shall adopt the arrangements for implementing this Regulation and in particular those relating to:</p>
      <p n="24">(a) the system of identification referred to in Article 1 (1);</p>
      <p n="25">(b) any derogations:</p>
      <p n="26">- referred to in Article 5 of Directive 88/409/EEC (9) for slaughterhouses wishing to restrict their production to the local market,</p>
      <p n="27">- which may be granted to Member States which so request for slaughterhouses in which few bovine animals are slaughtered.</p>
      <p n="28">Article 3</p>
      <p n="29">The Member States shall take all the measures necessary to ensure that the provisions of this Regulation are applied and to penalize any infringements.</p>
      <p n="30">Article 4</p>
      <p n="31">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="32">It shall apply from 1 January 1991.</p>
      <p n="33">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="34">Done at Brussels, 7 May 1990.</p>
      <p n="35">For the Council</p>
      <p n="36">The President</p>
      <p n="37">G. COLLINS</p>
      <p n="38">(1) OJ N° C 49, 28. 2. 1990, p. 55.</p>
      <p n="39">(2) OJ N° C 96, 17. 4. 1990.</p>
      <p n="40">(3) OJ N° C 112, 7. 5. 1990, p. 34.</p>
      <p n="41">(4) OJ N° L 123, 7. 5. 1981, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="42">(5) OJ N° 121, 29. 7. 1964, p. 2012/64.</p>
      <p n="43">(6) OJ N° L 382, 31. 12. 1988, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="44">(7) OJ N° L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="45">(8) OJ N° L 61, 4. 3. 1989, p. 43.</p>
      <p n="46">(9) OJ N° L 194, 22. 7. 1988, p. 28.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
