<TEI.2 id="jrc31990R2617-en" n="31990R2617" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31990R2617 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2617/90 of 11 September 1990 amending Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 on the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter intended for direct consumption in the Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990R2617:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990R2617:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31990R2617-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2617/90 of 11 September 1990 amending Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 on the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter intended for direct consumption in the Community</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 2617/90</p>
      <p n="4">of 11 September 1990</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 on the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter intended for direct consumption in the Community</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3879/89 (2), and in particular Article 7a (3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 (3), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1265/90 (4), provides for the granting of aid for concentrated butter obtained from butter or cream originating from the market and intended for direct consumption in the Community; whereas concentrated butter must be put up in sealed packs bearing one or more of the indications in Article 10 (3) of that Regulation; whereas, in view of national provisions on the description of foodstuffs, those indications do not cover all marketing possibilities and so should be supplemented;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Article 14 of Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 provides for certain entries to be made on the T 5 control copy when packed concentrated butter is dispatched to be taken over by the retail trade in another Member State; whereas, to avoid any confusion, it should be specified that that document is to be issued and used in accordance with Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2823/87 (5);</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="15">1. the sixth indent of Article 10 (3) is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="16">'- "Beurre concentré - Règlement (CEE) no 429/90" or "beurre concentré pour la cuisine - Règlement (CEE) no 429/90" or "beurre concentré pour la cuisine et la pâtisserie - Règlement (CEE) no 429/90" or "beurre cuisinier - Règlement (CEE) no 429/90" or "beurre de cuisine - Règlement (CEE) no 429/90",';</p>
      <p n="17">2. the introductory sentence of Article 14 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="18">'Where packed concentrated butter is dispatched to be taken over by the retail trade in another Member State, the necessary proof shall be furnished by production of the T 5 control copy issued and used in accordance with Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2823/87 (*). Box 104 of the T 5 control copy shall carry one of the following entries:</p>
      <p n="19">(*) OJ No L 270, 23. 9. 1987, p. 1.'</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Brussels, 11 September 1990.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="26">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="27">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="28">(2) OJ No L 378, 27. 12. 1989, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="29">(3) OJ No L 45, 21. 2. 1990, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="30">(4) OJ No L 124, 15. 5. 1990, p. 34.</p>
      <p n="31">(5) OJ No L 270, 23. 9. 1987, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
