<TEI.2 id="jrc31990D0530-en" n="31990D0530" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31990D0530 English</title>
        <title>90/530/EEC: Council Decision of 8 October 1990 concerning the conclusion of the framework agreement for trade and economic cooperation between the European economic community and the argentine republic</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>37 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990D0530:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990D0530:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31990D0530-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">90/530/EEC: Council Decision of 8 October 1990 concerning the conclusion of the framework agreement for trade and economic cooperation between the European economic community and the argentine republic</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 8 October 1990 concerning the conclusion of the Framework Agreement for trade and economic cooperation between the European Economic Community and the Argentine Republic (90/530/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 113 and 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, for the attainment of its aims in the sphere of external economic relations, the Community should approve the Framework Agreement for trade and economic cooperation with the Argentine Republic;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas certain forms of cooperation proposed under the Agreement exceed the powers of action provided for in the field of the common commercial policy,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The Framework Agreement for trade and economic cooperation between the European Economic Community and the Argentine Republic is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="12">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">The President of the Council, on behalf of the Community, shall give the notification provided for in Article 11 of the Agreement (3).</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">The Commission, assisted by representatives of the Member States, shall represent the Community in the Joint Committee set up by Article 7 of the Agreement.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Luxembourg, 8 October 1990.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Council</p>
      <p n="19">The President</p>
      <p n="20">E. RUBBI</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ No C 87, 5. 4. 1990, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) OJ No C 231, 17. 9. 1990.</p>
      <p n="23">(3) The date of entry into force of the Agreement will be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities by the General Secretariat of the Council.</p>
      <p n="24">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="25">EXCHANGE OF LETTERS</p>
      <p n="26">A. Letter No 1 Sir,</p>
      <p n="27">We should be obliged if you would confirm that your Government is in agreement with the following:</p>
      <p n="28">With regard to the barriers to trade which may arise for the European Economic Community and its Member States or the Argentine Republic as a result of the operation of shipping, it has been agreed that mutually satisfactory solutions on shipping should be sought with a view to promoting trade development.</p>
      <p n="29">To this end, it has likewise been agreed that the issue should be discussed at meetings of the Joint Committee.</p>
      <p n="30">Please accept, Sir, the assurance of our highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="31">On behalf of</p>
      <p n="32">the Council of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="33">B. Letter No 2 Sirs,</p>
      <p n="34">I have the honour to confirm that my Government is in agreement with the following:</p>
      <p n="35">'With regard to the barriers to trade which may arise for the European Economic Community and its Member States or the Argentine Republic as a result of the operation of shipping, it has been agreed that mutually satisfactory solutions on shipping should be sought with a view to promoting trade development.</p>
      <p n="36">To this end, it has likewise been agreed that the issue should be discussed at meeting of the Joint Committee.'</p>
      <p n="37">Please accept, Sirs, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
