<TEI.2 id="jrc31990D0637-en" n="31990D0637" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31990D0637 English</title>
        <title>90/637/EEC: Council Decision of 22 October 1990 concerning the conclusion of a protocol renewing the cooperation agreement between the European economic community and the kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>14 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990D0637:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990D0637:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31990D0637-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">90/637/EEC: Council Decision of 22 October 1990 concerning the conclusion of a protocol renewing the cooperation agreement between the European economic community and the kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 22 October 1990 concerning the conclusion of a Protocol renewing the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade (90/637/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the conclusion of a Protocol renewing the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community, and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade (1) is in their mutual interest;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the said Protocol should be approved,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The Protocol renewing the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="11">The text of the Protocol is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the Agreement referred to in Article 1 in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Luxembourg, 22 October 1990. For the Council The President G. DE MICHELIS</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
