<TEI.2 id="jrc31990L0439-en" n="31990L0439" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31990L0439 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 90/439/EEC of 24 July 1990 amending the Annex to Council Directive 82/471/EEC concern ing certain products used in animal feedingstuff</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990L0439:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31990L0439:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31990L0439-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 90/439/EEC of 24 July 1990 amending the Annex to Council Directive 82/471/EEC concern ing certain products used in animal feedingstuff</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE</p>
      <p n="4">of 24 July 1990</p>
      <p n="5">amending the Annex to Council Directive 82/471/EEC concern ing certain products used in animal feedingstuff</p>
      <p n="6">(90/439/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Directive 82/471/EEC of 30 June 1982 concerning certain products used in animal nutrition (1), as last amended by Commission Directive 89/520/EEC (2), and in particular Article 6 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Directive 82/471/EEC provides for regular amendment of the content of the Annex thereto as a result of developments in scientific or technical knowledge;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the study of two new products belonging to the group of protein products obtained from micro-organisms and the amino acids group has shown that these products fulfill the requirements of Directive 82/471/EEC; whereas the use of these products in animal nutrition should, therefore, be permitted under certain conditions;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordanced with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Feedingstuffs,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Annex to Directive 82/471/EEC is amended as set out in the Annex hereto.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with Article 1 not later than 30 June 1991. The shall immediately inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="18">The provisions adopted pursuant to the first paragraph shall make express reference to this Directive.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 3</p>
      <p n="20">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 24 July 1990.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ No L 213, 21. 7. 1982, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ No L 270, 19. 9. 1989, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="27">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="28">1. Under 1.4 'Lower fungi', the following group of products and products are added:</p>
      <p n="29">1.2.3.4.5.6.7 // // // // // // // // 1 // 2 // 3 // 4 // 5 // 6 // 7 // // // // // // // // Name of product group // Name of product // Chemical designation of product or identity of micro-organism // Nutrient substrate (specifications, if any) // Composition characteristics of product // Animal species // Special provisions // // // // // // // // '1.4.1. Products from production of antibiotics by fermentation // 1.4.1.1. Mycelium, wet by-product from the production of penicillin, ensiled by means of lactobacillus brevis, plantarun, sake, collenoid and streptococcus lactis to inactive the penicillin and heat treated // Nitrogenous compound Penicillium chrysogenum ATCC 48271 // Different sources of carbohydrates and their hydrolysates // Nitrogen expressed as crude protein: min. 7 % // Ruminants pigs // Declaration to be made on the label or packaging of the product: - the name: "Mycelium silage from the production of penicillin" - Nitrogen expressed as crude protein - crude ash - moisture - animal species or category Declaration to be made on the label or packaging of the compound feedingstuff: the name: "Mycelium silage from the production of penicillin".' // // // // // // //</p>
      <p n="30">2. In group 3.2 'Lysine', the following product is added:</p>
      <p n="31">1.2.3.4.5.6.7 // // // // // // // // 1 // 2 // 3 // 4 // 5 // 6 // 7 // // // // // // // // Name of product group // Name of product // Chemical designation of product or identity of micro-organism // Nutrient substrate (specifications, if any) // Composition characteristics of product // Animal species // Special provisions // // // // // // // // // '3.2.6. L-lysine phosphate and its by-products produced by fermentation with Brevibacterium lactofermentum NRRL B-11470 // [NH2-(CH2)4-CH (NH2)-COOH] ; H3PO4 // Sucrose ammonia and fish solubles // L-lysine: min. 35 % Phosphorus: min. 4,3 % // Poultry, pigs // Declaration to be made on the label or packaging of the product: - the name "L-lysine phosphate and its by-products from fermentation". - L-lysine and moisture content.' // // // // // // //</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
