<TEI.2 id="jrc32000R2224-en" n="32000R2224" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000R2224 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2224/2000 of 6 October 2000 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>202 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R2224:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R2224:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1264</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1519</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2709</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3275</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">863</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000R2224-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2224/2000 of 6 October 2000 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2224/2000</p>
      <p n="3">of 6 October 2000</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation No 136/66/EEC of 22 September 1966 on the common organisation of the market in oils and fats(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2702/1999(2),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 of 17 July 1984 laying down general rules on the granting of aid for the production of olive oil and of aid to olive oil producer organisations(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1639/98(4), and in particular Article 19 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Article 18 of Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 lays down that the olive yields and oil yields are to be fixed by homogenous production zones, on the basis of the figures supplied by producer Member States.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) The production zones are designated in the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 of 30 October 1997 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones(5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2075/98(6). For administrative and structural reasons, amendments should be made to the homogenous production zones for the 1999/2000 marketing year, particularly in Spain and Italy.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Oils and Fats,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. Point A is replaced by the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="17">2. In point D, under the heading "Comunidad autònoma Aragón":</p>
      <p n="18">(a) in the province "Zaragoza":</p>
      <p n="19">- "Los Pintanos, Sobradiel, Añon, Albeta, El Burgo de Ebro e Utebo" are added to zone 1,</p>
      <p n="20">- "Aladrén, Atea, Fuentes de Jiloca, Malanquilla, Mara, Montón, Murero, Nuévalos, Villarroya de la Sierra and Velilla de Jiloca" are added to zone 2,</p>
      <p n="21">- "Cuarte de Huerva" is added to zone 3,</p>
      <p n="22">- "Añón, Remolinos, Bórboles, Murillo de Gallego and Pinseque" are added to zone 4,</p>
      <p n="23">- "Abanto, Montón, Ruesca, Villarroya de la Sierra, Belmonte de Calatayud, Cervera de la Cañada and Salillas de Jalón" are added to zone 5,</p>
      <p n="24">- "Cuarte de Huerva, Alborge and Velilla de Ebro" are added to zone 6;</p>
      <p n="25">(b) in the province "Teruel":</p>
      <p n="26">- "Plou" is added to zone 3,</p>
      <p n="27">- "La Cerollera, La Codoñera, Lledo, Las Parras de Castellote and Torrevelilla" are added to zone 4;</p>
      <p n="28">(c) in the province "Huesca":</p>
      <p n="29">- "Albero Bajo" is added to zone 2,</p>
      <p n="30">- "Abizanda, Arén, Argavieso, Azara, Azlor, Baells, Barcabo, Benabarre, Casbas de Huesca, Estopiñán del Castillo, La Fueva, Graus, Isabena, Loporzano, Loscorrales, Lupiñen-Ortilla, Piracés, Salas Altas, Salillas, Senés de Alcubierre, Tardienta, Torralba de Aragón and Torres de Alcanadre" are added to zone 5.</p>
      <p n="31">Article 2</p>
      <p n="32">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="33">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="34">Done at Brussels, 6 October 2000.</p>
      <p n="35">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="36">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="37">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="38">(1) OJ 172, 30.9.1966, p. 3025/66.</p>
      <p n="39">(2) OJ L 327, 21.12.1999, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="40">(3) OJ L 208, 3.8.1984, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="41">(4) OJ L 210, 28.7.1998, p. 38.</p>
      <p n="42">(5) OJ L 297, 31.10.1997, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="43">(6) OJ L 265, 30.9.1998, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="44">ANEXO/BILAG/ANHANG/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ/ANNEX/ANNEXE/ALLEGATO/BIJLAGE/ANEXO/LIITE/BILAGA</p>
      <p n="45">"A. ITALIA/ITALIEN/ITALIEN/ΙΤΑΛΙΑ/ITALY/ITALIE/ITALIA/ITALIË/ITÁLIA/ITALIA/ITALIEN</p>
      <p n="46">Imperia:</p>
      <p n="47">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="48">Genova:</p>
      <p n="49">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="50">La Spezia:</p>
      <p n="51">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="52">Brescia:</p>
      <p n="53">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="54">2. Gardone Riviera, Gargnano, Limone sul Garda, Salò, Tignale, Toscolano-Maderno, Tremosine.</p>
      <p n="55">Verona:</p>
      <p n="56">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="57">Pesaro:</p>
      <p n="58">1. Barchi, Cartoceto, Colbordolo, Fano, Fossombrone, Fratte Rosa, Gabicce Mare, Gradara, Isola del Piano, Mombaroccio, Mondavio, Mondolfo, Monte Porzio, Monteciccardo, Montefelcino, Montelabbate, Montemaggiore al Metauro, Orciano di Pesaro, Pesaro, Piagge, Saltara, San Costanzo, San Giorgio di Pesaro, Sant'Angelo in Lizzola, Sant'Ippolito, Serrungarina, Tavullia.</p>
      <p n="59">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="60">Ancona:</p>
      <p n="61">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="62">Ascoli Piceno:</p>
      <p n="63">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="64">Massa Carrara:</p>
      <p n="65">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="66">Lucca:</p>
      <p n="67">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="68">Pistoia:</p>
      <p n="69">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="70">Firenze:</p>
      <p n="71">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="72">Prato:</p>
      <p n="73">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="74">Livorno:</p>
      <p n="75">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="76">Pisa:</p>
      <p n="77">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="78">Arezzo:</p>
      <p n="79">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="80">Siena:</p>
      <p n="81">1. Abbadia San Salvatore, Castiglione d'Orcia, Montalcino, Piancastagnaio, Pienza, San Giovanni d'Asso, San Quirico d'Orcia, Sarteano.</p>
      <p n="82">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="83">Grosseto:</p>
      <p n="84">1. Arcidosso, Castel del Piano, Castell'Azzara, Cinigiano, Monterotondo Marittimo, Montieri, Roccalbegna, Santa Fiora, Seggiano, Semproniano.</p>
      <p n="85">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="86">3. Capalbio, Castiglione delta Pescaia, Follonica, Grosseto, Isola del Giglio, Monte Argentario, Orbetello, Scarlino.</p>
      <p n="87">Perugia:</p>
      <p n="88">1. Bastia, Bettona, Bevagna, Cannara, Cascia, Castel Ritaldi, Castiglione del Lago, Cerreto di Spoleto, Citerna, Città della Pieve, Città di Castello, Collazzone, Corciano, Costacciaro, Deruta, Fossato di Vico, Fratta Todina, Giano dell'Umbria, Gualdo Cattaneo, Gualdo Tadino, Gubbio, Lisciano Niccone, Magione, Marsciano, Massa Martana, Monte Castello di Vibio, Monte Santa Maria Tiberina, Montefalco, Monteleone di Spoleto, Montone, Nocera Umbra, Norcia, Paciano, Panicale, Passignano sut Trasimeno, Perugia, Piegaro, Pietralunga, Poggiodomo, Preci, San Giustino, Sant'Anatolia di Narco, Scheggia e Pascelupo, Scheggino, Sellano, Sigillo, Todi, Torgiano, Tuoro sul Trasimeno, Umbertide, Valfabbrica, Vallo di Nera, Valtopina.</p>
      <p n="89">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="90">Viterbo:</p>
      <p n="91">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="92">2. Arlena di Castro, Canino, Cellere, Farnese, Ischia di Castro, Montalto di Castro, Tessennano.</p>
      <p n="93">Rieti:</p>
      <p n="94">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="95">2. Castelnuovo di Farfa, Fara in Sabina, Poggio Nativo, Toffia.</p>
      <p n="96">Roma:</p>
      <p n="97">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="98">2. Albano Laziale, Anguillara Sabazia, Anzio, Ardea, Ariccia, Artena, Bracciano, Campagnano di Roma, Canale Monterano, Capena, Casape, Castel Gandolfo, Castel Madama, Castelnuovo di Porto, Cave, Cerveteri, Ciampino, Civitavecchia, Civitella San Paolo, Colleferro, Colonna, Fiano Romano, Filacciano, Fiumicino, Formello, Frascati, Gallicano nel Lazio, Gavignano, Genazzano, Genzano di Roma, Grottaferrata, Guidonia Montecelio, Labico, Ladispoli, Lanuvio, Lariano, Magliano Romano, Manziana, Marcellina, Marino, Mazzano Romano, Mentana, Monte Porzio Catone, Montecompatri, Montelibretti, Monterotondo, Montorio Romano, Moricone, Morlupo, Nazzano, Nemi, Nerola, Nettuno, Olevano Romano, Palestrina, Palombara Sabina, Poli, Pomezia, Ponzano Romano, Riano, Rignano Flaminio, Roma, Sacrofano, San Cesareo, San Gregorio da Sassola, San Polo dei Cavalieri, San Vito Romano, Sant'Angelo Romano, Sant'Oreste, Santa Marinella, Tivoli, Torrita Tiberina, Trevignano Romano, Valmontone, Velletri, Zagarolo.</p>
      <p n="99">Latina:</p>
      <p n="100">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="101">Frosinone:</p>
      <p n="102">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="103">Caserta:</p>
      <p n="104">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="105">Benevento:</p>
      <p n="106">1. Airola, Amorosi, Arpaia, Bonea, Bucciano, Campoli del Monte Taburno, Castelvetere in Val Fortore, Cautano, Cerreto Sannita, Cusano Mutri, Dugenta, Durazzano, Faicchio, Foglianise, Forchia, Fragneto Monforte, Fragneto l'Abate, Frasso Telesino, Ginestra degli Schiavoni, Guardia Sanframondi, Limatola, Melizzano, Moiano, Molinara, Montefalcone di Val Fortore, Montesarchio, Paolisi, Paupisi, Pietraroja, Puglianello, San Lorenzello, San Lorenzo Maggiore, San Lupo, San Salvatore Telesino, Sant'Agata de' Goti, Solopaca, Telese, Tocco Caudio, Torrecuso, Vitulano.</p>
      <p n="107">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="108">Napoli:</p>
      <p n="109">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="110">Avellino:</p>
      <p n="111">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="112">Salerno:</p>
      <p n="113">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="114">2. Agropoli, Albanella, Alfano, Altavilla Silentina, Aquara, Auletta, Battipaglia, Bellizzi, Bellosguardo, Buccino, Caggiano, Campagna, Campora, Capaccio, Casal Velino, Casaletto Spartano, Caselle in Pittari, Castel San Lorenzo, Castelcivita, Castellabate, Castelnuovo Cilento, Cicerale, Colliano, Controne, Contursi Terme, Corleto Monforte, Cuccaro Vetere, Eboli, Felitto, Futani, Giffoni Valle Piana, Giffoni sei Casali, Gioi, Giungano, Ispani, Laureana Cilento, Laurino, Laurito, Lustra, Magliano Vetere, Moio della Civitella, Montano Antilia, Montecorice, Montecorvino Pugliano, Montecorvino Rovella, Monteforte Cilento, Morigerati, Ogliastro Cilento, Olevano sul Tusciano, Oliveto Citra, Omignano, Orria, Ottati, Palomonte, Perdifumo, Perito, Pertosa, Piaggine, Pollica, Postiglione, Prignano Cilento, Roccadaspide, Roccagloriosa, Rofrano, Romagnano al Monte, Roscigno, Rutino, Sacco, Salento, Salvitelle, San Cipriano Picentino, San Gregorio Magno, San Mauro Cilento, Sant'Angelo a Fasanella, Sarno, Serramezzana, Serre, Sessa Cilento, Sicignano degli Alburni, Stella Cilento, Stio, Torchiara, Torraca, Torre Orsaia, Tortorella, Trentinara, Valle dell'Angelo, Valva, Vibonati.</p>
      <p n="115">3. Ascea, Camerota, Cannalonga, Celle di Bulgheria, Centola, Ceraso, Novi Velia, Pisciotta, San Giovanni a Piro, San Mauro la Bruca, Santa Marina, Sapri, Vallo della Lucania.</p>
      <p n="116">L'Aquila:</p>
      <p n="117">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="118">Teramo:</p>
      <p n="119">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="120">2. Alba Adriatica, Ancarano, Atri, Bellante, Canzano, Castellalto, Castiglione Messer Raimondo, Castilenti, Cellino Attanasio, Colonnella, Controguerra, Corropoli, Giulianova, Martinsicuro, Montefino, Morro d'Oro, Mosciano Sant'Angelo, Nereto, Notaresco, Pineto, Roseto degli Abruzzi, Sant'Omero, Silvi, Torano Nuovo, Tortoreto.</p>
      <p n="121">Pescara:</p>
      <p n="122">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="123">2. Cappelle sul Tavo, Cepagatti, Città Sant'Angelo, Collecorvino, Elice, Loreto Aprutino, Montesilvano, Moscufo, Penne, Pescara, Pianella, Picciano, Rosciano, Spoltore, Tocco da Casauria.</p>
      <p n="124">Chieti:</p>
      <p n="125">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="126">2. Archi, Ari, Arielli, Atessa, Bucchianico, Canosa Sannita, Casalanguida, Casalbordino, Casalincontrada, Castel Frentano, Chieti, Crecchio, Cupello, Fossacesia, Francavilla al Mare, Fresagrandinaria, Frisa, Furci, Gissi, Giuliano Teatino, Lanciano, Lentella, Miglianico, Monteodorisio, Mozzagrogna, Orsogna, Ortona, Paglieta, Poggiofiorito, Pollutri, Ripa Teatina, Rocca San Giovanni, San Giovanni Teatino, San Salvo, San Vito Chietino, Santa Maria Imbaro, Scerni, Tollo, Torino di Sangro, Torrevecchia Teatina, Treglio, Vacri, Vasto, Villalfonsina, Villamagna.</p>
      <p n="127">Campobasso:</p>
      <p n="128">1. Campomarino, Colletorto, Guglionesi, Larino, Mafalda, Montecilfone, Montenero di Bisaccia, Palata, Petacciato, Portocannone, Rotello, San Giacomo degli Schiavoni, San Giuliano di Puglia, San Martino in Pensilis, Santa Croce di Magliano, Tavenna, Termoli, Ururi.</p>
      <p n="129">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="130">Isernia:</p>
      <p n="131">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="132">Foggia:</p>
      <p n="133">1. Cerignola, Margherita di Savoia, Orta Nova, San Ferdinando di Puglia, Stornara, Stornarella, Trinitapoli.</p>
      <p n="134">2. Apricena, Chieuti, Lesina, Poggio Imperiale, San Paolo di Civitate, San Severo, Serracapriola, Torremaggiore.</p>
      <p n="135">3. Cagnano Varano, Carpino, Ischitella, Manfredonia, Mattinata, Monte Sant'Angelo, Peschici, Rignano Garganico, Rodi Garganico, San Giovanni Rotondo, San Marco in Lamis, Sannicandro Garganico, Vico del Gargano, Vieste.</p>
      <p n="136">4. (*)</p>
      <p n="137">Bari:</p>
      <p n="138">1. Mola di Bari, Monopoli, Polignano a Mare.</p>
      <p n="139">2. Andria, Barletta, Bisceglie, Bitonto, Canosa di Puglia, Corato, Giovinazzo, Molfetta, Trani.</p>
      <p n="140">3. Acquaviva delle Fonti, Adelfia, Bari, Binetto, Bitetto, Bitritto, Capurso, Casamassima, Cassano delle Murge, Cellamare, Conversano, Grumo Appula, Modugno, Noicattaro, Palo del Colle, Rutigliano, Ruvo di Puglia, Sammichele di Bari, Sannicandro di Bari, Terlizzi, Toritto, Triggiano, Turi, Valenzano.</p>
      <p n="141">4. (*)</p>
      <p n="142">Taranto:</p>
      <p n="143">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="144">2. Avetrana, Lizzano, Manduria, Maruggio, Sava, Torricella.</p>
      <p n="145">Brindisi:</p>
      <p n="146">1. Carovigno, Ceglie Messapico, Cisternino, Fasano, Ostuni, San Michele Salentino, San Vito dei Normanni, Villa Castelli.</p>
      <p n="147">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="148">Lecce:</p>
      <p n="149">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="150">2. Aradeo, Bagnolo del Salento, Calimera, Cannole, Caprarica di Lecce, Carpignano Salentino, Castri di Lecce, Castrignano de' Greci, Castro Marino, Copertino, Corigliano d'Otranto, Cursi, Galatina, Galatone, Giuggianello, Giurdignano, Lequile, Leverano, Maglie, Martano, Martignano, Melendugno, Melpignano, Minervino di Lecce, Muro Leccese, Nardò, Neviano, Ortelle, Otranto, Palmariggi, Poggiardo, Porto Cesareo, San Cesario di Lecce, San Donato di Lecce, San Pietro in Lama, Sanarica, Santa Cesarea Terme, Seclì, Sogliano Cavour, Soleto, Sternatia, Surano, Uggiano la Chiesa, Vernole, Zollino.</p>
      <p n="151">3. Acquarica del Capo, Alessano, Alezio, Alliste, Andrano, Botrugno, Casarano, Castrignano del Capo, Collepasso, Corsano, Cutrofiano, Diso, Gagliano del Capo, Gallipoli, Matino, Melissano, Miggiano, Montesano Salentino, Morciano di Leuca, Nociglia, Parabita, Patù, Presicce, Racale, Ruffano, Salve, San Cassiano, Sannicola, Scorrano, Specchia, Spongano, Supersano, Taurisano, Taviano, Tiggiano, Tricase, Tuglie, Ugento.</p>
      <p n="152">Potenza:</p>
      <p n="153">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="154">2. Abriola, Albano di Lucania, Anzi, Avigliano, Balvano, Bella, Brienza, Brindisi Montagna, Calvello, Calvera, Campomaggiore, Carbone, Castelgrande, Castelluccio Inferiore, Castelluccio Superiore, Castelmezzano, Castelsaraceno, Castronuovo di Sant'Andrea, Episcopia, Fardella, Grumento Nova, Lagonegro, Latronico, Laurenzana, Lauria, Maratea, Marsico Nuovo, Marsicovetere, Moliterno, Muro Lucano, Paterno, Pescopagano, Picerno, Pietrapertosa, Pignola, Potenza, Rapone, Ruoti, Ruvo del Monte, San Costantino Albanese, San Fele, San Martino d'Agri, San Paolo Albanese, San Severino Lucano, Sant'Angelo le Fratte, Sarconi, Sasso di Castalda, Satriano di Lucania, Savoia di Lucania, Spinoso, Teana, Terranova di Pollino, Tito, Tramutola, Trecchina, Trivigno, Vaglio Basilicata, Viggianello, Viggiano.</p>
      <p n="155">Matera:</p>
      <p n="156">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="157">Cosenza:</p>
      <p n="158">1. Calopezzati, Cariati, Corigliano Calabro, Crosia, Mandatoriccio, Rossano, San Cosmo Albanese, San Demetrio Corone, San Giorgio Albanese, Santa Sofia d'Epiro, Vaccarizzo Albanese.</p>
      <p n="159">2. Acquaformosa, Acri, Albidona, Alessandria del Carretto, Altilia, Altomonte, Amendolara, Aprigliano, Belsito, Bianchi, Bisignano, Bocchigliero, Caloveto, Campana, Canna, Carolei, Carpanzano, Casole Bruzio, Cassano allo Ionio, Castiglione Cosentino, Castrolibero, Castroregio, Castrovillari, Celico, Cellara, Cerchiara di Calabria, Cerisano, Cervicati, Cerzeto, Civita, Colosimi, Cosenza, Cropolati, Dipignano, Domanico, Fagnano Castello, Figline Vegliaturo, Firmo, Francavilla Marittima, Frascineto, Grimaldi, Lago, Laino Borgo, Laino Castello, Lappano, Lattarico, Longobucco, Lungro, Luzzi, Malito, Malvito, Mangone, Marano Marchesato, Marano Principato, Marzi, Mendicino, Mongrassano, Montalto Uffugo, Montegiordano, Morano Calabro, Mormanno, Mottafollone, Nocara, Oriolo, Paludi, Panettieri, Papasidero, Parenti, Paterno Calabro, Pedace, Pedivigliano, Piane Crati, Pietrafitta, Pietrapaola, Plataci, Rende, Rocca Imperiale, Roggiano Gravina, Rogliano, Rose, Roseto Capo Spulico, Rota Greca, Rovito, San Basile, San Benedetto Ullano, San Donato di Ninea, San Fili, San Giovanni in Fiore, San Lorenzo Bellizzi, San Lorenzo del Vallo, San Marco Argentano, San Martino di Finita, San Pietro in Guarano, San Sosti, San Vincenzo la Costa, Sant'Agata di Esaro, Santa Caterina Albanese, Santo Stefano di Rogliano, Saracena, Scala Coeli, Scigliano, Serra Pedace, Spezzano Albanese, Spezzano Piccolo, Spezzano della Sila, Tarsia, Terranova da Sibari, Terravecchia, Torano Castello, Trebisace, Trenta, Villapiana, Zumpano.</p>
      <p n="160">3. (*)</p>
      <p n="161">Catanzaro:</p>
      <p n="162">1. Curinga, Feroleto Antico, Gizzeria, Lamezia Terme, Maida, San Pietro a Maida.</p>
      <p n="163">2. Amaroni, Badolato, Borgia, Cerva, Falerna, Gasperina, Guardavalle, Marcedusa, Montauro, Montepaone, Nocera Tirinese, Palermiti, Petrizzi, Petronà, Pianopoli, San Floro, San Mango d'Aquino, Sant'Andrea Apostolo dello Ionio, Satriano, Settingiano, Squillace, Staletti, Tiriolo, Vallefiorita.</p>
      <p n="164">3. Amato, Andali, Belcastro, Botricello, Caraffa di Catanzaro, Catanzaro, Cortale, Cropani, Davoli, Gagliato, Girifalco, Isca sullo Ionio, Jacurso, Marcellinara, Miglierina, San Pietro Apostolo, San Sostene, San Vito sullo Ionio, Santa Caterina dello Ionio, Sellia, Sellia Marina, Serrastretta, Sersale, Simeri Crichi, Soverato, Soveria Simeri, Zagarise.</p>
      <p n="165">4. (*)</p>
      <p n="166">Crotone:</p>
      <p n="167">1. Belvedere di Spinello, Crotone, Cutro, Isola di Capo Rizzuto, Rocca di Neto, San Mauro Marchesato, Scandale.</p>
      <p n="168">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="169">3. Caccuri, Castelsilano, Cerenzia, Cotronei, Mesoraca, Petilia Policastro, Roccabernarda, Santa Severina, Savelli, Verzino.</p>
      <p n="170">Vibo Valentia:</p>
      <p n="171">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="172">Reggio Calabria:</p>
      <p n="173">1. Bagaladi, Bagnara Calabra, Calanna, Campo Calabro, Cittanova, Cosoleto, Delianuova, Fiumara, Gioia Tauro, Laganadi, Melicuccà, Melicucco, Molochio, Montebello Ionico, Oppido Mamertina, Palmi, Reggio di Calabria, Rizziconi, Rosarno, San Ferdinando, San Lorenzo, San Procopio, Sant'Alessio in Aspromonte, Sant'Eufemia d'Aspromonte, Santa Cristina d'Aspromonte, Santo Stefano in Aspromonte, Scido, Scilla, Seminara, Sinopoli, Taurianova, Terranova Sappo Minulio, Varapodio, Villa San Giovanni.</p>
      <p n="174">2. Anoia, Bovalino, Candidoni, Cinquefrondi, Feroleto della Chiesa, Galatro, Giffone, Laureana di Borrello, Maropati, Polistena, San Giorgio Morgeto, San Pietro di Caridà, Sant'Ilario dello Ionio, Serrata.</p>
      <p n="175">3. Africo, Ardore, Benestare, Bianco, Bova, Bova Marina, Brancaleone, Bruzzano Zeffirio, Caraffa del Bianco, Cardeto, Careri, Casignana, Condofuri, Ferruzzano, Gioiosa Ionica, Locri, Marina di Gioiosa Ionica, Melito di Porto Salvo, Motta San Giovani, Palizzi, Platì, Portigliola, Ravagnese, Roccaforte del Greco, Roccella Ionica, Roghudi, San Luca, San Roberto, Sant'Agata del Bianco, Siderno, Staiti.</p>
      <p n="176">4. (*)</p>
      <p n="177">Trapani:</p>
      <p n="178">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="179">Palermo:</p>
      <p n="180">1. Alia, Aliminusa, Altavilla Milicia, Altofonte, Bagheria, Balestrate, Baucina, Belmonte Mezzagno, Bisacquino, Bolognetta, Borgetto, Caccamo, Caltavuturo, Campofelice di Fitalia, Campofelice di Roccella, Campofiorito, Camporeale, Carini, Castelbuono, Casteldaccia, Castellana Sicula, Cefalà Diana, Cefalù, Cerda, Chiusa Sclafani, Ciminna, Cinisi, Collesano, Contessa Entellina, Corleone, Ficarazzi, Giardinello, Giuliana, Lascari, Lercara Friddi, Marineo, Mezzojuso, Misilmeri, Monreale, Montelepre, Montemaggiore Belsito, Palazzo Adriano, Palermo, Partinico, Petralia Sottana, Piana degli Albanesi, Roccamena, Roccapalumba, San Cipirello, San Giuseppe Jato, San Mauro Castelverde, Santa Cristina Gela, Santa Flavia, Sciara, Scillato, Sclafani Bagni, Termini Imerese, Terrasini, Torretta, Trabia, Trappeto, Valledolmo, Ventimiglia di Sicilia, Vicari, Villafrati.</p>
      <p n="181">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="182">Messina:</p>
      <p n="183">1. Brolo, Castell'Umberto, Ficarra, Frazzanò, Galati Mamertino, Longi, Mandanici, Mirto, Montagnareale, Naso, Pagliara, Piraino, Raccuja, San Piero Patti, San Salvatore di Fitalia, Sant'Angelo di Brolo, Sinagra, Tortorici, Ucria.</p>
      <p n="184">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="185">Agrigento:</p>
      <p n="186">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="187">Caltanissetta:</p>
      <p n="188">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="189">Catania:</p>
      <p n="190">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="191">Ragusa:</p>
      <p n="192">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="193">Siracusa:</p>
      <p n="194">1. Augusta, Avola, Canicattini Bagni, Carlentini, Floridia, Lentini, Melilli, Noto, Pachino, Portopalo di Capo Passero, Priolo Gargallo, Rosolini, Siracusa, Solarino.</p>
      <p n="195">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="196">Sassari:</p>
      <p n="197">1. Alghero, Sennori, Sorso, Uri, Usini.</p>
      <p n="198">2. (*)</p>
      <p n="199">Nuoro:</p>
      <p n="200">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="201">Cagliari:</p>
      <p n="202">1. (*)".</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
