<TEI.2 id="jrc32000D0572-en" n="32000D0572" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000D0572 English</title>
        <title>2000/572/EC: Commission Decision of 8 September 2000 laying down animal and public health conditions and veterinary certification for imports of minced meat and meat preparations from third countries and repealing Decision 97/29/EC (notified under document number C(2000) 2533) (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>53 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000D0572:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000D0572:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">192</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2300</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2738</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5369</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000D0572-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2000/572/EC: Commission Decision of 8 September 2000 laying down animal and public health conditions and veterinary certification for imports of minced meat and meat preparations from third countries and repealing Decision 97/29/EC (notified under document number C(2000) 2533) (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 8 September 2000</p>
      <p n="4">laying down animal and public health conditions and veterinary certification for imports of minced meat and meat preparations from third countries and repealing Decision 97/29/EC</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2000) 2533)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2000/572/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 94/65/EC of 14 December 1994 laying down the requirements for the production and placing on the market of minced meat and meat preparations(1), and in particular Article 13 thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) Specific conditions relating to the requirements of Directive 94/65/EC for the importation into the Community of minced meat and meat preparations must be established in a model of certificate including both the public and the animal health conditions. These conditions may not be less stringent than those laid down in Articles 3 and 5 of that Directive.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) Commission Decision 97/29/EC(2) establishes health conditions and public health certification for the importation of minced meat and meat preparations from third countries.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) Animal health conditions have not yet been established.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) A new model of certificate must be established laying down both the animal and the public health conditions for imports of minced meat and meat preparations.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) Decision 97/29/EC must be repealed.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">This Decision lays down the animal and public health conditions and veterinary certification for the importation of minced meat and meat preparations.</p>
      <p n="21">Article 2</p>
      <p n="22">The importation of minced meat is subject to the following conditions:</p>
      <p n="23">1. it has been produced in accordance with the requirements laid down in Articles 3 and 7 of Directive 94/65/EC;</p>
      <p n="24">2. it comes from an establishment or establishments offering the guarantees provided for in Annex I of Directive 94/65/EC;</p>
      <p n="25">3. it has been deep-frozen at the production plant or plants of origin.</p>
      <p n="26">Article 3</p>
      <p n="27">The importation of meat preparations is subject to the following conditions:</p>
      <p n="28">1. they have been produced in accordance with the requirements laid down in Articles 5 and 7 of Directive 94/65/EC;</p>
      <p n="29">2. they come from an establishment or establishments offering the guarantees provided for in Annex I of Directive 94/65/EC;</p>
      <p n="30">3. they have been deep-frozen at the production plant or plants of origin.</p>
      <p n="31">Article 4</p>
      <p n="32">1. Each consignment of minced meat shall be accompanied by an original, numbered health certificate, completed, signed and dated, composed of a single sheet and conforming to the model laid down in Annex I.</p>
      <p n="33">2. Each consignment of meat preparations shall be accompanied by an original, numbered health certificate, completed, signed and dated, composed of a single sheet and conforming to the model laid down in Annex II.</p>
      <p n="34">3. The certificates shall be drawn up in at least one of the official languages of the Member State of introduction into the Community.</p>
      <p n="35">Article 5</p>
      <p n="36">This Decision shall apply from 1 October 2000.</p>
      <p n="37">Article 6</p>
      <p n="38">1. Decision 97/29/EC is repealed on the date referred to in Article 5.</p>
      <p n="39">2. Member States shall authorise the importation of minced meat and meat preparations, produced and certified according to the requirements of Decision 97/29/EC during the 35 days following the date mentioned in paragraph 1.</p>
      <p n="40">Article 7</p>
      <p n="41">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="42">Done at Brussels, 8 September 2000.</p>
      <p n="43">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="44">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="45">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="46">(1) OJ L 368, 31.12.1994, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="47">(2) OJ L 12, 15.1.1997, p. 33.</p>
      <p n="48">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="49">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000240EN.002102.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="50">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000240EN.002201.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="51">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="52">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000240EN.002302.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="53">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000240EN.002401.EPS"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
