<TEI.2 id="jrc32000R1474-en" n="32000R1474" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000R1474 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1474/2000 of 10 July 2000 determining the reduced amounts of agricultural components and additional duties applicable from 1 July 2000 to imports into the Community of certain goods covered by Council Regulation (EC) No 3448/93 under an Interim Agreement between the European Union and Israel</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>47 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R1474:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R1474:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1518</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4080</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5407</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">614</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">666</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000R1474-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1474/2000 of 10 July 2000 determining the reduced amounts of agricultural components and additional duties applicable from 1 July 2000 to imports into the Community of certain goods covered by Council Regulation (EC) No 3448/93 under an Interim Agreement between the European Union and Israel</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1474/2000</p>
      <p n="3">of 10 July 2000</p>
      <p n="4">determining the reduced amounts of agricultural components and additional duties applicable from 1 July 2000 to imports into the Community of certain goods covered by Council Regulation (EC) No 3448/93 under an Interim Agreement between the European Union and Israel</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 3448/93 of 6 December 1993 laying down the trade arrangements applicable to certain goods resulting from the processing of agricultural products(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2491/98(2), and in particular Article 7 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Pending the entry into force of the Euro-Mediterranean Agreement establishing an association between the European Communities and their Member States, of the one part, and the State of Israel, of the other part, signed in Brussels on 20 November 1995, an Interim Agreement between the European Community and the European Coal and Steel Community, of the one part, and the State of Israel, of the other part, on trade and accompanying measures was signed on 18 December 1995(3) and entered into force on 1 January 1996. This Agreement provides within the quota limits for reductions in the agricultural component for certain processed agricultural products.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) Council Regulation (EC) No 1981/94 of 25 July 1994 opening and providing for the administration of Community tariff quotas for certain products originating in Algeria, Cyprus, Egypt, Israel, Jordan, Malta, Morocco, the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, Tunisia and Turkey, and providing detailed rules for extending and adapting these tariff quotas(4), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 563/2000(5), opened the quotas within which certain processed agricultural products originating in Israel are granted a reduction in the agricultural components. The reduced agricultural components and additional duties must be fixed.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) Commission Regulation (EC) No 1460/96(6), amended by Regulation (EC) No 2495/97(7), establishes detailed rules for the application of preferential trade arrangements applicable to certain goods resulting from the processing of agricultural products, referred to in Article 7 of Regulation (EC) No 3448/93,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">From 1 July 2000, the reduced agricultural components applicable to imports of goods covered by Regulation (EC) No 3448/93 for which a reduction in the agricultural component is provided for in the Interim Agreement concluded with Israel and the corresponding reduced additional duties shall be fixed in the Annexes to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="17">It shall apply from 1 July 2000.</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 10 July 2000.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Erkki Liikanen</p>
      <p n="22">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ L 318, 20.12.1993, p. 18.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ L 309, 19.11.1998, p. 28.</p>
      <p n="25">(3) OJ L 71, 20.3.1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(4) OJ L 199, 2.8.1994, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="27">(5) OJ L 68, 16.3.2000, p. 46.</p>
      <p n="28">(6) OJ L 187, 26.7.1996, p. 18.</p>
      <p n="29">(7) OJ L 343, 13.12.1997, p. 18.</p>
      <p n="30">ANEXO I/BILAG I/ANHANG I/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ I/ANNEX I/ANNEXE I/ALLEGATO I/BIJLAGE I/ANEXO I/LIITE I/BILAGA I</p>
      <p n="31">Elementos agrícolas (por 100 kilogramos de peso neto)/Landbrugselementer (pr. 100 kg nettovægt)/Landwirtschaftliche Teilbeträge (für 100 kg Eigengewicht)/Αγροτικά στοιχεία (για 100 kg καθαρού βάρους)/Agricultural components (per 100 kilograms net weight)/Éléments agricoles (par 100 kilogrammes poids net)/Elementi agricoli (per 100 kg peso netto)/Landbouwelementen (per 100 kg nettogewicht)/Elementos agrícolas (por 100 quilogramas de peso líquido)/Maatalousosat (100 nettopainokilolta)/Jordbruksbeståndsdelar (per 100 kg nettovikt)</p>
      <p n="32">PARTE 1/DEL 1/TEIL 1/ΜΕΡΟΣ 1/PART 1/PARTIE 1/PARTE 1/DEEL 1/PARTE 1/OSA 1/DEL 1</p>
      <p n="33">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="34">PARTE 2/DEL 2/TEIL 2/ΜΕΡΟΣ 2/PART 2/PARTIE 2/PARTE 2/DEEL 2/PARTE 2/OSA 2/DEL 2</p>
      <p n="35">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="36">PARTE 3/DEL 3/TEIL 3/ΜΕΡΟΣ 3/PART 3/PARTIE 3/PARTE 3/DEEL 3/PARTE 3/OSA 3/DEL 3</p>
      <p n="37">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="38">ANEXO II/BILAG II/ANHANG II/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ II/ANNEX II/ANNEXE II/ALLEGATO II/BIJLAGE II/ANEXO II/LIITE II/BILAGA II</p>
      <p n="39">Importes de los derechos adicionales sobre el azúcar (AD S/Z) y sobre la harina (AD F/M) (por 100 kilogramos de peso neto)/Tillægstold for sukker (AD S/Z) og for mel (AD F/M) (pr. 100 kg nettovægt)/Beträge der Zusatzzölle für Zucker (AD S/Z) und für Mehl (AD F/M) (für 100 kg Nettogewicht)/Ποσά πρόσθετων δασμών στη ζάχαρη (AD S/Z) και στο αλεύρι (AD F/M) (για 100 kg καθαρού βάρους)/Amounts of additional duties on sugar (AD S/Z) and on flour (AD F/M) (per 100 kilograms net weight)/Montants des droits additionnels sur le sucre (AD S/Z) et sur la farine (AD F/M) (par 100 kilogrammes poids net)/Importi dei dazi aggiuntivi sullo zucchero (AD S/Z) e sulla farina (AD F/M) (per 100 kg peso netto)/Bedragen der aanvullende invoerrechten op suiker (AD S/Z) en op meel (AD F/M) (per 100 kg nettogewicht)/Montantes dos direitos adicionais sobre o açúcar (AD S/Z) e sobre a farinha (AD F/M) (por 100 quilogramas de peso líquido)/Sokeriin (AD S/Z) ja jauhoihin (AD F/M) (100 nettopainokilolta) sovellettavat lisätullit/Tilläggstull för socker (AD S/Z) och för mjöl (AD F/M) (per 100 kg nettovikt)</p>
      <p n="40">PARTE 1/DEL 1/TEIL 1/ΜΕΡΟΣ 1/PART 1/PARTIE 1/PARTE 1/DEEL 1/PARTE 1/OSA 1/DEL 1</p>
      <p n="41">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="42">PARTE 2/DEL 2/TEIL 2/ΜΕΡΟΣ 2/PART 2/PARTIE 2/PARTE 2/DEEL 2/PARTE 2/OSA 2/DEL 2</p>
      <p n="43">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="44">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="45">PARTE 3/DEL 3/TEIL 3/ΜΕΡΟΣ 3/PART 3/PARTIE 3/PARTE 3/DEEL 3/PARTE 3/OSA 3/DEL 3</p>
      <p n="46">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="47">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
