<TEI.2 id="jrc32000L0074-en" n="32000L0074" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000L0074 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 2000/74/EC of 22 November 2000 adapting to technical progress Council Directive 93/29/EEC on the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators for two- or three-wheel motor vehicles (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>69 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000L0074:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000L0074:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1252</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2081</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4653</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4654</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5235</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">848</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000L0074-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 2000/74/EC of 22 November 2000 adapting to technical progress Council Directive 93/29/EEC on the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators for two- or three-wheel motor vehicles (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Directive 2000/74/EC</p>
      <p n="3">of 22 November 2000</p>
      <p n="4">adapting to technical progress Council Directive 93/29/EEC on the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators for two- or three-wheel motor vehicles</p>
      <p n="5">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Directive 92/61/EEC of 30 June 1992 relating to the type-approval of two- or three-wheel motor vehicles(1), as last amended by Directive 2000/7/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council(2), and in particular Article 16 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Directive 93/29/EEC of 14 June 1993 on the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators for two- or three-wheel motor vehicles(3), and in particular Article 4 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">(1) Directive 93/29/EEC is one of the separate directives under the Community type-approval procedure introduced by Directive 92/61/EEC. The provisions of Directive 92/61/EEC relating to systems, components and separate technical units for vehicles therefore apply to that Directive.</p>
      <p n="12">(2) Developments in technology now enable Directive 93/29/EEC to be adapted to technical progress. In order to enable the full type-approval system to function properly, it is therefore necessary to clarify or supplement certain requirements of the Directive concerned.</p>
      <p n="13">(3) To this end, the requirements concerning the designation and identification of certain symbols should be aligned with those of Council Directive 78/316/EEC of 21 December 1977 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to the interior fittings of motor vehicles (identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators)(4), as amended by Commission Directive 93/91/EEC(5), and certain information contained in the information document should be clarified.</p>
      <p n="14">(4) The measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the opinion of the Committee for Adaptation to Technical Progress set up under Article 13 of Council Directive 70/156/EEC of 6 February 1970 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to the type-approval of motor vehicles and their trailers(6), as last amended by Directive 2000/40/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council(7),</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">Annexes I and II to Directive 93/29/EEC are hereby amended in accordance with the Annex to this Directive.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">1. With effect from 1 January 2002, Member States may not, on grounds relating to the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators:</p>
      <p n="20">- refuse to grant EC type-approval for a type of two- or three-wheel motor vehicle, or</p>
      <p n="21">- prohibit the registration, sale or entry into service of two- or three-wheel motor vehicles,</p>
      <p n="22">if the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators complies with the requirements of Directive 93/29/EEC, as amended by this Directive.</p>
      <p n="23">2. With effect from 1 July 2002, Member States shall refuse to grant EC type-approval for any new type of two- or three-wheel motor vehicle on grounds relating to the identification of controls, tell-tales and indicators if the requirements of Directive 93/79/EEC, as amended by this Directive, are not fulfilled.</p>
      <p n="24">Article 3</p>
      <p n="25">1. Member States shall adopt and publish, no later than 31 December 2001, the provisions necessary to comply with this Directive. They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="26">They shall apply those provisions from 1 January 2002.</p>
      <p n="27">When Member States adopt those provisions, they shall contain a reference to this Directive or shall be accompanied by such a reference on the occasion of their official publiclation. Member States shall determine how such reference is to be made.</p>
      <p n="28">2. Member States shall communicate to the Commission the texts of the main provisions of national law that they adopt in the field governed by this Directive.</p>
      <p n="29">Article 4</p>
      <p n="30">This Directive shall enter into force on the 20th day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="31">Article 5</p>
      <p n="32">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="33">Done at Brussels, 22 November 2000.</p>
      <p n="34">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="35">Erkki Liikanen</p>
      <p n="36">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="37">(1) OJ L 225, 10.8.1992, p. 72.</p>
      <p n="38">(2) OJ L 106, 3.5.2000, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="39">(3) OJ L 188, 29.7.1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="40">(4) OJ L 81, 28.3.1978, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="41">(5) OJ L 284, 19.11.1993, p. 25.</p>
      <p n="42">(6) OJ L 42, 23.2.1970, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="43">(7) OJ L 203, 10.8.2000, p. 9.</p>
      <p n="44">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="45">I. Annex I is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="46">1. Section 2.1.1. is replaced by the following text: "2.1.1. These symbols shall stand out clearly against the background."</p>
      <p n="47">2. Section 2.1.5. is amended as follows: - the following is added to the caption to figure 3 : &gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="48">Note:</p>
      <p n="49">if there are separate tell-tales for the left and right direction indicators, the two arrows may also be used separately.</p>
      <p n="50">- figure 12 is replaced by the following: '</p>
      <p n="51">Figure 12</p>
      <p n="52">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000300EN.002602.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="53">- the caption to figure 13 is replaced by the following: "Figure 13</p>
      <p n="54">Engine ignition or cut-off control in "out of use" position"</p>
      <p n="55">- the caption to figure 14 is replaced by the following text: "Figure 14</p>
      <p n="56">Engine ignition or cut-off control in the "operating" position"</p>
      <p n="57">- figure 15 is replaced by the following: '</p>
      <p n="58">Figure 15</p>
      <p n="59">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000300EN.002603.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="60">the caption to figure 16 is replaced by the following text: "Figure 16</p>
      <p n="61">Position (side) lamps</p>
      <p n="62">(if the control is not separate, it may be identified by the symbol shown in figure 15)</p>
      <p n="63">Tell-tale colour: green"</p>
      <p n="64">- figure 17 is deleted.</p>
      <p n="65">- figures 18 and 19 are renumbered 17 and 18 respectively.</p>
      <p n="66">- note (1) is replaced by the following: "(1) The framed areas may be solid."</p>
      <p n="67">II. Annex II is amended as follows: Appendix 1 is replaced by the following text:</p>
      <p n="68">"Appendix 1</p>
      <p n="69">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000300EN.002702.EPS"&gt;"</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
