<TEI.2 id="jrc32000R2356-en" n="32000R2356" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000R2356 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2356/2000 of 24 October 2000 amending Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999 laying down rules for the application of Council Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999 on Community support for pre-accession measures for agriculture and rural development in the applicant countries of central and eastern Europe in the pre-accession period (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R2356:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R2356:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">12</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1542</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2965</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">862</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">914</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000R2356-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2356/2000 of 24 October 2000 amending Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999 laying down rules for the application of Council Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999 on Community support for pre-accession measures for agriculture and rural development in the applicant countries of central and eastern Europe in the pre-accession period (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2356/2000</p>
      <p n="3">of 24 October 2000</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999 laying down rules for the application of Council Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999 on Community support for pre-accession measures for agriculture and rural development in the applicant countries of central and eastern Europe in the pre-accession period</p>
      <p n="5">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999 of 21 June 1999 on Community support for pre-accession measures for agriculture and rural development in the applicant countries of central and eastern Europe in the pre-accession period(1), and in particular Article 8 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Article 8 of Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999 set parameters and limits which need further clarification in order to better reflect Community structural policy applied in the framework of Council Regulation (EC) No 1260/1999 of 21 June 1999 laying down general provisions on the Structural Funds(2).</p>
      <p n="11">(2) In particular, it should be clarified that "public aid" referred to in Article 8(2) of Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999 relates to all public aid not only that granted under the programmes referred to in Article 9 of that Regulation.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) Commission Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999(3) permits only new machinery and equipment to be eligible for support in the processing and marketing sector; a possibility of having recourse to second-hand equipment under certain circumstances is warranted.</p>
      <p n="13">(4) Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999 limits support for investment in processing and marketing of fishery products to products originating in the applicant countries or the Community; that limitation is not required under Council legislation nor is it a desirable limitation in the fisheries sector within Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999.</p>
      <p n="14">(5) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Agricultural Structures and Rural Development Committee,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">Regulation (EC) No 2759/1999 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="18">1. Article 3(1) is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="19">"1. Support may be granted for investments provided for in Articles 25 and 26 of Regulation (EC) No 1257/1999 relating to improving the processing and marketing of the agricultural including fishery products included in Annex I to the Treaty. Agricultural products, excluding fishery products, must originate in applicant countries or the Community. Investments at the retail level shall be excluded from support."</p>
      <p n="20">2. Article 3(2)(b) is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="21">"(b) new machinery and equipment including computer software; however on a case-by-case basis the Commission may agree on eligibility of second-hand equipment subject to specific safeguards in particular concerning provenance and technical specification;".</p>
      <p n="22">3. The title of Article 8 is replaced by the following:"Eligibility and aid intensity".</p>
      <p n="23">4. The following paragraph is added at the end of Article 8:</p>
      <p n="24">"4. For the application of Article 8(2) of Regulation (EC) No 1268/1999:</p>
      <p n="25">(a) 'revenue generating investments' include all investments, except those in infrastructure which do not generate substantial net revenue;</p>
      <p n="26">(b) 'public aid' means all such aid whether or not granted under the programme."</p>
      <p n="27">Article 2</p>
      <p n="28">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="29">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="30">Done at Brussels, 24 October 2000.</p>
      <p n="31">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="32">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="33">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="34">(1) OJ L 161, 26.6.1999, p. 87.</p>
      <p n="35">(2) OJ L 161, 26.6.1999, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="36">(3) OJ L 331, 23.12.1999, p. 51.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
