<TEI.2 id="jrc32000R0749-en" n="32000R0749" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000R0749 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 749/2000 of 11 April 2000 adapting the total quantities referred to in Article 3 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 establishing an additional levy in the milk and milk products sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>49 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R0749:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R0749:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1565</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2591</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2763</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2972</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000R0749-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 749/2000 of 11 April 2000 adapting the total quantities referred to in Article 3 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 establishing an additional levy in the milk and milk products sector</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 749/2000</p>
      <p n="3">of 11 April 2000</p>
      <p n="4">adapting the total quantities referred to in Article 3 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 establishing an additional levy in the milk and milk products sector</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 of 28 December 1992 establishing an additional levy in the milk and milk products sector(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1256/1999(2), and in particular Articles 3(2) and 4(2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Article 3(2) of Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 lays down that the guaranteed total quantities for Finland may be increased to compensate "SLOM" producers, up to a maximum of 200000 tonnes. In accordance with Article 6 of Commission Regulation (EC) No 671/95(3), as amended by Regulation (EC) No 1390/95(4), Finland has notified the quantities concerned for the 1999/2000 marketing year.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) Article 4(2) of Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 lays down that the individual reference quantities are increased or established at the duly justified request of producers to take account of changes affecting their deliveries and/or direct sales and that the increase or establishment of such a reference quantity is subject to a corresponding reduction or cancellation of the other reference quantity the producer owns.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) Such adjustments may not lead to an increase, for the Member State concerned, in the sum of the deliveries and direct sales referred to in Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92. Where the individual reference quantities undergo a definitive change, the quantities referred to in Article 3 are adjusted accordingly.</p>
      <p n="12">(4) In accordance with the third indent of Article 8 of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 536/93(5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1255/98(6), Belgium, Denmark, Germany, Spain, France, Ireland, Italy, the Netherlands, Austria, Portugal, Finland and the United Kingdom have notified quantities which have undergone a definitive change in accordance with the second subparagraph of Article 4(2) of Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92.</p>
      <p n="13">(5) The total quantities applicable for the period from 1 April 1999 to 31 March 2000 laid down in the table given in Article 3(2) of Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 and consequently those applicable for subsequent periods laid down in the Annex to that Regulation should therefore be adjusted.</p>
      <p n="14">(6) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">Regulation (EEC) No 3950/92 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="18">1. The table in Article 3(2) is replaced by that given in Annex I hereto.</p>
      <p n="19">2. The Annex is replaced by Annex II hereto.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Brussels, 11 April 2000.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="26">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="27">(1) OJ L 405, 31.12.1992, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="28">(2) OJ L 160, 26.6.1999, p. 73.</p>
      <p n="29">(3) OJ L 70, 30.3.1995, p. 2.</p>
      <p n="30">(4) OJ L 135, 21.6.1995, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="31">(5) OJ L 57, 10.3.1993, p. 12.</p>
      <p n="32">(6) OJ L 173, 18.6.1998, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="34">"Total reference quantities as applicable from 1 April 1999 to 31 March 2000</p>
      <p n="35">&gt;TABLE&gt;"</p>
      <p n="36">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="37">"ANNEX</p>
      <p n="38">a) Total reference quantities referred to in Article 3(2) as applicable from 1 April 2000 to 31 March 2001</p>
      <p n="39">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="40">b) Total reference quantities referred to in Article 3(2) as applicable from 1 April 2001 to 31 March 2002</p>
      <p n="41">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="42">c) Total reference quantities referred to in Article 3(2) as applicable from 1 April 2002 to 31 March 2005</p>
      <p n="43">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="44">d) Total reference quantities referred to in Article 3(2) as applicable from 1 April 2005 to 31 March 2006</p>
      <p n="45">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="46">e) Total reference quantities referred to in Article 3(2) as applicable from 1 April 2006 to 31 March 2007</p>
      <p n="47">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="48">f) Total reference quantities referred to in Article 3(2) as applicable from 1 April 2007 to 31 March 2008</p>
      <p n="49">&gt;TABLE&gt;"</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
