<TEI.2 id="jrc32000R1348-en" n="32000R1348" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32000R1348 English</title>
        <title>Council regulation (EC) No 1348/2000 of 29 May 2000 on the service in the Member States of judicial and extrajudicial documents in civil or commercial matters</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>202 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R1348:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32000R1348:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">523</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">524</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5258</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5283</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32000R1348-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council regulation (EC) No 1348/2000 of 29 May 2000 on the service in the Member States of judicial and extrajudicial documents in civil or commercial matters</head>
      <p n="2">Council regulation (EC) No 1348/2000</p>
      <p n="3">of 29 May 2000</p>
      <p n="4">on the service in the Member States of judicial and extrajudicial documents in civil or commercial matters</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 61(c) and Article 67(1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission(1),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(2),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee(3),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">(1) The Union has set itself the objective of maintaining and developing the Union as an area of freedom, security and justice, in which the free movement of persons is assured. To establish such an area, the Community is to adopt, among others, the measures relating to judicial cooperation in civil matters needed for the proper functioning of the internal market.</p>
      <p n="12">(2) The proper functioning of the internal market entails the need to improve and expedite the transmission of judicial and extrajudicial documents in civil or commercial matters for service between the Member States.</p>
      <p n="13">(3) This is a subject now falling within the ambit of Article 65 of the Treaty.</p>
      <p n="14">(4) In accordance with the principles of subsidiarity and proportionality as set out in Article 5 of the Treaty, the objectives of this Regulation cannot be sufficiently achieved by the Member States and can therefore be better achieved by the Community. This Regulation does not go beyond what is necessary to achieve those objectives.</p>
      <p n="15">(5) The Council, by an Act dated 26 May 1997(4), drew up a Convention on the service in the Member States of the European Union of judicial and extrajudicial documents in civil or commercial matters and recommended it for adoption by the Member States in accordance with their respective constitutional rules. That Convention has not entered into force. Continuity in the results of the negotiations for conclusion of the Convention should be ensured. The main content of this Regulation is substantially taken over from it.</p>
      <p n="16">(6) Efficiency and speed in judicial procedures in civil matters means that the transmission of judicial and extrajudicial documents is to be made direct and by rapid means between local bodies designated by the Member States. However, the Member States may indicate their intention of designating only one transmitting or receiving agency or one agency to perform both functions for a period of five years. This designation may, however, be renewed every five years.</p>
      <p n="17">(7) Speed in transmission warrants the use of all appropriate means, provided that certain conditions as to the legibility and reliability of the document received are observed. Security in transmission requires that the document to be transmitted be accompanied by a pre-printed form, to be completed in the language of the place where service is to be effected, or in another language accepted by the Member State in question.</p>
      <p n="18">(8) To secure the effectiveness of this Regulation, the possibility of refusing service of documents is confined to exceptional situations.</p>
      <p n="19">(9) Speed of transmission warrants documents being served within days of reception of the document. However, if service has not been effected after one month has elapsed, the receiving agency should inform the transmitting agency. The expiry of this period should not imply that the request be returned to the transmitting agency where it is clear that service is feasible within a reasonable period.</p>
      <p n="20">(10) For the protection of the addressee's interests, service should be effected in the official language or one of the official languages of the place where it is to be effected or in another language of the originating Member State which the addressee understands.</p>
      <p n="21">(11) Given the differences between the Member States as regards their rules of procedure, the material date for the purposes of service varies from one Member State to another. Having regard to such situations and the possible difficulties that may arise, this Regulation should provide for a system where it is the law of the receiving Member State which determines the date of service. However, if the relevant documents in the context of proceedings to be brought or pending in the Member State of origin are to be served within a specified period, the date to be taken into consideration with respect to the applicant shall be that determined according to the law of the Member State of origin. A Member State is, however, authorised to derogate from the aforementioned provisions for a transitional period of five years, for appropriate reasons. Such a derogation may be renewed by a Member State at five-year intervals due to reasons related to its legal system.</p>
      <p n="22">(12) This Regulation prevails over the provisions contained in bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements having the same scope, concluded by the Member States, and in particular the Protocol annexed to the Brussels Convention of 27 September 1968(5) and the Hague Convention of 15 November 1965 in relations between the Member States party thereto. This Regulation does not preclude Member States from maintaining or concluding agreements or arrangements to expedite or simplify the transmission of documents, provided that they are compatible with the Regulation.</p>
      <p n="23">(13) The information transmitted pursuant to this Regulation should enjoy suitable protection. This matter falls within the scope of Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data(6), and of Directive 97/66/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 15 December 1997 concerning the processing of personal data and the protection of privacy in the telecommunications sector(7).</p>
      <p n="24">(14) The measures necessary for the implementation of this Regulation should be adopted in accordance with Council Decision 1999/468/EC of 28 June 1999 laying down the procedures for the exercise of implementing powers conferred on the Commission(8).</p>
      <p n="25">(15) These measures also include drawing up and updating the manual using appropriate modern means.</p>
      <p n="26">(16) No later than three years after the date of entry into force of this Regulation, the Commission should review its application and propose such amendments as may appear necessary.</p>
      <p n="27">(17) The United Kingdom and Ireland, in accordance with Article 3 of the Protocol on the position of the United Kingdom and Ireland annexed to the Treaty on European Union and the Treaty establishing the European Community, have given notice of their wish to take part in the adoption and application of this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="28">(18) Denmark, in accordance with Articles 1 and 2 of the Protocol on the position of Denmark annexed to the Treaty on European Union and the Treaty establishing the European Community, is not participating in the adoption of this Regulation, and is therefore not bound by it nor subject to its application,</p>
      <p n="29">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="30">CHAPTER I</p>
      <p n="31">GENERAL PROVISIONS</p>
      <p n="32">Article 1</p>
      <p n="33">Scope</p>
      <p n="34">1. This Regulation shall apply in civil and commercial matters where a judicial or extrajudicial document has to be transmitted from one Member State to another for service there.</p>
      <p n="35">2. This Regulation shall not apply where the address of the person to be served with the document is not known.</p>
      <p n="36">Article 2</p>
      <p n="37">Transmitting and receiving agencies</p>
      <p n="38">1. Each Member State shall designate the public officers, authorities or other persons, hereinafter referred to as "transmitting agencies", competent for the transmission of judicial or extrajudicial documents to be served in another Member State.</p>
      <p n="39">2. Each Member State shall designate the public officers, authorities or other persons, hereinafter referred to as "receiving agencies", competent for the receipt of judicial or extrajudicial documents from another Member State.</p>
      <p n="40">3. A Member State may designate one transmitting agency and one receiving agency or one agency to perform both functions. A federal State, a State in which several legal systems apply or a State with autonomous territorial units shall be free to designate more than one such agency. The designation shall have effect for a period of five years and may be renewed at five-year intervals.</p>
      <p n="41">4. Each Member State shall provide the Commission with the following information:</p>
      <p n="42">(a) the names and addresses of the receiving agencies referred to in paragraphs 2 and 3;</p>
      <p n="43">(b) the geographical areas in which they have jurisdiction;</p>
      <p n="44">(c) the means of receipt of documents available to them; and</p>
      <p n="45">(d) the languages that may be used for the completion of the standard form in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="46">Member States shall notify the Commission of any subsequent modification of such information.</p>
      <p n="47">Article 3</p>
      <p n="48">Central body</p>
      <p n="49">Each Member State shall designate a central body responsible for:</p>
      <p n="50">(a) supplying information to the transmitting agencies;</p>
      <p n="51">(b) seeking solutions to any difficulties which may arise during transmission of documents for service;</p>
      <p n="52">(c) forwarding, in exceptional cases, at the request of a transmitting agency, a request for service to the competent receiving agency.</p>
      <p n="53">A federal State, a State in which several legal systems apply or a State with autonomous territorial units shall be free to designate more than one central body.</p>
      <p n="54">CHAPTER II</p>
      <p n="55">JUDICIAL DOCUMENTS</p>
      <p n="56">Section 1</p>
      <p n="57">Transmission and service of judicial documents</p>
      <p n="58">Article 4</p>
      <p n="59">Transmission of documents</p>
      <p n="60">1. Judicial documents shall be transmitted directly and as soon as possible between the agencies designated on the basis of Article 2.</p>
      <p n="61">2. The transmission of documents, requests, confirmations, receipts, certificates and any other papers between transmitting agencies and receiving agencies may be carried out by any appropriate means, provided that the content of the document received is true and faithful to that of the document forwarded and that all information in it is easily legible.</p>
      <p n="62">3. The document to be transmitted shall be accompanied by a request drawn up using the standard form in the Annex. The form shall be completed in the official language of the Member State addressed or, if there are several official languages in that Member State, the official language or one of the official languages of the place where service is to be effected, or in another language which that Member State has indicated it can accept. Each Member State shall indicate the official language or languages of the European Union other than its own which is or are acceptable to it for completion of the form.</p>
      <p n="63">4. The documents and all papers that are transmitted shall be exempted from legalisation or any equivalent formality.</p>
      <p n="64">5. When the transmitting agency wishes a copy of the document to be returned together with the certificate referred to in Article 10, it shall send the document in duplicate.</p>
      <p n="65">Article 5</p>
      <p n="66">Translation of documents</p>
      <p n="67">1. The applicant shall be advised by the transmitting agency to which he or she forwards the document for transmission that the addressee may refuse to accept it if it is not in one of the languages provided for in Article 8.</p>
      <p n="68">2. The applicant shall bear any costs of translation prior to the transmission of the document, without prejudice to any possible subsequent decision by the court or competent authority on liability for such costs.</p>
      <p n="69">Article 6</p>
      <p n="70">Receipt of documents by receiving agency</p>
      <p n="71">1. On receipt of a document, a receiving agency shall, as soon as possible and in any event within seven days of receipt, send a receipt to the transmitting agency by the swiftest possible means of transmission using the standard form in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="72">2. Where the request for service cannot be fulfilled on the basis of the information or documents transmitted, the receiving agency shall contact the transmitting agency by the swiftest possible means in order to secure the missing information or documents.</p>
      <p n="73">3. If the request for service is manifestly outside the scope of this Regulation or if non-compliance with the formal conditions required makes service impossible, the request and the documents transmitted shall be returned, on receipt, to the transmitting agency, together with the notice of return in the standard form in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="74">4. A receiving agency receiving a document for service but not having territorial jurisdiction to serve it shall forward it, as well as the request, to the receiving agency having territorial jurisdiction in the same Member State if the request complies with the conditions laid down in Article 4(3) and shall inform the transmitting agency accordingly, using the standard form in the Annex. That receiving agency shall inform the transmitting agency when it receives the document, in the manner provided for in paragraph 1.</p>
      <p n="75">Article 7</p>
      <p n="76">Service of documents</p>
      <p n="77">1. The receiving agency shall itself serve the document or have it served, either in accordance with the law of the Member State addressed or by a particular form requested by the transmitting agency, unless such a method is incompatible with the law of that Member State.</p>
      <p n="78">2. All steps required for service of the document shall be effected as soon as possible. In any event, if it has not been possible to effect service within one month of receipt, the receiving agency shall inform the transmitting agency by means of the certificate in the standard form in the Annex, which shall be drawn up under the conditions referred to in Article 10(2). The period shall be calculated in accordance with the law of the Member State addressed.</p>
      <p n="79">Article 8</p>
      <p n="80">Refusal to accept a document</p>
      <p n="81">1. The receiving agency shall inform the addressee that he or she may refuse to accept the document to be served if it is in a language other than either of the following languages:</p>
      <p n="82">(a) the official language of the Member State addressed or, if there are several official languages in that Member State, the official language or one of the official languages of the place where service is to be effected; or</p>
      <p n="83">(b) a language of the Member State of transmission which the addressee understands.</p>
      <p n="84">2. Where the receiving agency is informed that the addressee refuses to accept the document in accordance with paragraph 1, it shall immediately inform the transmitting agency by means of the certificate provided for in Article 10 and return the request and the documents of which a translation is requested.</p>
      <p n="85">Article 9</p>
      <p n="86">Date of service</p>
      <p n="87">1. Without prejudice to Article 8, the date of service of a document pursuant to Article 7 shall be the date on which it is served in accordance with the law of the Member State addressed.</p>
      <p n="88">2. However, where a document shall be served within a particular period in the context of proceedings to be brought or pending in the Member State of origin, the date to be taken into account with respect to the applicant shall be that fixed by the law of that Member State.</p>
      <p n="89">3. A Member State shall be authorised to derogate from the provisions of paragraphs 1 and 2 for a transitional period of five years, for appropriate reasons.</p>
      <p n="90">This transitional period may be renewed by a Member State at five-yearly intervals due to reasons related to its legal system. That Member State shall inform the Commission of the content of such a derogation and the circumstances of the case.</p>
      <p n="91">Article 10</p>
      <p n="92">Certificate of service and copy of the document served</p>
      <p n="93">1. When the formalities concerning the service of the document have been completed, a certificate of completion of those formalities shall be drawn up in the standard form in the Annex and addressed to the transmitting agency, together with, where Article 4(5) applies, a copy of the document served.</p>
      <p n="94">2. The certificate shall be completed in the official language or one of the official languages of the Member State of origin or in another language which the Member State of origin has indicated that it can accept. Each Member State shall indicate the official language or languages of the European Union other than its own which is or are acceptable to it for completion of the form.</p>
      <p n="95">Article 11</p>
      <p n="96">Costs of service</p>
      <p n="97">1. The service of judicial documents coming from a Member State shall not give rise to any payment or reimbursement of taxes or costs for services rendered by the Member State addressed.</p>
      <p n="98">2. The applicant shall pay or reimburse the costs occasioned by:</p>
      <p n="99">(a) the employment of a judicial officer or of a person competent under the law of the Member State addressed;</p>
      <p n="100">(b) the use of a particular method of service.</p>
      <p n="101">Section 2</p>
      <p n="102">Other means of transmission and service of judicial documents</p>
      <p n="103">Article 12</p>
      <p n="104">Transmission by consular or diplomatic channels</p>
      <p n="105">Each Member State shall be free, in exceptional circumstances, to use consular or diplomatic channels to forward judicial documents, for the purpose of service, to those agencies of another Member State which are designated pursuant to Article 2 or 3.</p>
      <p n="106">Article 13</p>
      <p n="107">Service by diplomatic or consular agents</p>
      <p n="108">1. Each Member State shall be free to effect service of judicial documents on persons residing in another Member State, without application of any compulsion, directly through its diplomatic or consular agents.</p>
      <p n="109">2. Any Member State may make it known, in accordance with Article 23(1), that it is opposed to such service within its territory, unless the documents are to be served on nationals of the Member State in which the documents originate.</p>
      <p n="110">Article 14</p>
      <p n="111">Service by post</p>
      <p n="112">1. Each Member State shall be free to effect service of judicial documents directly by post to persons residing in another Member State.</p>
      <p n="113">2. Any Member State may specify, in accordance with Article 23(1), the conditions under which it will accept service of judicial documents by post.</p>
      <p n="114">Article 15</p>
      <p n="115">Direct service</p>
      <p n="116">1. This Regulation shall not interfere with the freedom of any person interested in a judicial proceeding to effect service of judicial documents directly through the judicial officers, officials or other competent persons of the Member State addressed.</p>
      <p n="117">2. Any Member State may make it known, in accordance with Article 23(1), that it is opposed to the service of judicial documents in its territory pursuant to paragraph 1.</p>
      <p n="118">CHAPTER III</p>
      <p n="119">EXTRAJUDICIAL DOCUMENTS</p>
      <p n="120">Article 16</p>
      <p n="121">Transmission</p>
      <p n="122">Extrajudicial documents may be transmitted for service in another Member State in accordance with the provisions of this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="123">CHAPTER IV</p>
      <p n="124">FINAL PROVISIONS</p>
      <p n="125">Article 17</p>
      <p n="126">Implementing rules</p>
      <p n="127">The measures necessary for the implementation of this Regulation relating to the matters referred to below shall be adopted in accordance with the advisory procedure referred to in Article 18(2):</p>
      <p n="128">(a) drawing up and annually updating a manual containing the information provided by Member States in accordance with Article 2(4);</p>
      <p n="129">(b) drawing up a glossary in the official languages of the European Union of documents which may be served under this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="130">(c) updating or making technical amendments to the standard form set out in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="131">Article 18</p>
      <p n="132">Committee</p>
      <p n="133">1. The Commission shall be assisted by a committee.</p>
      <p n="134">2. Where reference is made to this paragraph, Articles 3 and 7 of Decision 1999/468/EC shall apply.</p>
      <p n="135">3. The Committee shall adopt its rules of procedure.</p>
      <p n="136">Article 19</p>
      <p n="137">Defendant not entering an appearance</p>
      <p n="138">1. Where a writ of summons or an equivalent document has had to be transmitted to another Member State for the purpose of service, under the provisions of this Regulation, and the defendant has not appeared, judgment shall not be given until it is established that:</p>
      <p n="139">(a) the document was served by a method prescribed by the internal law of the Member State addressed for the service of documents in domestic actions upon persons who are within its territory; or</p>
      <p n="140">(b) the document was actually delivered to the defendant or to his residence by another method provided for by this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="141">and that in either of these cases the service or the delivery was effected in sufficient time to enable the defendant to defend.</p>
      <p n="142">2. Each Member State shall be free to make it known, in accordance with Article 23(1), that the judge, notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph 1, may give judgment even if no certificate of service or delivery has been received, if all the following conditions are fulfilled:</p>
      <p n="143">(a) the document was transmitted by one of the methods provided for in this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="144">(b) a period of time of not less than six months, considered adequate by the judge in the particular case, has elapsed since the date of the transmission of the document;</p>
      <p n="145">(c) no certificate of any kind has been received, even though every reasonable effort has been made to obtain it through the competent authorities or bodies of the Member State addressed.</p>
      <p n="146">3. Notwithstanding paragraphs 1 and 2, the judge may order, in case of urgency, any provisional or protective measures.</p>
      <p n="147">4. When a writ of summons or an equivalent document has had to be transmitted to another Member State for the purpose of service, under the provisions of this Regulation, and a judgment has been entered against a defendant who has not appeared, the judge shall have the power to relieve the defendant from the effects of the expiration of the time for appeal from the judgment if the following conditions are fulfilled:</p>
      <p n="148">(a) the defendant, without any fault on his part, did not have knowledge of the document in sufficient time to defend, or knowledge of the judgment in sufficient time to appeal; and</p>
      <p n="149">(b) the defendant has disclosed a prima facie defence to the action on the merits.</p>
      <p n="150">An application for relief may be filed only within a reasonable time after the defendant has knowledge of the judgment.</p>
      <p n="151">Each Member State may make it known, in accordance with Article 23(1), that such application will not be entertained if it is filed after the expiration of a time to be stated by it in that communication, but which shall in no case be less than one year following the date of the judgment.</p>
      <p n="152">5. Paragraph 4 shall not apply to judgments concerning status or capacity of persons.</p>
      <p n="153">Article 20</p>
      <p n="154">Relationship with agreements or arrangements to which Member States are Parties</p>
      <p n="155">1. This Regulation shall, in relation to matters to which it applies, prevail over other provisions contained in bilateral or multilateral agreements or arrangements concluded by the Member States, and in particular Article IV of the Protocol to the Brussels Convention of 1968 and the Hague Convention of 15 November 1965.</p>
      <p n="156">2. This Regulation shall not preclude individual Member States from maintaining or concluding agreements or arrangements to expedite further or simplify the transmission of documents, provided that they are compatible with this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="157">3. Member States shall send to the Commission:</p>
      <p n="158">(a) a copy of the agreements or arrangements referred to in paragraph 2 concluded between the Member States as well as drafts of such agreements or arrangements which they intend to adopt;</p>
      <p n="159">and</p>
      <p n="160">(b) any denunciation of, or amendments to, these agreements or arrangements.</p>
      <p n="161">Article 21</p>
      <p n="162">Legal aid</p>
      <p n="163">This Regulation shall not affect the application of Article 23 of the Convention on Civil Procedure of 17 July 1905, Article 24 of the Convention on Civil Procedure of 1 March 1954 or Article 13 of the Convention on International Access to Justice of 25 October 1980 between the Member States Parties to these Conventions.</p>
      <p n="164">Article 22</p>
      <p n="165">Protection of information transmitted</p>
      <p n="166">1. Information, including in particular personal data, transmitted under this Regulation shall be used by the receiving agency only for the purpose for which it was transmitted.</p>
      <p n="167">2. Receiving agencies shall ensure the confidentiality of such information, in accordance with their national law.</p>
      <p n="168">3. Paragraphs 1 and 2 shall not affect national laws enabling data subjects to be informed of the use made of information transmitted under this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="169">4. This Regulation shall be without prejudice to Directives 95/46/EC and 97/66/EC.</p>
      <p n="170">Article 23</p>
      <p n="171">Communication and publication</p>
      <p n="172">1. Member States shall communicate to the Commission the information referred to in Articles 2, 3, 4, 9, 10, 13, 14, 15, 17(a) and 19.</p>
      <p n="173">2. The Commission shall publish in the Official Journal of the European Communities the information referred to in paragraph 1.</p>
      <p n="174">Article 24</p>
      <p n="175">Review</p>
      <p n="176">No later than 1 June 2004, and every five years thereafter, the Commission shall present to the European Parliament, the Council and the Economic and Social Committee a report on the application of this Regulation, paying special attention to the effectiveness of the bodies designated pursuant to Article 2 and to the practical application of point (c) of Article 3 and Article 9. The report shall be accompanied if need be by proposals for adaptations of this Regulation in line with the evolution of notification systems.</p>
      <p n="177">Article 25</p>
      <p n="178">Entry into force</p>
      <p n="179">This Regulation shall enter into force on 31 May 2001.</p>
      <p n="180">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in the Member States in accordance with the Treaty establishing the European Community.</p>
      <p n="181">Done at Brussels, 29 May 2000.</p>
      <p n="182">For the Council</p>
      <p n="183">The President</p>
      <p n="184">A. Costa</p>
      <p n="185">(1) OJ C 247 E, 31.8.1999, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="186">(2) Opinion of 17 November 1999 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="187">(3) OJ C 368, 20.12.1999, p. 47.</p>
      <p n="188">(4) OJ C 261, 27.8.1997, p. 1. On the same day as the Convention was drawn up the Council took note of the explanatory report on the Convention which is set out on page 26 of the aforementioned Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="189">(5) Brussels Convention of 27 September 1968 on Jurisdiction and the Enforcement of Judgments in Civil and Commercial Matters (OJ L 299, 13.12.1972, p. 32; consolidated version, OJ C 27, 26.1.1998, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="190">(6) OJ L 281, 23.11.1995, p. 31.</p>
      <p n="191">(7) OJ L 24, 30.1.1998, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="192">(8) OJ L 184, 17.7.1999, p. 23.</p>
      <p n="193">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="194">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.004402.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="195">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.004501.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="196">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.004601.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="197">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.004701.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="198">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.004801.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="199">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.004901.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="200">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.005001.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="201">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.005101.EPS"&gt;</p>
      <p n="202">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2000160EN.005201.EPS"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
