<TEI.2 id="jrc42000D0491-en" n="42000D0491" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 42000D0491 English</title>
        <title>2000/491/EC, ECSC, Euratom: Decision of the Representatives of the Governments of the Member States of 26 July 2000 appointing Judges and Advocates-General to the Court of Justice of the European Communities</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>33 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:42000D0491:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:42000D0491:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1537</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">255</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3559</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4043</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5141</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc42000D0491-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2000/491/EC, ECSC, Euratom: Decision of the Representatives of the Governments of the Member States of 26 July 2000 appointing Judges and Advocates-General to the Court of Justice of the European Communities</head>
      <p n="2">Decision of the Representatives of the Governments of the Member States</p>
      <p n="3">of 26 July 2000</p>
      <p n="4">appointing Judges and Advocates-General to the Court of Justice of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="5">(2000/491/EC, ECSC, Euratom)</p>
      <p n="6">THE REPRESENTATIVES OF THE GOVERNMENTS OF THE MEMBER STATES OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 223 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Coal and Steel Community, and in particular Article 32b thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular Article 139 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">(1) The terms of office of Ms Ninon COLNERIC and Messrs David A. O. EDWARD, Peter JANN, P. J. G. KAPTEYN, Antonio Mario LA PERGOLA, José Carlos MOITINHO DE ALMEIDA, Jean-Pierre PUISSOCHET, Hans RAGNEMALM, Judges, and those of Messrs Georgios COSMAS, Nial FENNELLY, Philippe LEGER and Antonio SAGGIO, Advocates-General to the Court of Justice of the European Communities, expire on 6 October 2000.</p>
      <p n="12">(2) A partial replacement of the Court of Justice of the European Communities should take place for the period from 7 October 2000 up to and including 6 October 2006,</p>
      <p n="13">HAVE DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">1. The following are hereby appointed Judges of the Court of Justice of the European Communities for the period from 7 October 2000 to 6 October 2006:</p>
      <p n="16">Ms Ninon COLNERIC</p>
      <p n="17">Mr José Narciso DA CUNHA RODRIGUES</p>
      <p n="18">Mr David A. O. EDWARD</p>
      <p n="19">Mr Peter JANN</p>
      <p n="20">Mr Antonio Mario LA PERGOLA</p>
      <p n="21">Mr Jean-Pierre PUISSOCHET</p>
      <p n="22">Mr Christiaan W. A. TIMMERMANS</p>
      <p n="23">Mr Stig VON BAHR</p>
      <p n="24">2. The following are hereby appointed Advocates-General of the Court of Justice of the European Communities for the period from 7 October 2000 to 6 October 2006:</p>
      <p n="25">Mr L. A. GEELHOED</p>
      <p n="26">Mr Philippe LEGER</p>
      <p n="27">Ms Christine STIX-HACKL</p>
      <p n="28">Mr Antonio TIZZANO</p>
      <p n="29">Article 2</p>
      <p n="30">This Decision shall be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="31">Done at Brussels, 26 July 2000.</p>
      <p n="32">The President</p>
      <p n="33">P. Vimont</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
