<TEI.2 id="jrc21976A1129_03-en" n="21976A1129(03)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21976A1129(03) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>69 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21976A1129(03):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21976A1129(03):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21976A1129_03-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">Agreement in the form of an exchange of letters amending Table I annexed to Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland</p>
      <p n="3">Brussels, ...</p>
      <p n="4">Your Excellency,</p>
      <p n="5">The Contracting Parties to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland signed on 22 July 1972 have examined in the Joint Committee the possibility of making certain amendments to Table I annexed to Protocol 2 to the said Agreement. The proposed amendments are set out in Annex I.</p>
      <p n="6">I have the honour to confirm to you the agreement of the Community to the amendments and I propose that they enter into force on 1 January 1977. I should be grateful if you would confirm the agreement of your Government to the amendments and to the date proposed for their entry into force.</p>
      <p n="7">In addition, I should like to take this opportunity to inform you that since 1 January 1976 non-crystallizable sorbitol has been transferred from heading No 29.04 to heading No 38.19 of the Common Customs Tariff. Since this product is listed in Table I of Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the Community and your country, it would be desirable for practical reasons to adjust the tariff lists in the Agreement. These adjustments are set out in Annex II. This change of heading does not affect in any way the tariff treatment laid down by Protocol 2 for the product in question.</p>
      <p n="8">Please accept, Your Excellency, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="9">On behalf of the Council</p>
      <p n="10">of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="11">ANNEX I Amendments to be made to Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland</p>
      <p n="12">Table I is amended as follows: -</p>
      <p n="13">in subheading 29.16 A ex VIII. Other, the description is replaced by:</p>
      <p n="14">German text:</p>
      <p n="15">ex VIII. andere: -</p>
      <p n="16">Glycerinsäure, Glykolsäure, Zuckersäure, Isozuckersäure, Heptazuckersäure, ihre Salze und Ester.</p>
      <p n="17">English text:</p>
      <p n="18">ex VIII. Other: -</p>
      <p n="19">Glyceric acid, glycolic acid, saccharic acid, isosaccharic acid, heptasaccharic acid, their salts and esters.</p>
      <p n="20">French text:</p>
      <p n="21">ex VIII. autres: -</p>
      <p n="22">Acide glycérique, acide glycolique, acide saccharique, acide isosaccharique, acide heptasaccharique, leurs sels et leurs esters.</p>
      <p n="23">Italian text:</p>
      <p n="24">ex VIII. altri: -</p>
      <p n="25">Acido glicerico, acido glicolico, acido saccarico, acido isosaccarico, acido eptasaccarico, loro sali e loro esteri.</p>
      <p n="26">Dutch text:</p>
      <p n="27">ex VIII. andere: -</p>
      <p n="28">Glycerinezuur, glycolzuur, suikerzuur, isosuikerzuur, heptasuikerzuur, alsmede zouten en esters daarvan.</p>
      <p n="29">The Danish text remains unchanged.</p>
      <p n="30">ANNEX II Amendments to be made to Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland</p>
      <p n="31">Table I is amended as follows: -</p>
      <p n="32">in heading No 38.19, subheading</p>
      <p n="33">ex T. Other:</p>
      <p n="34">is replaced by:</p>
      <p n="35">&lt;PIC FILE="T0008887"&gt;</p>
      <p n="36">Brussels, ...</p>
      <p n="37">Sir,</p>
      <p n="38">I have the honour to acknowledge receipt of your letter of today worded as follows:</p>
      <p n="39">"The Contracting Parties to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland signed on 22 July 1972 have examined in the Joint Committee the possibility of making certain amendments to Table I annexed to Protocol 2 to the said Agreement. The proposed amendments are set out in Annex I.</p>
      <p n="40">I have the honour to confirm to you the agreement of the Community to the amendments and I propose that they enter into force on 1 January 1977. I should be grateful if you would confirm the agreement of your Government to the amendments and to the date proposed for their entry into force.</p>
      <p n="41">In addition, I should like to take this opportunity to inform you that since 1 January 1976 non-crystallizable sorbitol has been transferred from heading No 29.04 to heading No 38.19 of the Common Customs Tariff. Since this product is listed in Table I of Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the Community and your country, it would be desirable for practical reasons to adjust the tariff lists in the Agreement. These adjustments are set out in Annex II. This change of heading does not affect in any way the tariff treatment laid down by Protocol 2 for the product in question."</p>
      <p n="42">I have the honour to confirm the agreement of your Government to the contents of your letter and to the date proposed for the entry into force of the amendments.</p>
      <p n="43">Please accept, Sir, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="44">For the Government of</p>
      <p n="45">the Republic of Iceland</p>
      <p n="46">ANNEX I Amendments to be made to Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland</p>
      <p n="47">Table I is amended as follows: -</p>
      <p n="48">in subheading 29.16 A ex VIII. Other, the description is replaced by:</p>
      <p n="49">German text:</p>
      <p n="50">ex VIII. andere: -</p>
      <p n="51">Glycerinsäure, Glykolsäure, Zuckersäure, Isozuckersäure, Heptazuckersäure, ihre Salze und Ester.</p>
      <p n="52">English text:</p>
      <p n="53">ex VIII. Other: -</p>
      <p n="54">Glyceric acid, glycolic acid, saccharic acid, isosaccharic acid, heptasaccharic acid, their salts and esters.</p>
      <p n="55">French text:</p>
      <p n="56">ex VIII. autres: -</p>
      <p n="57">Acide glycérique, acide glicolique, acide saccharique, acide isosaccharique, acide heptasaccharique, leurs sels et leurs esters.</p>
      <p n="58">Italian text:</p>
      <p n="59">ex VIII. altri: -</p>
      <p n="60">Acido glicerico, acido glycolico, acido saccarico, acido isosaccarico, acido eptasaccarico, loro sali e loro esteri.</p>
      <p n="61">Dutch text:</p>
      <p n="62">ex VIII. andere: -</p>
      <p n="63">Glicerinezuur, glycolzuur, suikerzuur, isosuikerzuur, heptasuikerzuur, alsmede zouten en esters daarvan.</p>
      <p n="64">The Danish text remains unchanged.</p>
      <p n="65">ANNEX II Amendments to be made to Protocol 2 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Iceland</p>
      <p n="66">Table I is amended as follows: -</p>
      <p n="67">in heading No 38.19, subheading</p>
      <p n="68">ex T. Other:</p>
      <p n="69">is replaced by:</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
