<TEI.2 id="jrc31976R0311-en" n="31976R0311" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31976R0311 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 311/76 of 9 February 1976 on the compilation of statistics on foreign workers</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>33 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976R0311:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976R0311:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31976R0311-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 311/76 of 9 February 1976 on the compilation of statistics on foreign workers</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 311/76 of 9 February 1976 on the compilation of statistics on foreign workers</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 213 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (2),</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas statistics should be made available concerning the number of foreign workers and the first employment taken up by such workers in the Member States of the Community,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">1. Member States shall, in respect of workers who are nationals of another Member State or of a third country, compile statistics on: - the number of workers,</p>
      <p n="12">- the first employment taken up by the worker concerned in its territory in a given year.</p>
      <p n="13">The statistics shall comprise the following information: - nationality,</p>
      <p n="14">- sex,</p>
      <p n="15">- age,</p>
      <p n="16">- branch of activity or occupational group,</p>
      <p n="17">- region.</p>
      <p n="18">2. Member States shall compile statistics once a year from the various sources normally available to them, in particular social security data, censuses, statistics supplied by employers or residence or work permits.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">1. Upon the entry into force of this Regulation, Member States shall forward to the Commission all available data on the information referred to in Article 1 (1).</p>
      <p n="21">Within a maximum period of five years following the entry into force of this Regulation, Member States shall forward to the Commission all the data on the information referred to in Article 1 (1).</p>
      <p n="22">2. Member States, when forwarding the data to the Commission, shall state the sources used.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 3</p>
      <p n="24">1. In implementing this Regulation, Member States shall collaborate closely with the Commission.</p>
      <p n="25">2. Member States shall inform the Commission not later than 31 March each year of progress made in applying the second subparagraph of Article 2 (1).</p>
      <p n="26">The Commission shall report to the Council on the basis of the information obtained.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 4</p>
      <p n="28">This Regulation shall enter into force on the first day of the month following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="29">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="30">Done at Brussels, 9 February 1976.</p>
      <p n="31">For the Council</p>
      <p n="32">The President</p>
      <p n="33">G. THORN (1)OJ No C 129, 11.12.1972, p. 13. (2)OJ No C 60, 26.7.1973, p. 7.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
