<TEI.2 id="jrc31976R1155-en" n="31976R1155" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31976R1155 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1155/76 of 18 May 1976 amending Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 as regards quality standards for asparagus fern</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>104 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976R1155:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976R1155:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31976R1155-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1155/76 of 18 May 1976 amending Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 as regards quality standards for asparagus fern</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1155/76 of 18 May 1976 amending Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 as regards quality standards for asparagus fern</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 234/68 of 27 February 1968 on the establishment of a common organization of the market in live trees and other plants, bulbs, roots and the like, cut flowers and ornamental foliage (1), and in particular Article 4 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas experience has shown that the special provisions relating to asparagus fern set out in Annex II A to Council Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 of 12 March 1968 fixing quality standards for fresh cut flowers and fresh ornamental foliage (2), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 802/71 (3), do not correspond to modern marketing practices;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas therefore the said Annex II A should be amended accordingly;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the Management Committee for live trees and other plants, bulbs, roots and the like, cut flowers and ornamental foliage has not delivered an opinion within the time limit set by its chairman,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Annex II A to Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 is hereby replaced by the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 18 May 1976.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="17">P.J. LARDINOIS</p>
      <p n="18">Member of the Commission (1)OJ No L 55, 2.3.1968, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 71, 21.3.1968, p. 8. (3)OJ No L 88, 20.4.1971, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="19">ANNEX COMMON QUALITY STANDARDS FOR FRESH ORNAMENTAL FOLIAGE</p>
      <p n="20">SPECIAL PROVISIONS FOR FOLIAGE OF ASPARAGUS SPRENGERI</p>
      <p n="21">I. DESCRIPTION OF PRODUCE</p>
      <p n="22">These special provisions apply to the foliage of Asparagus densiflorus (Kunth) Jeasop "Sprengeri" (Syn. Asparagus L. sprengeri Rgl.).</p>
      <p n="23">II. QUALITY REQUIREMENTS</p>
      <p n="24">(i) Class I</p>
      <p n="25">The foliage of Asparagus sprengeri in this class must be: - well developed, not broken and without side growth,</p>
      <p n="26">- well furnished with firmly attached cladodes,</p>
      <p n="27">- free of yellowing,</p>
      <p n="28">- free of fruits.</p>
      <p n="29">(ii) Class II</p>
      <p n="30">This class includes all foliage of Asparagus sprengeri not meeting the requirements of Class I but meeting the quality requirements laid down for fresh foliage particularly regarding the typical colouring which should exclude any yellowing.</p>
      <p n="31">III. SIZING</p>
      <p n="32">Length shall be measured from the end of the stem to the tip. For Asparagus sprengeri this sizing must comply with the following scale: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0010084"&gt;</p>
      <p n="33">Shoots of Asparagus sprengeri forming a bunch must be of more or less uniform length.</p>
      <p n="34">IV. TOLERANCES</p>
      <p n="35">A. Quality tolerances</p>
      <p n="36">The following tolerances shall be permitted in each unit of presentation: (i) Class I</p>
      <p n="37">10 % of the stems may vary from the requirements of this class but they must comply with those of Class II. No tolerance shall be permitted for stems which are broken or which have a side growth.</p>
      <p n="38">(ii) Class II</p>
      <p n="39">10 % of the stems may vary from the requirements of this class. Any defects must not impair the utility of the products.</p>
      <p n="40">B. Length tolerances</p>
      <p n="41">10 % of the number of stems which exceed the fixed limits is permitted ; the shortest stems may in no case be more than 5 cm shorter than the code given.</p>
      <p n="42">V. PACKAGING AND PRESENTATION</p>
      <p n="43">A. Presentation</p>
      <p n="44">The foliage of Asparagus sprengeri shall be made up into bunches of 100 g, 250 g or multiples of 250 g.</p>
      <p n="45">B. Uniformity</p>
      <p n="46">Broken stems shall be made up into separate bunches. Stems in the same bunch must be uniform in shape and colour.</p>
      <p n="47">C. Packaging</p>
      <p n="48">Packaging must be such as to protect the produce adequately. Paper or other materials in direct contact with the produce must be new ; when printed matter is used, the printing must be on the outside only so as not to come into contact with the produce.</p>
      <p n="49">VI. MARKING</p>
      <p n="50">The following particulars must accompany the goods: A. Identification &gt;PIC FILE= "T0010085"&gt;</p>
      <p n="51">B. Nature of produce</p>
      <p n="52">Asparagus sprengeri or Asparagus densiflorus and possibly the variety.</p>
      <p n="53">C. Origin of product (optional)</p>
      <p n="54">Region of origin or national, regional or local name.</p>
      <p n="55">D. Commercial specifications - class,</p>
      <p n="56">- minimum and maximum length or code of size,</p>
      <p n="57">- number of bunches and unit weight of each bunch.</p>
      <p n="58">E. Official control mark (optional).</p>
      <p n="59">SPECIAL PROVISIONS FOR ASPARAGUS PLUMOSUS</p>
      <p n="60">I. DESCRIPTION OF PRODUCT</p>
      <p n="61">These special provisions apply to the foliage of Asparagus setaccus (Kunth) Jessop (Syn. Asparagus L. plumosus Bak.).</p>
      <p n="62">III. QUALITY REQUIREMENTS</p>
      <p n="63">A. Special requirements</p>
      <p n="64">The typical colouring of the species comprises a range of varying shades of green (1). The products must not, however, be clorotic ; they must be furnished with cladodes having an equal colouring.</p>
      <p n="65">Foliage of Asparagus plumosus may be presented in the form of: - fern (shoots of regular growth having the appearance of palm leaves),</p>
      <p n="66">- clipped fern (shoots of which the upper ends have been cut off, having the appearance of a garland of greenery).</p>
      <p n="67">B. Classification (i) Class I</p>
      <p n="68">The foliage of Asparagus plumosus in this class must: - be well developed,</p>
      <p n="69">- have a stem well garnished with foliage,</p>
      <p n="70">- be furnished with firmly attached cladodes. (1)Asparagus plumosus foliage bearing the description "blond" or "biondo" is also admissible, provided that it conforms to the requirements of the quality standard applicable for this product.</p>
      <p n="71">Fern must not be broken and must be without side growth. Clipped fern may be included in this class.</p>
      <p n="72">(ii) Class II</p>
      <p n="73">This class includes all foliage of Asparagus plumosus not meeting the requirements of Class I but meeting the quality requirements laid down for fresh foliage and the special requirements above. Nevertheless, produce having certain defects of appearance may be included in this class. Broken fern or fern with side growth should be presented separately.</p>
      <p n="74">III. SIZING</p>
      <p n="75">The length shall be measured from the end of the stem to the tip. For fern the sizing must comply with the following scale: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0010086"&gt;</p>
      <p n="76">For clipped fern the sizing must comply with the following scale: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0010087"&gt;</p>
      <p n="77">IV. TOLERANCES</p>
      <p n="78">A. Quality tolerances</p>
      <p n="79">The following tolerances shall be permitted in each unit of presentation: (i) Class I</p>
      <p n="80">10 % of the stems may vary from the requirements of this class but they must comply with those of Class II.</p>
      <p n="81">No tolerance shall be permitted for fern which is broken or which has a side growth.</p>
      <p n="82">(ii) Class II</p>
      <p n="83">10 % of the stems may vary from the requirements of this class. Any defects must not impair the utility of the products.</p>
      <p n="84">B. Length tolerance</p>
      <p n="85">10 % of the number of stems which exceed the fixed limits is permitted ; the shortest stems may in no case be more than 5 cm shorter than the code given.</p>
      <p n="86">V. PACKAGING AND PRESENTATION</p>
      <p n="87">A. Presentation</p>
      <p n="88">The foliage of Asparagus plumosus shall be made up into bunches of 10 stems or multiples of 10.</p>
      <p n="89">B. Uniformity</p>
      <p n="90">Fern in one bunch must be of uniform colouring. Fern, clipped fern and fern without points of growth, exclusively classified in Class II, shall be made up into separate bunches.</p>
      <p n="91">C. Packaging</p>
      <p n="92">Packaging must be such as to protect the produce adequately. Paper or other materials in direct contact with the produce must be new ; when printed matter is used, the printing must be on the outside only so as not to come into contact with the produce.</p>
      <p n="93">VI. MARKING</p>
      <p n="94">The following particulars must accompany the goods: A. Identification. &gt;PIC FILE= "T0010088"&gt;</p>
      <p n="95">B. Nature of produce (optional)</p>
      <p n="96">Asparagus plumosus or Asparagus setaccus.</p>
      <p n="97">C. Origin of produce (optional)</p>
      <p n="98">Region of origin or national, regional or local name.</p>
      <p n="99">D. Commercial specifications - class,</p>
      <p n="100">- the indication "fern" or "clipped fern",</p>
      <p n="101">- number of bunches and number of stems per bunch,</p>
      <p n="102">- minimum and maximum length or code of size,</p>
      <p n="103">- the indication "blond" or "biondo" should the occasion arise.</p>
      <p n="104">E. Official control mark (optional).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
