<TEI.2 id="jrc31976L0766-en" n="31976L0766" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31976L0766 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 76/766/EEC of 27 July 1976 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to alcohol tables</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>49 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976L0766:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976L0766:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31976L0766-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 76/766/EEC of 27 July 1976 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to alcohol tables</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DIRECTIVE of 27 July 1976 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to alcohol tables (76/766/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 100 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (2),</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, in several Member States there are laws concerning the determination of the alcoholic strength of a mixture of water and ethanol, and whereas these laws differ from one Member State to another, thus creating obstacles to trade ; whereas, Community harmonization in this field and the establishment of a common definition are therefore necessary;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, in its resolution of 17 December 1973 (3) on industrial policy, the Council invited the Commission to forward to it before 1 December 1974 a proposal for a Directive on alcoholometry and alcoholometers;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas harmonization of the laws, regulations and administrative provisions relating to the method for determining alcoholic strength from the results of measurements taken is essential also as a complement to the Directive on the harmonization of alcoholometers and alcohol hydrometers, in order to remove all risk of ambiguity or dispute,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">This Directive defines the method of expressing alcoholic strength, by volume or by mass, as defined in the Annex, and gives a formula to enable tables to be drawn up for calculating alcoholic strength on the basis of the measurements taken.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">As from 1 January 1980 Member States may not question the figures for alcoholic strength derived from the alcoholometric tables drawn up on the basis of the formula shown in the Annex, and from measurements taken with alcoholometers or alcohol hydrometers bearing the EEC marks and signs or with instruments providing at least an equivalent degree of accuracy, on grounds connected with the use of these tables or instruments.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 3</p>
      <p n="17">The symbols used to indicate alcoholic strength as mentioned in Article 2 and defined in the Annex shall be as follows:</p>
      <p n="18">"% vol" for alcoholic strength by volume,</p>
      <p n="19">"% mas" for alcoholic strength by mass.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 4</p>
      <p n="21">As from 1 January 1980, Member States shall prohibit the use of alcoholic strengths which do not comply with the requirements of this Directive.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 5</p>
      <p n="23">1. Member States shall adopt and publish within a period of 24 months from the date of notification (1)OJ No C 76, 7.4.1975, p. 39. (2)OJ No C 248, 29.10.1975, p. 22. (3)OJ No C 117, 31.12.1973, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="24">of this Directive the measures necessary to conform with this Directive and shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="25">They shall apply these measures from 1 January 1980 at the latest.</p>
      <p n="26">2. Member States shall inform the Commission of the texts of the main provisions of national law which they adopt in the field covered by this Directive.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 6</p>
      <p n="28">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="29">Done at Brussels, 27 July 1976.</p>
      <p n="30">For the Council</p>
      <p n="31">The President</p>
      <p n="32">M. van der STOEL</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="34">ALCOHOLIC STRENGTH</p>
      <p n="35">1. DEFINITION</p>
      <p n="36">The "alcoholic strength by volume" of a mixture of water and ethanol is the ratio of the volume of pure alcohol present in the mixture at 20 ºC to the total volume of the mixture at the same temperature.</p>
      <p n="37">The "alcoholic strength by mass" of a mixture of water and ethanol is the ratio of the mass of alcohol present in this mixture to the total mass of the mixture.</p>
      <p n="38">2. EXPRESSION OF ALCOHOLIC STRENGTH</p>
      <p n="39">The alcoholic strength is expressed as the parts of alcohol per hundred parts of the mixture.</p>
      <p n="40">The relevant symbols are:</p>
      <p n="41">"% vol" for the alcoholic strength by volume,</p>
      <p n="42">"% mas" for the alcoholic strength by mass.</p>
      <p n="43">3. DETERMINATION OF ALCOHOLIC STRENGTH</p>
      <p n="44">The procedures to be carried out to determine the alcoholic strength by means of the instruments provided for in the Council Directive of 27 July 1976 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to alcoholometers and alcohol hydrometers (1) shall be as follows: - the reading of an alcoholometer or alcohol hydrometer, at the temperature of the mixture,</p>
      <p n="45">- the measurement of the temperature of the mixture.</p>
      <p n="46">The results shall be obtained from the international alcohol tables.</p>
      <p n="47">4. FORMULA FOR THE CALCULATION OF INTERNATIONAL ALCOHOL TABLES FOR MIXTURES OF WATER AND ETHANOL &gt;PIC FILE= "T0009534"&gt; (1)See page 143 of this Official Journal. &gt;PIC FILE= "T9000936"&gt;</p>
      <p n="48">NUMERICAL COEFFICIENTS IN THE FORMULA</p>
      <p n="49">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0009535"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
