<TEI.2 id="jrc31976D0753-en" n="31976D0753" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31976D0753 English</title>
        <title>76/753/Euratom: Commission Decision of 17 September 1976 concluding the framework Agreement for commercial and economic cooperation between the European Communities and Canada</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976D0753:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31976D0753:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31976D0753-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">76/753/Euratom: Commission Decision of 17 September 1976 concluding the framework Agreement for commercial and economic cooperation between the European Communities and Canada</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 17 September 1976 concluding the Framework Agreement for commercial and economic cooperation between the European Communities and Canada (76/753/Euratom)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular the second paragraph of Article 101 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the approval of the Council,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Framework Agreement for commercial and economic cooperation between the European Communities and Canada, signed in Ottawa on 6 July 1976, should be concluded on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community,</p>
      <p n="7">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="8">Article 1</p>
      <p n="9">The Framework Agreement for commercial and economic cooperation between the European Communities and Canada is hereby concluded and approved on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community.</p>
      <p n="10">The text of the Agreement is annexed to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">The President of the Commission shall give, as regards the Community, the notification provided for in Article 8 of the Agreement (1).</p>
      <p n="13">Article 3</p>
      <p n="14">This Decision shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 17 September 1976.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="17">Christopher SOAMES</p>
      <p n="18">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="19">(1) The date of entry into force of the Agreement, as regards the European Atomic Energy Community, will be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
