<TEI.2 id="jrc31998R1009-en" n="31998R1009" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31998R1009 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1009/98 of 14 May 1998 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>39 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31998R1009:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31998R1009:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1642</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3568</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4687</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31998R1009-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1009/98 of 14 May 1998 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 1009/98 of 14 May 1998 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2777/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common organisation of the market in poultrymeat (1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) 2916/95 (2), and in particular Article 3(2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2370/96 (4), lays down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3665/87 (5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 604/98 (6), lays down common detailed rules for the application of the system of export refunds on agricultural products; whereas Article 3 thereof defines the day of export; whereas the text of Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 should be amended to adjust it to that definition;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Commission Regulation (EC) No 2448/95 of 10 October 1995 amending Annex I to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2658/87 on the tariff and statistical nomenclature and on the Common Customs Tariff (7) establishes new subdivisions of CN code 0105 with effect from 1 January 1996; whereas Articles 1 and 9 of Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 should therefore be adjusted;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Articles 4 and 9 of and Annex II to Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 contain errors which should be corrected;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the time limit for notification by Member States to the Commission of applications for 'ex-post` export licences should be the same as for other export licences;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of Management Committee for Poultrymeat and Eggs,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="15">1. in Articles 1 and 9(1), 'CN codes 0105 11 and 0105 19` is replaced by 'CN codes 0105 11, 0105 12 and 0105 19`;</p>
      <p n="16">2. in Article 4(3)(a), the references to Sections 17 and 18 are replaced by references to Sections 15 and 16;</p>
      <p n="17">3. in Article 9:</p>
      <p n="18">(a) in the first subparagraph of paragraph 2:</p>
      <p n="19">- the reference to Section 22 is replaced by a reference to Section 20,</p>
      <p n="20">- the phrase 'the date on which they took place` is replaced by 'the date of export within the meaning of Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) No 3665/87`;</p>
      <p n="21">(b) in the first subparagraph of paragraph 3, the first sentence is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="22">'Member States shall communicate to the Commission, each Friday from 1 p.m., by fax, the number of 'ex-post` export licences applied for or the absence of such applications, during the current week.`;</p>
      <p n="23">(c) in paragraph 4, the second subparagraph is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="24">'This licence accords entitlement to payment of the refund applicable on the day of export within the meaning of Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) No 3665/87.`;</p>
      <p n="25">4. in Annex II, Part A, 'ECU/100 kg` is replaced by 'ECU/100 kg or 100 pieces`.</p>
      <p n="26">Article 2</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 June 1998.</p>
      <p n="28">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="29">Done at Brussels, 14 May 1998.</p>
      <p n="30">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="31">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="32">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="33">(1) OJ L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 77.</p>
      <p n="34">(2) OJ L 305, 19. 12. 1995, p. 49.</p>
      <p n="35">(3) OJ L 133, 17. 6. 1995, p. 26.</p>
      <p n="36">(4) OJ L 323, 13. 12. 1996, p. 12.</p>
      <p n="37">(5) OJ L 351, 14. 12. 1987, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="38">(6) OJ L 80, 18. 3. 1998, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="39">(7) OJ L 259, 30. 10. 1995, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
