<TEI.2 id="jrc32005D0086-en" n="32005D0086" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32005D0086 English</title>
        <title>2005/86/EC: Commission Decision of 28 January 2005 amending Decision 2003/71/EC as regards its period of validity (notified under document number C(2005) 186)Text with EEA relevance</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>33 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0086:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0086:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32005D0086-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2005/86/EC: Commission Decision of 28 January 2005 amending Decision 2003/71/EC as regards its period of validity (notified under document number C(2005) 186)Text with EEA relevance</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 28 January 2005</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 2003/71/EC as regards its period of validity</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2005) 186)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2005/86/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 91/496/EEC of 15 July 1991 laying down the principles governing the organisation of veterinary checks on animals entering the Community from third countries and amending Directives 89/662/EEC, 90/425/EEC and 90/675/EEC [1], and in particular Article 18(7) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Having regard to Council Directive 97/78/EC of 18 December 1997 laying down the principles governing the organisation of veterinary checks on products entering the Community from third countries [2] and in particular Article 22(6) thereof,</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="13">(1) The occurrence of infectious salmon anaemia (ISA) in the Faroe Islands led to the adoption of Commission Decision 2003/71/EC of 29 January 2003 on certain protective measures in respect of infectious salmon anaemia in the Faroe Islands [3].</p>
      <p n="14">(2) Despite the control measures undertaken by the Faroe Islands, further outbreaks of ISA occurred and were notified by that State to the Commission in 2004.</p>
      <p n="15">(3) The Faroe Islands have submitted to the veterinary subgroup established under the EU-Faroe Island Agreement [4] a contingency plan in conformity with Article 15 of Council Directive 93/53/EEC of 24 June 1993 introducing minimum Community measures for the control of certain fish diseases [5]. The contingency plan includes a withdrawal scheme in accordance with Article 6 of Directive 93/53/EEC. The contingency plan, including vaccination procedures, and withdrawal scheme submitted in September 2004 have been approved by the subgroup.</p>
      <p n="16">(4) In the light of the disease situation in the Faroe Islands and the implementation of a control strategy including vaccination, the protective measures provided for in Decision 2003/71/EC should remain applicable as long as vaccination is applied. The vaccination is expected to remain as the control strategy for at least the next two years.</p>
      <p n="17">(5) Decision 2003/71/EC should therefore be amended in order to extend its period of validity.</p>
      <p n="18">(6) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="19">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="20">Article 1</p>
      <p n="21">In Article 6 of Decision 2003/71/EC, " 31 January 2005" is replaced by " 31 January 2007".</p>
      <p n="22">Article 2</p>
      <p n="23">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="24">Done at Brussels, 28 January 2005.</p>
      <p n="25">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">Markos Kyprianou</p>
      <p n="27">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="28">[1] OJ L 268, 24.9.1991, p. 56. Directive as last amended by the 2003 Act of Accession.</p>
      <p n="29">[2] OJ L 24, 30.1.1998, p. 9. Directive as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council (OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="30">[3] OJ L 26, 31.1.2003, p. 80. Decision as last amended by Decision 2004/160/EC (OJ L 50, 20.2.2004, p. 65).</p>
      <p n="31">[4] OJ L 53, 22.2.1997, p. 2.</p>
      <p n="32">[5] OJ L 175, 19.7.1993, p. 23. Directive as last amended by the 2003 Act of Accession.</p>
      <p n="33">--------------------------------------------------</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
