<TEI.2 id="jrc32005D0107-en" n="32005D0107" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32005D0107 English</title>
        <title>2005/107/EC: Commission Decision of 2 February 2005 amending Annexes I and II to Decision 2002/308/EC establishing lists of approved zones and approved farms with regard to one or more of the fish diseases viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN) (notified under document number C(2005) 188) (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0107:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0107:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32005D0107-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2005/107/EC: Commission Decision of 2 February 2005 amending Annexes I and II to Decision 2002/308/EC establishing lists of approved zones and approved farms with regard to one or more of the fish diseases viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN) (notified under document number C(2005) 188) (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 2 February 2005</p>
      <p n="4">amending Annexes I and II to Decision 2002/308/EC establishing lists of approved zones and approved farms with regard to one or more of the fish diseases viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN)</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2005) 188)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2005/107/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 91/67/EEC of 28 January 1991 concerning the animal health conditions governing the placing on the market of aquaculture animals and products [1], and in particular Articles 5 and 6 thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) Commission Decision 2002/308/EC [2] establishes the lists of approved zones and approved fish farms situated in non-approved zones with regard to certain fish diseases.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) France has submitted the justifications for obtaining the status of approved zones, with regard to VHS and IHN, for certain zones in its territory. The documentation provided shows that those zones meet the requirements of Article 5 of Directive 91/67/EEC. They therefore qualify for the status of approved zones and should be added to the list of approved zones.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) Denmark, France and Italy have submitted the justifications for obtaining the status of approved farms in non-approved zones, with regard to VHS and IHN, for certain farms in their territory. The documentation provided shows that those farms meet the requirements of Article 6 of Directive 91/67/EEC. They therefore qualify for the status of approved farm in a non-approved zone and should be added to the list of approved farms.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) Commission Decision 2003/634/EC [3] approves and lists programmes submitted by the Member States for the purpose of obtaining the status of approved zones and of approved farms with regard to VHS and IHN. Italy has notified that two programmes approved by that Decision have been finalised. The documentation provided shows that one farm qualifies for the status of approved farm in a non-approved zone and should be added to the list of approved farms, while one zone qualifies for the status of approved zones and should be added to the list of approved zones.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) Decision 2002/308/EC should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">Decision 2002/308/EC is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="21">1. Annex I is replaced by Annex I to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="22">2. Annex II is replaced by Annex II to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="25">Done at Brussels, 2 February 2005.</p>
      <p n="26">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="27">Markos Kyprianou</p>
      <p n="28">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="29">[1] OJ L 46, 19.2.1991, p. 1. Directive as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 806/2003 (OJ L 122, 16.5.2003, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="30">[2] OJ L 106, 23.4.2002, p. 28. Decision as last amended by Decision 2004/850/EC (OJ L 368, 15.12.2004, p. 28).</p>
      <p n="31">[3] OJ L 220, 3.9.2003, p. 8. Decision as last amended by Decision 2004/328/EC (OJ L 104, 8.4.2004, p. 129).</p>
      <p n="32">--------------------------------------------------</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="34">--------------------------------------------------</p>
      <p n="35">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="36">--------------------------------------------------</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
