<TEI.2 id="jrc32005D0154-en" n="32005D0154" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32005D0154 English</title>
        <title>2005/154/EC: Commission Decision of 18 February 2005 amending Decision 2003/760/EC laying down special conditions governing imports of fishery and products from French Polynesia, as regards the designation of the competent authority and the model of health certificate (notified under document number C(2005) 356) (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>37 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0154:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32005D0154:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32005D0154-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2005/154/EC: Commission Decision of 18 February 2005 amending Decision 2003/760/EC laying down special conditions governing imports of fishery and products from French Polynesia, as regards the designation of the competent authority and the model of health certificate (notified under document number C(2005) 356) (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 18 February 2005</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 2003/760/EC laying down special conditions governing imports of fishery and products from French Polynesia, as regards the designation of the competent authority and the model of health certificate</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2005) 356)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2005/154/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 91/493/EEC of 22 July 1991 laying down the health conditions for the production and the placing on the market of fishery products [1], and in particular Article 11(1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) In Commission Decision 2003/760/EC [2], the "Département de la Qualité Alimentaire et de l’Action Vétérinaire (DQAAV) du Service de Développement Rural du Ministère de l’Agriculture et de l’Élevage" is identified as the competent authority in French Polynesia for verifying and certifying compliance of fishery and aquaculture products with the requirements of Directive 91/493/EEC.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) Following a restructuring of the Polynesian administration, the competent authority has changed to the "Département de la qualité alimentaire et de l’action vétérinaire (DQAAV) du Ministère de la promotion des ressources naturelles, chargé de la perliculture, de la pêche, de l’aquaculture, de l’agriculture, de l'élevage, des eaux et forêts et de la recherche".</p>
      <p n="14">(3) This new authority is capable of effectively verifying the application of the rules in force.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) The DQAAV has provided official assurances on compliance with the standards for health controls and monitoring of fishery and aquaculture products as set out in Directive 91/493/EEC and on the fulfilment of hygienic requirements equivalent to those laid down in that Directive.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) Decision 2003/760/EC should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">Decision 2003/760/EC is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="21">1. Article 1 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="22">"Article 1</p>
      <p n="23">The "Département de la qualité alimentaire et de l’action vétérinaire (DQAAV) du Ministère de la promotion des ressources naturelles, chargé de la perliculture, de la pêche, de l’aquaculture, de l’agriculture, de l'élevage, des eaux et forêts et de la recherche" shall be the competent authority in French Polynesia for verifying and certifying compliance of fishery and aquaculture products with the requirements of Directive 91/493/EEC."</p>
      <p n="24">2. Annex I is replaced by the Annex to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="25">Article 2</p>
      <p n="26">This Decision shall apply from 10 April 2005.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 3</p>
      <p n="28">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="29">Done at Brussels, 18 February 2005.</p>
      <p n="30">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="31">Markos Kyprianou</p>
      <p n="32">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="33">[1] OJ L 268, 24.9.1991, p. 15. Directive as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 806/2003 (OJ L 122, 16.5.2003, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="34">[2] OJ L 273, 24.10.2003, p. 23.</p>
      <p n="35">--------------------------------------------------</p>
      <p n="36">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="37">--------------------------------------------------</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
