<TEI.2 id="jrc21996A0706_01-en" n="21996A0706(01)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21996A0706(01) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>62 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21996A0706(01):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21996A0706(01):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">11</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1804</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2602</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3461</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5765</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21996A0706_01-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">SECOND PROTOCOL TO THE GENERAL AGREEMENT ON THE TRADE IN SERVICES</p>
      <p n="3">MEMBERS OF THE WORLD TRADE ORGANIZATION (hereinafter referred to as the 'WTO`) whose Schedules of Specific Commitments and Lists of Exemptions from Article II of the General Agreement on Trade in Services concerning financial services are annexed to this Protocol (hereinafter referred to as 'Members concerned`),</p>
      <p n="4">HAVING CARRIED out negotiations under the terms of the Ministerial Decision on financial services adopted at Marrakesh on 15 April 1994,</p>
      <p n="5">HAVING REGARD to the Second Annex on financial services, and to the Decision on the application of that Annex adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 30 June 1995,</p>
      <p n="6">AGREE AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="7">1. A schedule of specific commitments and a list of exemptions from Article II concerning financial services annexed to this Protocol relating to a Member shall, upon the entry into force of this Protocol for that Member, replace the financial services sections of the Schedule of Specific Commitments and the List of Article II Exemptions of that Member.</p>
      <p n="8">2. This Protocol shall be open for acceptance, by signature or otherwise, by the Members concerned until 30 June 1996.</p>
      <p n="9">3. This Protocol shall enter into force on the 30th day following the date of its acceptance by all Members concerned. If by 1 July 1996 it has not been accepted by all Members concerned, those Members which have accepted it before that date may, within a period of 30 days thereafter, decide on its entry into force.</p>
      <p n="10">4. This Protocol shall be deposited with the Director-General of the WTO. The Director-General of the WTO shall promptly furnish to each Member of the WTO a certified copy of this Protocol and notifications of acceptances thereof pursuant to paragraph 3.</p>
      <p n="11">5. This Protocol shall be registered in accordance with the provisions of Article 102 of the Charter of the United Nations.</p>
      <p n="12">Done at Geneva this . . . day of [month] one thousand nine hundred and ninety-five, in a single copy in the English, French and Spanish languages, each text being authentic, except as otherwise provided for in respect of the schedules annexed hereto.</p>
      <p n="13">THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITY AND ITS MEMBER STATES</p>
      <p n="14">SCHEDULE OF SPECIFIC COMMITMENTS</p>
      <p n="15">Supplement 1</p>
      <p n="16">Revision</p>
      <p n="17">(This is authentic in English only)</p>
      <p n="18">This text replaces the Financial Services section contained in:</p>
      <p n="19">pages 61 to 77 of document GATS/SC/31,</p>
      <p n="20">pages 24 to 29 of document GATS/SC/7,</p>
      <p n="21">pages 23 to 26 of document GATS/SC/33 and</p>
      <p n="22">pages 30 to 32 of document GATS/SC/82.</p>
      <p n="23">EUROPEAN COMMUNITY AND ITS MEMBER STATES</p>
      <p n="24">SCHEDULE OF SPECIFIC COMMITMENTS</p>
      <p n="25">Modes of supply: (1) Cross-border supply (2) Consumption abroad (3) Commercial presence (4) Presence of natural persons</p>
      <p n="26">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="27">EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES AND THEIR MEMBER STATES</p>
      <p n="28">FINAL LIST OF ARTICLE II (EXEMPTIONS)</p>
      <p n="29">(This is authentic in English only)</p>
      <p n="30">EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES AND THEIR MEMBER STATES</p>
      <p n="31">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="32">DECISION ADOPTING THE SECOND PROTOCOL TO THE GENERAL AGREEMENT ON TRADE IN SERVICES</p>
      <p n="33">Adopted by the Committee on Trade in Financial Services on 21 July 1995</p>
      <p n="34">THE COMMITTEE ON TRADE IN FINANCIAL SERVICES,</p>
      <p n="35">HAVING REGARD to the results of the negotiations conducted under the terms of the Decision on financial services adopted at Marrakesh on 15 April 1994,</p>
      <p n="36">HAVING REGARD to the Second Annex on financial services, and to the Decision on the application of that Annex adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 30 June 1995,</p>
      <p n="37">DECIDES AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="38">1. To adopt the text of the Second Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services.</p>
      <p n="39">2. Commencing immediately and continuing until the date of entry into force of the Second Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services, Members concerned shall, to the fullest extent consistent with their existing legislation, not take measures which would be inconsistent with their undertakings resulting from these negotiations.</p>
      <p n="40">3. The Committee on Trade in Financial Services shall monitor the acceptance of the Protocol by Members concerned and shall, at the request of a Member, examine any concerns raised regarding the application of paragraph 2.</p>
      <p n="41">DECISION ON COMMITMENTS IN FINANCIAL SERVICES</p>
      <p n="42">Adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 21 July 1995</p>
      <p n="43">THE COUNCIL FOR TRADE IN SERVICES,</p>
      <p n="44">HAVING REGARD to the Second Annex on financial services, and the Second Services adopted by the Council for Trade in Services,</p>
      <p n="45">HAVING REGARD to the Decision on the Application of the Second Annex on financial services adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 30 June 1995,</p>
      <p n="46">NOTING the results of the negotiations carried out under the terms of the Decision on financial services adopted at Marrakesh on 15 April 1994,</p>
      <p n="47">DECIDES AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="48">1. If the Second Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services (GATS) does not enter into force in accordance with paragraph 3 therein:</p>
      <p n="49">(a) Notwithstanding Article XXI of the GATS, a Member may during a period of 60 days beginning on 1 August 1996, modify or withdraw all or part of the specific commitments on financial services inscribed in its schedule.</p>
      <p n="50">(b) Notwithstanding Article II of the GATS and paragraphs 1 and 2 of the Annex on Article II exemptions, a Member may, during the period referred to in point (a), list in that Annex measures relating to financial services which are inconsistent with paragraph 1 of Article II of the GATS.</p>
      <p n="51">2. The Committee on Trade in Financial Services shall establish any procedures for the implementation of paragraph 1.</p>
      <p n="52">SECOND DECISION ON FINANCIAL SERVICES</p>
      <p n="53">Adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 21 July 1995</p>
      <p n="54">THE COUNCIL FOR TRADE IN SERVICES,</p>
      <p n="55">HAVING REGARD to the Second Annex on financial services,</p>
      <p n="56">NOTING the results of the negotiations carried out under the terms of the Decision on financial services adopted at Marrakesh on 15 April 1994,</p>
      <p n="57">HAVING REGARD to the Decision on the application of the Second Annex on financial services adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 30 June 1995,</p>
      <p n="58">DECIDES AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="59">1. Notwithstanding Article XXI of the General Agreement on Trade in Services (GATS), a Member may during a period of 60 days beginning on 1 November 1997, modify or withdraw all or part of the specific commitments on financial services inscribed in its schedule.</p>
      <p n="60">2. Notwithstanding Article II of the GATS and paragraphs 1 and 2 of the Annex on Article II exemptions, a Member may, during the same period referred to in paragraph 1, list in that Annex measures relating to financial services which are inconsistent with paragraph 1 of Article II of the GATS.</p>
      <p n="61">3. The Committee on Trade in Financial Services shall oversee any negotiations that may take place prior to the date specified in paragraph 1. It shall also establish any procedures necessary for the application of paragraphs 1 and 2.</p>
      <p n="62">4. The application of this Decision shall be contingent upon the entry into force of the Second Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
