<TEI.2 id="jrc21996A0706_02-en" n="21996A0706(02)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21996A0706(02) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21996A0706(02):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21996A0706(02):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">11</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1633</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2602</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3461</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5765</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21996A0706_02-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">THIRD PROTOCOL TO THE GENERAL AGREEMENT ON TRADE IN SERVICES</p>
      <p n="3">MEMBERS OF THE WORLD TRADE ORGANIZATION whose schedules of specific commitments to the General Agreement on Trade in Services relating to movement of natural persons are annexed to this Protocol,</p>
      <p n="4">HAVING CARRIED out negotiations under the terms of the Ministerial Decision on negotiations on movement of natural persons adopted at Marrakech on 15 April 1994,</p>
      <p n="5">HAVING REGARD to the results of such negotiations,</p>
      <p n="6">HAVING REGARD to the Decision on the movement of natural persons adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 30 June 1995,</p>
      <p n="7">AGREE AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="8">1. The commitments on movement of natural persons annexed to this Protocol relating to a Member shall, upon the entry into force of this Protocol for that Member, replace or supplement the relevant entries on movement of natural persons in the schedule of specific commitments of that Member.</p>
      <p n="9">2. This Protocol shall be open for acceptance, by signature or otherwise, by Members concerned until 30 June 1996.</p>
      <p n="10">3. This Protocol shall enter into force on the 30th day after 1 January 1996 for those Members which have accepted it by that date, and for those accepting it after that date, which date shall not be beyond 30 June 1996, it shall enter into force on the 30th day following the date of each acceptance. If a Member whose schedule is annexed to this Protocol does not accept it by that date, the matter shall be referred to the Council for Trade in Services for consideration and appropriate action.</p>
      <p n="11">4. This Protocol shall be deposited with the Director-General of the World Trade Organization. The Director-General shall promptly furnish to each Member a certified copy of this Protocol and notifications of acceptances thereof pursuant to paragraph 3.</p>
      <p n="12">5. This Protocol shall be registered in accordance with the provisions of Article 102 of the Charter of the United Nations.</p>
      <p n="13">Done at Geneva this . . . day of [month] one thousand nine hundred and ninety-five, in a single copy in the English, French and Spanish languages, each text being authentic, except as otherwise provided for in respect of the schedules annexed hereto.</p>
      <p n="14">EUROPEAN COMMUNITY AND ITS MEMBER STATES</p>
      <p n="15">SCHEDULE OF SPECIFIC COMMITMENTS</p>
      <p n="16">Supplement 2</p>
      <p n="17">(This is authentic in English only)</p>
      <p n="18">This text supplements the entries relating to the movement of natural persons section contained on pages 7 to 11 document GATS/SC/31.</p>
      <p n="19">EUROPEAN COMMUNITY AND ITS MEMBER STATES</p>
      <p n="20">SCHEDULE OF SPECIFIC COMMITMENTS</p>
      <p n="21">Modes of supply: (1) Cross-border supply (2) Consumption abroad (3) Commercial presence (4) Presence of natural persons</p>
      <p n="22">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="23">DECISION ON MOVEMENT OF NATURAL PERSONS COMMITMENTS</p>
      <p n="24">Adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 21 July 1995</p>
      <p n="25">THE COUNCIL FOR TRADE IN SERVICES,</p>
      <p n="26">HAVING REGARD to the results of the negotiations conducted under the terms of the Decision on movement of natural persons adopted in Marrakesh on 15 April 1994,</p>
      <p n="27">HAVING REGARD to the Decision on the movement of natural persons adopted by the Council for Trade in Services on 30 June 1995,</p>
      <p n="28">DECIDES AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="29">1. To adopt the text of the Third Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services.</p>
      <p n="30">2. Commencing immediately and continuing until the date of entry into force of the Third Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services, Members concerned shall, to the fullest extent consistent with their existing legislation, not take measures which would be inconsistent with their undertakings resulting from these negotiations.</p>
      <p n="31">3. The Council for Trade in Services shall monitor the acceptance of the Protocol by Members concerned and shall, at the request of a Member, examine any concerns raised regarding the application of paragraph 2 above.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
