<TEI.2 id="jrc31996L0064-en" n="31996L0064" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31996L0064 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 96/64/EC of 2 October 1996 adapting to technical progress Council Directive 77/389/EEC on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to motor vehicle towing devices (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>139 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996L0064:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996L0064:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">13</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2897</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4654</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4658</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5070</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5234</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31996L0064-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 96/64/EC of 2 October 1996 adapting to technical progress Council Directive 77/389/EEC on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to motor vehicle towing devices (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE 96/64/EC of 2 October 1996 adapting to technical progress Council Directive 77/389/EEC on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to motor vehicle towing devices (Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 77/389/EEC of 17 May 1977 on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to motor vehicle towing-devices (1), and in particular Article 4 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Directive 77/389/EEC is one of the separate directives of the EC type-approval procedure which has been established by Directive 70/156/EEC (2), as last amended by Directive 96/27/EC (3); whereas, consequently, the provisions laid down in Directive 70/156/EEC relating to vehicle systems, components and separate technical units apply to this Directive;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, in particular, Articles 3 (4) and 4 (3) of Directive 70/156/EEC necessitate that each separate Directive has attached to it an information document incorporating the relevant items of Annex I to that Directive and also a type-approval certificate based on Annex VI thereto in order that type-approval may be computerized;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas these amendments relate only to the administrative provisions contained in the Directive; whereas it is not necessary therefore to invalidate existing approvals to the Directive nor to prevent the registration, sale and entry into service of new vehicles covered by such approvals;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the opinion of the Committee for Adaptation to Technical Progress established by Directive 70/156/EEC,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">1. The Articles of Directive 77/389/EEC are amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="13">- Article 1 reads as follows: '. . . with the exception of vehicles which run on rails and of agricultural and forestry tractors and all mobile machinery.`,</p>
      <p n="14">- in Article 2 'Annex` is replaced by 'Annex II`,</p>
      <p n="15">- in Article 3 'Annex` is replaced by 'Annex II`,</p>
      <p n="16">- in Article 4 'this Annex` is replaced by 'the Annexes`.</p>
      <p n="17">2. The Annex to Directive 77/389/EEC are amended in accordance with the Annex to this Directive.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">With effect from 1 October 1997, Member States:</p>
      <p n="20">- shall no longer grant EC type-approval pursuant to Article 4 (1) of Directive 70/156/EEC, and</p>
      <p n="21">- may refuse national type-approval</p>
      <p n="22">for a new type of vehicle on grounds relating to the towing devices, if it fails to comply with the provisions of Directive 77/389/EEC, as amended by this Directive.</p>
      <p n="23">This Directive will not invalidate any approval previously granted under Directive 77/389/EEC nor prevent extension of such approvals under terms of Directive under which they were originally granted.</p>
      <p n="24">Article 3</p>
      <p n="25">1. Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with this Directive by 1 October 1997. They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="26">When Member States adopt these provisions, these shall contain a reference to this Directive or shall be accompanied by such reference at the occasion of their official publication. The procedure for such reference shall be adopted by the Member States.</p>
      <p n="27">2. Member States shall communicate to the Commission the texts of the main procedure of the national law that they adopt in the field governed by this Directive.</p>
      <p n="28">Article 4</p>
      <p n="29">This Directive shall enter into force on the 20th day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="30">Article 5</p>
      <p n="31">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="32">Done at Brussels, 2 October 1996.</p>
      <p n="33">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="34">Martin BANGEMANN</p>
      <p n="35">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="36">(1) OJ No L 145, 13. 6. 1977, p. 41.</p>
      <p n="37">(2) OJ No L 42, 23. 2. 1970, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="38">(3) OJ No L 169, 8. 7. 1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="39">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="40">AMENDMENTS TO THE ANNEX TO DIRECTIVE 77/389/EEC</p>
      <p n="41">1. A list of Annexes is inserted between the Articles and the Annex to read as follows:</p>
      <p n="42">'LIST OF ANNEXES</p>
      <p n="43">Annex I: Administrative provisions for type-approval</p>
      <p n="44">Appendix 1: Information document</p>
      <p n="45">Appendix 2: Type-approval certificate</p>
      <p n="46">Annex II: Towing-devices`</p>
      <p n="47">2. A new Annex I is inserted to read:</p>
      <p n="48">'ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="49">ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISIONS FOR TYPE-APPROVAL</p>
      <p n="50">1. APPLICATION FOR EC TYPE-APPROVAL OF A VEHICLE TYPE</p>
      <p n="51">1.1. The application for EC type-approval pursuant to Article 3 (4) of Directive 70/156/EEC of a vehicle type with regard to its towing devices shall be submitted by the manufacturer.</p>
      <p n="52">1.2. A model for the information document is given in Appendix 1.</p>
      <p n="53">1.3. The following must be submitted to the technical service responsible for conducting the type-approval tests:</p>
      <p n="54">1.3.1. a vehicle representative of the type to be approved.</p>
      <p n="55">2. GRANTING OF EC TYPE-APPROVAL OF A VEHICLE TYPE</p>
      <p n="56">2.1. If the relevant requirements are satisfied, EC type-approval pursuant to Article 4 (3) and, if applicable, 4 (4) of Directive 70/156/EEC shall be granted.</p>
      <p n="57">2.2. A model for the EC type-approval certificate is given in Appendix 2.</p>
      <p n="58">2.3. An approval number in accordance with Annex VII to Directive 70/156/EEC shall be assigned to each type of vehicle approved. The same Member State shall not assign the same number to another type of vehicle.</p>
      <p n="59">3. MODIFICATIONS OF THE TYPE AND AMENDMENTS TO APPROVALS</p>
      <p n="60">3.1. In the case of modifications of the type approved pursuant to this Directive, the provisions of Article 5 of Directive 70/156/EEC shall apply.</p>
      <p n="61">4. CONFORMITY OF PRODUCTION</p>
      <p n="62">4.1. Measures to ensure the conformity of production shall be taken in accordance with the provisions laid down in Article 10 of Directive 70/156/EEC.`</p>
      <p n="63">3. The following two new Appendices 1 and 2 are inserted:</p>
      <p n="64">'Appendix 1</p>
      <p n="65">&gt;START OF GRAPHIC&gt;</p>
      <p n="66">INFORMATION DOCUMENT No ........</p>
      <p n="67">PURSUANT TO ANNEX I OF COUNCIL DIRECTIVE 70/156/EEC (*) RELATING TO EC TYPE-APPROVAL OF A VEHICLE WITH RESPECT TO THE TOWING-DEVICES</p>
      <p n="68">(Directive 77/389/EEC, as last amended by Directive . . . /. . . )</p>
      <p n="69">The following information, if applicable, must be supplied in triplicate and include a list of contents. Any drawings must be supplied in appropriate scale and in sufficient detail on size A4 or on a folder of A4 format. Photographs, if any, must show sufficient detail.</p>
      <p n="70">If the systems, components or separate technical units have electronic controls, information concerning their performance must be supplied.</p>
      <p n="71">0. GENERAL</p>
      <p n="72">0.1. Make (trade name of manufacturer):</p>
      <p n="73">0.2. Type and general commercial description(s):</p>
      <p n="74">0.3. Means of identification of type, if marked on the vehicle (b):</p>
      <p n="75">0.3.1. Location of that marking:</p>
      <p n="76">0.4. Category of vehicle (c):</p>
      <p n="77">0.5. Name and address of manufacturer:</p>
      <p n="78">0.8. Address(es) of assembly plant(s):</p>
      <p n="79">1. GENERAL CONSTRUCTION CHARACTERISTICS OF THE VEHICLE</p>
      <p n="80">1.1. Photographs and/or drawings of a representative vehicle:</p>
      <p n="81">2. MASSES AND DIMENSIONS (e) (in kg and mm)</p>
      <p n="82">(Refer to drawing where applicable)</p>
      <p n="83">2.8. Technically permissible maximum laden mass stated by the manufacturer (y) (maximum and minimum):</p>
      <p n="84">2.11.5. Vehicle is/is not (1) suitable for towing loads (item 1.2 of Annex II to Directive 77/389/EEC)</p>
      <p n="85">12. MISCELLANEOUS</p>
      <p n="86">12.3. Towing device(s)</p>
      <p n="87">12.3.1. Front: hook/eye/other (1)</p>
      <p n="88">12.3.2. Rear: hook/eye/other/none (1)</p>
      <p n="89">12.3.3. Drawing or photograph of the chassis/area of the vehicle body showing the position, construction and mounting of the towing device(s):</p>
      <p n="90">Date, File</p>
      <p n="91">(*) The item numbers and footnotes used in this Information Document correspond to those set out in Annex I to Directive 70/156/EEC. Items not relevant for the purpose of this Directive are omitted.</p>
      <p n="92">(1) Delete where inapplicable.</p>
      <p n="93">&gt;END OF GRAPHIC&gt;</p>
      <p n="94">Appendix 2</p>
      <p n="95">&gt;START OF GRAPHIC&gt;</p>
      <p n="96">MODEL</p>
      <p n="97">(maximum format: A4 (210 × 297 mm))</p>
      <p n="98">EC TYPE-APPROVAL CERTIFICATE</p>
      <p n="99">Stamp of administration</p>
      <p n="100">Communication concerning the:</p>
      <p n="101">- type-approval (1)</p>
      <p n="102">- extension of type-approval (1)</p>
      <p n="103">- refusal of type-approval (1)</p>
      <p n="104">- withdrawal of type-approval (1)</p>
      <p n="105">of a type of a vechicle/component/separate technical unit (1) with regard to Directive . . . /. . . /EEC, as last amended by Directive . . . /. . . /EC</p>
      <p n="106">Type-approval number:</p>
      <p n="107">Reason for extension:</p>
      <p n="108">SECTION I</p>
      <p n="109">0.1. Make (trade name of manufacturer):</p>
      <p n="110">0.2. Type and general commercial description(s):</p>
      <p n="111">0.3. Means of identification of type if marked on the vehicle/component/separate technical unit (1) (2):</p>
      <p n="112">0.3.1. Location of that marking:</p>
      <p n="113">0.4. Category of vehicle (1) (3):</p>
      <p n="114">0.5. Name and address of manufacturer:</p>
      <p n="115">0.7. In the case of components and separate technical units, location and method of affixing of the EC approval mark:</p>
      <p n="116">0.8. Address(es) of assembly plant(s):</p>
      <p n="117">SECTION II</p>
      <p n="118">1. Additional information (where applicable): see Addendum</p>
      <p n="119">2. Technical service responsible for carrying out the tests:</p>
      <p n="120">3. Date of test report:</p>
      <p n="121">4. Number of test report:</p>
      <p n="122">5. Remarks (if any): see Addendum</p>
      <p n="123">6. Place:</p>
      <p n="124">7. Date:</p>
      <p n="125">8. Signature:</p>
      <p n="126">9. The index to the information package lodged with the approval authority, which may be obtained on request, is attached.</p>
      <p n="127">(1) Delete where not applicable.</p>
      <p n="128">(2) If the means of identification of type contains characters not relevant to describe the vehicle, component or separate technical unit types covered by this type-approval certificate such characters shall be represented in the documentation by the symbol: "?" (e. g. ABC??123??).</p>
      <p n="129">(3) As defined in Annex II A to Directive 70/156/EEC.</p>
      <p n="130">Addendum to EC type-approval certificate No ........</p>
      <p n="131">concerning the type-approval of a vehicle with regard to Directive 77/389/EEC, as last amended by Directive . . . /. . . /EC</p>
      <p n="132">1. Additional information</p>
      <p n="133">1.1. Location:</p>
      <p n="134">1.2. Method of attachment:</p>
      <p n="135">5. Remarks:</p>
      <p n="136">&gt;END OF GRAPHIC&gt;</p>
      <p n="137">`</p>
      <p n="138">4. The present Annex becomes Annex II.</p>
      <p n="139">In Section 1.2 'Annex I` is replaced by 'Annex II A`.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
