<TEI.2 id="jrc31996R0983-en" n="31996R0983" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31996R0983 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 983/96 of 31 May 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 738/94 laying down certain rules for the implementation of Council Regulation (EC) No 520/94 establishing a Community procedure for administering quantitative quotas</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>174 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R0983:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R0983:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1154</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1642</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1644</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2450</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3591</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">616</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31996R0983-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 983/96 of 31 May 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 738/94 laying down certain rules for the implementation of Council Regulation (EC) No 520/94 establishing a Community procedure for administering quantitative quotas</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 983/96 of 31 May 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 738/94 laying down certain rules for the implementation of Council Regulation (EC) No 520/94 establishing a Community procedure for administering quantitative quotas</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 520/94 of 7 March 1994 establishing a Community procedure for administering quantitative quotas (1), as amended by Regulation (EC) No 138/96 (2), and in particular Article 24 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas in Regulation (EC) No 738/94 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1150/95 (4), the Commission laid down certain general rules for applying Regulation (EC) No 520/94 to any Community quantitative quota, with the exception of those listed in Article 1 (2) of Regulation;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 3 of Regulation (EC) No 738/94, concerning applications for licences, requires that the applicant undertake to return the licence to the competent authority in the event that all or part of it is unused;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Article 1 (2) of Regulation (EC) No 138/96 provides for all licences, used or unused, to be returned to the competent authority; whereas Article 3 of Regulation (EC) No 738/94 should therefore be amended to widen the scope of the undertaking to include the return of used licences;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the telephone numbers of certain national competent authorities should be updated;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Committee set up by Article 22 of Regulation (EC) No 520/94 to administer the quotas,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">Article 3 (2) (g) of Regulation (EC) No 738/94 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="14">'(g) a statement by the applicant that the information given in the application is correct, that the applicant is established in the European Community, that the application is the only one made for the quota in question, and that the applicant undertakes to return the licence whether or not it is used, worded as follows:</p>
      <p n="15">"El abajo firmante certifica que los datos incluidos en la presente solicitud son exactos y han sido declarados de buena fe, que está establecido en la Comunidad Europea y que la presente solicitud constituye la única solicitud presentada por él o en su nombre y relativa al contingente aplicable a las mercancías descritas en esta solicitud.</p>
      <p n="16">El abajo firmante se compromete a restituir la licencia a la autoridad competente de expedición a más tardar dentro de los diez días laborables siguientes a su fecha de expiración."</p>
      <p n="17">»Undertegnede bekræfter hermed, at oplysningerne i denne ansøgning er korrekte og afgivet i god tro, at jeg er etableret i Det Europæiske Fællesskab, og at denne ansøgning er den eneste, der er indgivet af mig eller i mit navn vedrørende kontingentet for de i denne ansøgning beskrevne varer.</p>
      <p n="18">Jeg forpligter mig til at returnere tilladelsen til den kompetente myndighed, der har udstedt den, senest ti arbejdsdage efter udløbsdatoen.«</p>
      <p n="19">'Ich, der Unterzeichnete, bescheinige hiermit, daß die Angaben in diesem Antrag richtig sind und in gutem Glauben gemacht wurden, daß ich in der Europäischen Gemeinschaft ansässig bin, daß es sich bei diesem Antrag um den einzigen Antrag handelt, der von mir oder in meinem Namen in bezug auf das Kontingent für die in diesem Antrag beschriebenen Waren abgegeben wurde.</p>
      <p n="20">Ich verpflichte mich, die Genehmigung der zuständigen ausstellenden Behörden spätestens binnen zehn Arbeitstagen nach Ablauf der Genehmigung zurückzugeben.'</p>
      <p n="21">"Ï õðïãñÜöùí ðéóôïðïéþ üôé ïé ðëçñïöïñßåò ðïõ áíáãñÜöïíôáé óôçí ðáñïýóá áßôçóç åßíáé áêñéâåßò êáé êáôá÷ùñßæïíôáé êáëÞ ôç ðßóôåé, üôé åßíáé åãêáôåóôçìÝíïò óôçí ÅõñùðáúêÞ Êïéíüôçôá, üôé ç ðáñïýóá áßôçóç áðïôåëåß ôç ìïíáäéêÞ áßôçóç ðïõ Ý÷ù õðïâÜëåé Þ Ý÷åé õðïâëçèåß åð' ïíüìáôß ìïõ üóïí áöïñÜ ôçí ðïóüóôùóç ç ïðïßá åöáñìüæåôáé ãéá ôá åìðïñåýìáôá ðïõ ðåñéãñÜöïíôáé óôçí ðáñïýóá áßôçóç.</p>
      <p n="22">ÁíáëáìâÜíù ôçí õðï÷ñÝùóç íá åðéóôñÝøù ôçí Üäåéá óôçí áñìüäéá ãéá ôçí Ýêäïóç áñ÷Þ ôï áñãüôåñï åíôüò äÝêá åñãÜóéìùí çìåñþí ìåôÜ ôçí çìåñïìçíßá ëÞîçò ôçò."</p>
      <p n="23">"I, the undersigned, declare that the information given in this application is correct and is given in good faith, that I am established in the European Community, and that this application is the only one made by me or on my behalf for the quota relating to the goods described in the application.</p>
      <p n="24">I undertake to return the licence to the competent issuing authority within 10 working days of its expiry."</p>
      <p n="25">"Je soussigné certifie que les renseignements portés sur la présente demande sont exacts et établis de bonne foi, que je suis établi dans la Communauté européenne, que la présente demande constitue l'unique demande déposée par moi-même ou en mon nom et relative au contingent applicable aux marchandises décrites dans cette demande.</p>
      <p n="26">Je m'engage à restituer la licence à l'autorité compétente de délivrance au plus tard dans les dix jours ouvrables suivant sa date d'expiration."</p>
      <p n="27">"Io sottoscritto certifico che le informazioni figuranti sulla presente domanda sono esatte e fornite in buona fede, che sono stabilito nella comunità europea e che la presente domanda è l'unica presentata da me o a mio nome relativamente al contingente applicabile alle merci descritte nella presente domanda.</p>
      <p n="28">Mi impegno a restituire la licenza all'autorità competente per il rilascio entro dieci giorni lavorativi successivi alla data di scadenza."</p>
      <p n="29">"Ik, ondergetekende, verklaar dat de in deze aanvraag voorkomende gegevens juist zijn en te goeder trouw worden verstrekt, dat ik in de Gemeenschap gevestigd ben en dat deze aanvraag de enige door of namens mij ingediende aanvraag is met betrekking tot het contingent dat op de in de aanvraag omscheven goederen van toepassing is.</p>
      <p n="30">Ik verbind mij ertoe de vergunning binnen tien werkdagen na de uiterste geldigheidsdatum bij de bevoegde instantie van afgifte in te leveren."</p>
      <p n="31">"Eu, abaixo assinado, certifico que as informações transmitidas no presente pedido são exactas e estabelecidas de boa-fé; que estou estabelecido na Comunidade Europeia; que o presente pedido constitui o único pedido por mim apresentado ou em meu nome relativo ao contingente aplicável às mercadorias descritas nesse pedido.</p>
      <p n="32">Comprometo-me a restituir a licença à autoridade responsável pela sua emissão o mais tardar dez dias úteis após a sua data de caducidade."</p>
      <p n="33">`Minä allekirjoittanut todistan, että tässä hakemuksessa ilmoitetut tiedot ovat oikeita ja vilpittömässä mielessä annettuja ja että olen sijoittautunut Euroopan yhteisöön ja että tämä hakemus on ainoa minun jättämäni tai minun nimissäni jätetty hakemus, joka koskee tässä hakemuksessa kuvattuihin tavaroihin sovellettavaa kiintiötä.</p>
      <p n="34">Sitoudun palauttamaan lisenssin sen myöntäneelle toimivaltaiselle viranomaiselle 10 työpäivän kuluessa sen voimassaolon päättymispäivästä.`</p>
      <p n="35">`Undertecknad intygar att upplysningarna i denna ansökan är korrekta och avgivna i god tro, att jag är etablerad i Europeiska gemenskapen och att detta är den enda ansökan som gjorts av mig eller i mitt namn avseende den kvot som är tillämplig på de varor som beskrivs i denna ansökan.</p>
      <p n="36">Jag åtar mig att återlämna licensen till den behöriga myndighet som har utställt den senast tio arbetsdagar efter det att den löpt ut.`</p>
      <p n="37">followed by the date and the applicant's signature and name printed in capital letters.`</p>
      <p n="38">Article 2</p>
      <p n="39">In Article 13 of Regulation (EC) No 738/94, the words 'unused or partly-used` are deleted.</p>
      <p n="40">Article 3</p>
      <p n="41">Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 1150/95 is replaced by the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="42">Article 4</p>
      <p n="43">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="44">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="45">Done at Brussels, 31 May 1996.</p>
      <p n="46">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="47">Leon BRITTAN</p>
      <p n="48">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="49">(1) OJ No L 66, 10. 3. 1994, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="50">(2) OJ No L 21, 27. 1. 1996, p. 6.</p>
      <p n="51">(3) OJ No L 87, 31. 3. 1994, p. 47.</p>
      <p n="52">(4) OJ No L 116, 23. 5. 1995, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="53">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="54">'ANEXO I - ANNEXE I - ANNEX I - ANHANG I - ALLEGATO I - ÐÁÑÁÑÔÇÌÁ É - ANEXO I - BIJLAGE I - BILAG I - LIITE I - BILAGA I</p>
      <p n="55">Lista de las autoridades nacionales competentes</p>
      <p n="56">Liste des autorités nationales compétentes</p>
      <p n="57">List of the national competent authorities</p>
      <p n="58">Liste der zuständigen Behörden der Mitgliedstaaten</p>
      <p n="59">Elenco delle competenti autorità nazionali</p>
      <p n="60">Ðßíáêáò ôùí áñìüäéùí åèíéêþí áñ÷þí</p>
      <p n="61">Lista das autoridades nacionais competentes</p>
      <p n="62">Lijst van bevoegde nationale instanties</p>
      <p n="63">Liste over kompetente nationale myndigheder</p>
      <p n="64">Luettelo kansallisista toimivaltaisista viranomaisista</p>
      <p n="65">Lista över nationella kompetenta myndigheter</p>
      <p n="66">1. Belgique/België</p>
      <p n="67">Ministère des affaires économiques/Ministerie van Economische Zaken</p>
      <p n="68">Administration des relations économiques, 4e division - Mise en oeuvre des politiques commerciales/Bestuur van de Economische Betrekkingen, 4e afdeling - Toepassing van de Handelspolitiek</p>
      <p n="69">Service "Licences"/Dienst Vergunningen</p>
      <p n="70">rue Général Léman/Generaal Lemanstraat 60</p>
      <p n="71">B-1040 Bruxelles/Brussel</p>
      <p n="72">Tél.: (32 2) 230 90 43</p>
      <p n="73">Fax: (32 2) 230 83 22-231 14 84</p>
      <p n="74">2. Danmark</p>
      <p n="75">Erhvervsfremme Styrelsen</p>
      <p n="76">Søndergade 25</p>
      <p n="77">DK-8600 Silkeborg</p>
      <p n="78">Tlf. (45) 87 20 40 60</p>
      <p n="79">Fax (45) 87 20 40 77</p>
      <p n="80">3. Deutschland</p>
      <p n="81">Bundesamt für Wirtschaft</p>
      <p n="82">Frankfurterstraße 29-31</p>
      <p n="83">D-65760 Eschborn</p>
      <p n="84">Tel.: (49-61-96) 404-0</p>
      <p n="85">Fax: (49-61-96) 40 42 12</p>
      <p n="86">4. ÅëëÜäá</p>
      <p n="87">Õðïõñãåßï ÅèíéêÞò Ïéêïíïìßáò</p>
      <p n="88">ÃåíéêÞ Ãñáììáôåßá Äéåèíþí Ïéêïíïìéêþí Ó÷Ýóåùí</p>
      <p n="89">ÃåíéêÞ Äéåýèõíóç Åîùôåñéêþí Ïéêïíïìéêþí</p>
      <p n="90">êáé Åìðïñéêþí Ó÷Ýóåùí</p>
      <p n="91">Ä/íóç Äéáäéêáóéþí Åîùôåñéêïý Åìðïñßïõ</p>
      <p n="92">ÊïñíÜñïõ 1</p>
      <p n="93">GR-10563 ÁèÞíá</p>
      <p n="94">ôçë: (30-1) 328 60 31, 328 60 32</p>
      <p n="95">ôÝëåöáî: (30-1) 328 60 29, 328 60 59</p>
      <p n="96">5. España</p>
      <p n="97">Ministerio de Economía y Hacienda</p>
      <p n="98">Dirección General de Comercio Exterior</p>
      <p n="99">Paseo de la Castellana n° 162</p>
      <p n="100">E-28071 Madrid</p>
      <p n="101">Tel: (34-1) 349 38 94 - 349 38 78</p>
      <p n="102">Telefax: (34-1) 349 38 32 - 349 38 31</p>
      <p n="103">6. France</p>
      <p n="104">Services des titres du commerce extérieur</p>
      <p n="105">8, rue de la Tour-des-Dames</p>
      <p n="106">F-75436 Paris Cedex 09</p>
      <p n="107">Tél.: (33 1) 44 63 25 25</p>
      <p n="108">Télécopieur: (33 1) 44 63 26 59 - 44 63 26 67</p>
      <p n="109">7. Ireland</p>
      <p n="110">Department of Tourism and Trade</p>
      <p n="111">Licensing Unit</p>
      <p n="112">Kildare Street</p>
      <p n="113">IRL-Dublin 2</p>
      <p n="114">Tel: (353-1) 662 14 44</p>
      <p n="115">Fax: (353-1) 676 61 54</p>
      <p n="116">8. Italia</p>
      <p n="117">Ministero del Commercio con l'estero</p>
      <p n="118">Direzione generale delle importazioni e delle esportazioni</p>
      <p n="119">Viale America 341</p>
      <p n="120">I-00144 Roma</p>
      <p n="121">Tel.: (39-6) 59 931</p>
      <p n="122">Telefax: (39-6) 59 93 26 31 - 59 93 22 35</p>
      <p n="123">Telex: 610083 - 610471 - 614478</p>
      <p n="124">9. Luxembourg</p>
      <p n="125">Ministère des affaires étrangères</p>
      <p n="126">Office des licences</p>
      <p n="127">Boîte postale 113</p>
      <p n="128">L-2011 Luxembourg</p>
      <p n="129">Tél.: (352) 22 61 62</p>
      <p n="130">Télécopieur: (352) 46 61 38</p>
      <p n="131">10. Nederland</p>
      <p n="132">Centrale Dienst voor In- en Uitvoer</p>
      <p n="133">Engelse Kamp 2</p>
      <p n="134">Postbus 30003</p>
      <p n="135">NL-9700 RD Groningen</p>
      <p n="136">Tel. (31-50) 523 91 11</p>
      <p n="137">Fax (31-50) 526 06 98</p>
      <p n="138">11. Österreich</p>
      <p n="139">Bundesministerium für wirtschaftliche Angelegenheiten</p>
      <p n="140">Landstraßer Hauptstraße 55-57</p>
      <p n="141">A-1031 Wien</p>
      <p n="142">Tel.: (43-1) 71 10 23 61</p>
      <p n="143">Fax: (43-1) 715 83 47</p>
      <p n="144">12. Portugal</p>
      <p n="145">Ministério da Economia</p>
      <p n="146">Direcção-Geral do Comércio</p>
      <p n="147">Avenida da República, 79</p>
      <p n="148">P-1000 Lisboa</p>
      <p n="149">Tel.: (351-1) 793 09 93 - 793 30 02</p>
      <p n="150">Telefax: (351-1) 793 22 10 - 796 37 23</p>
      <p n="151">Telex: 13418</p>
      <p n="152">13. Suomi</p>
      <p n="153">Tullihallitus</p>
      <p n="154">PL 512</p>
      <p n="155">FIN-00101 Helsinki</p>
      <p n="156">Puh.: (358-0) 6141</p>
      <p n="157">Telekopio: (358-0) 614 28 52</p>
      <p n="158">14. Sverige</p>
      <p n="159">Kommerskollegium</p>
      <p n="160">Box 1209</p>
      <p n="161">S-111 82 STOCKHOLM</p>
      <p n="162">Tel.: 46 8 791 05 00</p>
      <p n="163">Fax: 46 8 20 03 24</p>
      <p n="164">15. United Kingdom</p>
      <p n="165">Department of Trade and Industry</p>
      <p n="166">Import Licencing Branch</p>
      <p n="167">Queensway House</p>
      <p n="168">West Precinct</p>
      <p n="169">Billingham</p>
      <p n="170">Stockton on Tees</p>
      <p n="171">UK TS23 2NF</p>
      <p n="172">Tel: (44-1642) 36 43 33 - 36 43 34</p>
      <p n="173">Fax: (44-1642) 53 35 57</p>
      <p n="174">Telex: 58608`</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
