<TEI.2 id="jrc31996D0296-en" n="31996D0296" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31996D0296 English</title>
        <title>96/296/EC: Commission Decision of 18 April 1996 amending Decision 92/486/EEC as regards the form of cooperation between the Animo host centre and Member States (Text with EEA relevance)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996D0296:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996D0296:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1445</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1937</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3422</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5358</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">618</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">619</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31996D0296-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">96/296/EC: Commission Decision of 18 April 1996 amending Decision 92/486/EEC as regards the form of cooperation between the Animo host centre and Member States (Text with EEA relevance)</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 18 April 1996 amending Decision 92/486/EEC as regards the form of cooperation between the Animo host centre and Member States (Text with EEA relevance) (96/296/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 90/425/EEC of 26 June 1990 concerning the veterinary and zootechnical checks applicable in intra-Community trade in certain live animals and products with a view to the completion of the internal market (1), as last amended by Directive 92/118/EEC (2), and in particular Article 20 (3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, to enable a detailed study of the various options for the structural development of the Animo network, the current system should be extended for a year, with the possibility of a further extension of one year; whereas, to this end, Commission Decision 92/486/EEC of 25 September 1992 establishing the form of cooperation between the Animo host centre and Member States (3) must be amended; as last amended by the Act of Accession of Austria, Finland and Sweden;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the charges applicable from 1 April 1996 must take account of the number of units linked;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the number of units linked to the network on 1 April 1996 should be used as the basis; whereas in this regard it is necessary to refer to Commission Decision 96/295/EC (4) identifying and fixing the list of Animo units;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The following Article is inserted in Decision 92/486/EEC:</p>
      <p n="13">'Article 2a</p>
      <p n="14">1. The coordination authorities provided for in Article 1 shall ensure that the contracts referred to in that Article:</p>
      <p n="15">- are extended for one year;</p>
      <p n="16">- allow for the possibility of a further extension of one year.</p>
      <p n="17">2. In respect of paragraph 1, the follow charges shall apply:</p>
      <p n="18">ECU 386 per unit (central unit, local unit, frontier inspection post) listed in Decision 96/295/EC (*).</p>
      <p n="19">(*) OJ No L 113, 7. 5. 1996, p. 1.`</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Decision shall enter into force on 1 April 1996.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 3</p>
      <p n="23">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="24">Done at Brussels, 18 April 1996.</p>
      <p n="25">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="27">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="28">(1) OJ No L 224, 18. 8. 1990, p. 29.</p>
      <p n="29">(2) OJ No L 62, 15. 3. 1993, p. 49.</p>
      <p n="30">(3) OJ No L 291, 7. 10. 1992, p. 20.</p>
      <p n="31">(4) See page 1 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
