<TEI.2 id="jrc31996R2238-en" n="31996R2238" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31996R2238 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2238/96 of 22 November 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>35 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R2238:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R2238:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1642</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3408</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3568</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4687</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4743</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5435</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31996R2238-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2238/96 of 22 November 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 2238/96 of 22 November 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2777/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common organization of the market in poultrymeat (1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 2916/95 (2), and in particular Article 3 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 (3) as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1158/96 (4), lays down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licenses in the poultrymeat sector;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas experience has shown that it is necessary, in order to avoid speculative applications, to reduce the period of validity of licences for product category 6 and for particular destinations and to limit for exports under these licences the period referred to in Article 28 of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3665/87 of 27 November 1987 laying down common detailed rules for the application of the system of export refunds on agricultural products (5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1384/95 (6);</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Poultrymeat and Eggs,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="12">1. In Article 2, the following paragraph 5 is added:</p>
      <p n="13">'5. By way of derogation from paragraph 1, licences for category 6 (a) referred to in Annex I shall be valid 15 days from the actual date of issue within the meaning of Article 21 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 3719/88. In this case, notwithstanding Article 28 (5) of Regulation (EEC) No 3665/87, the period during which the products may remain covered by the arrangements provided for in Article 5 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 565/80 (*) shall be equal to the remainder of the term of validity of the export licence.</p>
      <p n="14">(*) OJ No L 62, 7. 3. 1980, p. 5.`</p>
      <p n="15">2. Annex I is replaced by Annex I to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="16">3. Annex II of this Regulation is added as Annex IV.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 22 November 1996.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="23">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ No L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 77.</p>
      <p n="25">(2) OJ No L 305, 19. 12. 1995, p. 49.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) OJ No L 133, 17. 6. 1995, p. 26.</p>
      <p n="27">(4) OJ No L 153, 27. 6. 1996, p. 25.</p>
      <p n="28">(5) OJ No L 351, 14. 12. 1987, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="29">(6) OJ No L 134, 20. 6. 1995, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="30">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="31">'ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="32">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="34">'ANNEX IV</p>
      <p n="35">Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Georgia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgystan, Moldova, Latvia, Russia, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, Ukraine, Lithuania, Estonia.`</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
