<TEI.2 id="jrc31996R2370-en" n="31996R2370" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31996R2370 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2370/96 of 12 December 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>74 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R2370:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R2370:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1642</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2247</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2300</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3408</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4687</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4743</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31996R2370-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2370/96 of 12 December 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 2370/96 of 12 December 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 laying down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2777/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common organization of the market in poultrymeat (1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 2916/95 (2), and in particular Article 3 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2238/96 (4), lays down detailed rules for implementing the system of export licences in the poultrymeat sector;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, in order to avoid speculative applications, the period of validity of licences for product category 6 was reduced for particular destinations by Regulation (EC) No 2238/96; whereas it is also necessary, in order to achieve the said objectives, to make the destination for products of category 6 compulsory;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Poultrymeat and Eggs,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">In Article 2 of Regulation (EC) No 1372/95 the following paragraphs 6 and 7 are added:</p>
      <p n="12">'6. In the case of licences for products of category 6 (a) referred to in Annex I it is obligatory to export to the country of destination indicated in case 7 or to any country referred to in Annex IV.</p>
      <p n="13">To this end, licence applications and licences shall contain at least one of the following</p>
      <p n="14">- in section 20:</p>
      <p n="15">- Categoría 6 a)</p>
      <p n="16">- Kategori 6a)</p>
      <p n="17">- Kategorie 6a</p>
      <p n="18">- Êáôçãïñßá 6 á)</p>
      <p n="19">- Category 6 (a)</p>
      <p n="20">- Catégorie 6a)</p>
      <p n="21">- Categoria 6a)</p>
      <p n="22">- Categorie 6a)</p>
      <p n="23">- Categoria 6a)</p>
      <p n="24">- Tuoteluokka 6a)</p>
      <p n="25">- Kategori 6a),</p>
      <p n="26">- in section 22:</p>
      <p n="27">- Exportación obligatoria a los países mencionados en el Anexo IV del Reglamento (CE) n° 1372/95</p>
      <p n="28">- Udførsel obligatorisk til lande, der er anført i bilag IV til forordning (EF) nr. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="29">- Ausfuhr nach den in Anhang IV der Verordnung (EG) Nr. 1372/95 genannten Länder ist verbindlich</p>
      <p n="30">- Õðï÷ñåùôéêÞ åîáãùãÞ óå ÷þñåò ðïõ áíáöÝñïíôáé óôï ðáñÜñôçìá IV ôïõ êáíïíéóìïý (ÅÊ) áñéè. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="31">- Export obligatory to countries referred to in Annex IV to Regulation (EC) No 1372/95</p>
      <p n="32">- Exportation obligatoire vers les pays visés à l'annexe IV du règlement (CE) n° 1372/95</p>
      <p n="33">- Esportazione obbligatoria verso paesi elencati nell'allegato IV del regolamento (CE) n. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="34">- Verplichte uitvoer naar landen die zijn vermeld in bijlage IV bij Verordening (EG) nr. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="35">- Exportação obrigatória para países referidos no anexo IV do Regulamento (CE) nº 1372/95</p>
      <p n="36">- Velvoittaa viemään asetuksen (EY) N:o 1372/95 liitteessä IV tarkoitettuihin maihin</p>
      <p n="37">- Export obligatorisk till länderna i bilaga IV till förordning (EG) nr 1372/95.</p>
      <p n="38">7. In the case of licences for products of category 6 (b) referred to in Annex I it is obligatory to export to the country of destination indicated in case 7 or to any other country not referred to in Annex IV.</p>
      <p n="39">To this end, licence applications and licences shall contain at least one of the following</p>
      <p n="40">- in section 20:</p>
      <p n="41">- Categoría 6 b)</p>
      <p n="42">- Kategori 6b)</p>
      <p n="43">- Kategorie 6b</p>
      <p n="44">- Êáôçãïñßá 6 â)</p>
      <p n="45">- Category 6 (b)</p>
      <p n="46">- Catégorie 6b)</p>
      <p n="47">- Categoria 6b)</p>
      <p n="48">- Categorie 6b)</p>
      <p n="49">- Categoria 6b)</p>
      <p n="50">- Tuoteluokka 6b)</p>
      <p n="51">- Kategori 6b),</p>
      <p n="52">- in section 22:</p>
      <p n="53">- Exportación obligatoria a los países no mencionados en el Anexo IV del Reglamento (CE) n° 1372/95</p>
      <p n="54">- Udførsel obligatorisk til lande, der ikke er anført i bilag IV til forordning (EF) nr. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="55">- Ausfuhr nach einem der nicht in Anhang IV der Verordnung (EG) Nr. 1372/95 genannten Länder ist verbindlich</p>
      <p n="56">- Õðï÷ñåùôéêÞ åîáãùãÞ óå ÷þñåò ðïõ äåí áíáöÝñïíôáé óôï ðáñÜñôçìá IV ôïõ êáíïíéóìïý (ÅÊ) áñéè. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="57">- Export obligatory to countries not referred to in Annex IV to Regulation (EC) No 1372/95</p>
      <p n="58">- Exportation obligatoire vers les pays autres que ceux visés à l'annexe IV du règlement (CE) n° 1372/95</p>
      <p n="59">- Esportazione obbligatoria verso paesi non elencati nell'allegato IV del regolamento (CE) n. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="60">- Verplichte uitvoer naar landen die niet zijn vermeld in bijlage IV bij Verordening (EG) nr. 1372/95</p>
      <p n="61">- Exportação obrigatória para países não referidos no anexo IV do Regulamento (CE) nº 1372/95</p>
      <p n="62">- Velvoittaa viemään muihin kuin asetuksen (EY) N:o 1372/95 liitteessä IV tarkoitettuihin maihin</p>
      <p n="63">- Export obligatorisk till länder som inte anges i bilaga IV till förordning (EG) nr 1372/95.`</p>
      <p n="64">Article 2</p>
      <p n="65">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="66">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="67">Done at Brussels, 12 December 1996.</p>
      <p n="68">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="69">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="70">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="71">(1) OJ No L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 77.</p>
      <p n="72">(2) OJ No L 305, 19. 12. 1995, p. 49.</p>
      <p n="73">(3) OJ No L 133, 17. 6. 1995, p. 26.</p>
      <p n="74">(4) OJ No L 299, 23. 11. 1996, p. 16.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
