<TEI.2 id="jrc31996R0540-en" n="31996R0540" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31996R0540 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 540/96 of 25 March 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 3010/95 totally or partially suspending the customs duties applicable to certain products falling within Chapters 1 to 24 and Chapter 27 of the Combined Nomenclature originating in Malta and Turkey (1995)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>38 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R0540:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31996R0540:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1260</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1774</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2735</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2772</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4350</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4580</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31996R0540-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 540/96 of 25 March 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 3010/95 totally or partially suspending the customs duties applicable to certain products falling within Chapters 1 to 24 and Chapter 27 of the Combined Nomenclature originating in Malta and Turkey (1995)</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC) No 540/96 of 25 March 1996 amending Regulation (EC) No 3010/95 totally or partially suspending the customs duties applicable to certain products falling within Chapters 1 to 24 and Chapter 27 of the Combined Nomenclature originating in Malta and Turkey (1995)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Regulation (EC) No 3010/95 (1) totally or partially suspended the customs duties applicable to certain agricultural goods and to certain petroleum products originating in Turkey and Malta; whereas the validity of that Regulation ended on 31 December 1995;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas existing trade relations should not be interrupted; whereas accordingly it appears appropriate to continue applying the said Regulation;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the tariff advantages granted in this context should at least be equivalent to those accorded by the Community to developing countries under the Generalized System of Preferences;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Customs Union between the European Community and Turkey took effect as from 31 December 1995; whereas, as a result, it is appropriate to amend the Annexes to the aforementioned Regulation,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">Regulation (EC) No 3010/95 shall be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="13">1. in the title, '(1995)` shall be deleted.</p>
      <p n="14">2. Article 1 shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="15">'Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The following are allowed for importation into the Community at the customs rate indicated for each:</p>
      <p n="17">- starting from 1 January 1995, the products of Chapters 1 to 24 of the Combined Nomenclature, originating in Malta and Turkey, as listed in Annexes I and II,</p>
      <p n="18">- from 1 January 1995 to 30 December 1995, the petroleum products of Chapter 27 of the Combined Nomenclature, refined in Turkey, as listed in Annex III.`</p>
      <p n="19">3. the Annexes shall be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="20">(a) in the heading in the last column of Annex I, 'Period 1. 7 to 31. 12. 1995` shall be replaced by 'Starting from 1. 7. 1995`;</p>
      <p n="21">(b) in Annex I, as regards order numbers 16.0500, 15.0510, 16.0520, 16.1070 and 16.2900, the table shall be replaced by the table in Annex I to this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="22">(c) Annex II shall be replaced by the Annex in Annex II to this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="23">(d) Annex III shall be deleted with effect from 31 December 1995.</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="26">It shall apply from 1 January 1995, except for Annex II, which shall apply from 31 December 1995.</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 25 March 1996.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Council</p>
      <p n="30">The President</p>
      <p n="31">S. AGNELLI</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ No L 314, 28. 12. 1995, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="34">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="35">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="36">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="37">'ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="38">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
