<TEI.2 id="jrc31995D0355-en" n="31995D0355" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31995D0355 English</title>
        <title>95/355/Euratom: Commission Decision of 28 June 1995 concerning the conclusion of a memorandum of understanding for cooperation between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada in the field of controlled nuclear fusion, by the Commission for and on behalf of the Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>15 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995D0355:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995D0355:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1123</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1379</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">223</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5100</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5344</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">616</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31995D0355-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">95/355/Euratom: Commission Decision of 28 June 1995 concerning the conclusion of a memorandum of understanding for cooperation between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada in the field of controlled nuclear fusion, by the Commission for and on behalf of the Community</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 28 June 1995 concerning the conclusion of a memorandum of understanding for cooperation between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada in the field of controlled nuclear fusion, by the Commission for and on behalf of the Community (95/355/Euratom)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular Article 101 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Whereas the Council, in its Decision of 20 February 1995 approved the conclusion, by the Commission, of the memorandum of understanding for cooperation between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada in the field of controlled nuclear fusion,</p>
      <p n="6">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="7">Article 1</p>
      <p n="8">The memorandum of understanding for cooperation between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada in the field of controlled nuclear fusion is hereby concluded for and on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="9">The text of memorandum of understanding is appended to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="10">Article 2</p>
      <p n="11">The Member of the Commission responsible for science, research and development or her designated representative is authorized to sign the memorandum of understanding for the purpose of binding the European Atomic Energy Community.</p>
      <p n="12">Done at Brussels, 28 June 1995.</p>
      <p n="13">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="14">Jacques SANTER</p>
      <p n="15">The President</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
