<TEI.2 id="jrc31995R0838-en" n="31995R0838" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31995R0838 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC, Euratom, ECSC) No 838/95 of 10 April 1995 amending Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 laying down the form of the laissez-passer to be issued to members and servants of the institutions</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>220 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R0838:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R0838:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1048</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4031</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4057</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">488</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5251</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5313</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31995R0838-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC, Euratom, ECSC) No 838/95 of 10 April 1995 amending Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 laying down the form of the laissez-passer to be issued to members and servants of the institutions</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC, EURATOM, ECSC) No 838/95 of 10 April 1995 amending Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 laying down the form of the laissez-passer to be issued to members and servants of the institutions</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to Article 7 (1) of the Protocol on the Privileges and Immunities of the European Communities annexed to the Treaty establishing a Single Council and a Single Commission of the European Communities,</p>
      <p n="5">Whereas, pursuant to Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 (1), the laissez-passer issued to members and servants of the institutions are drawn up in nine languages;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas following the enlargement of the European Union, the laissez-passer should be drawn up in eleven languages and the model of the laissez-passer annexed to the said Regulation should therefore be adapted,</p>
      <p n="7">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="8">Article 1</p>
      <p n="9">The Annex to Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1826/69 shall be replaced by the Annex appearing in the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="10">Article 2</p>
      <p n="11">Those laissez-passer whose validity has not yet expired shall remain valid until the issue of a laissez-passer in the form laid down by this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 3</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Luxembourg, 10 April 1995.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Council</p>
      <p n="17">The President</p>
      <p n="18">A. JUPPÉ</p>
      <p n="19">(1) OJ No L 235, 18. 9. 1969, p. 1. Regulation as last amended by Regulation (ECSC, EC, Euratom) No 1303/94 (OJ No L 142, 7. 6. 1994, p. 1).</p>
      <p n="20">ANEXO - BILAG - ANHANG - ÐÁÑÁÑÔÇÌÁ - ANNEX - ANNEXE - ALLEGATO - BIJLAGE - ANEXO - LIITE - BILAGA</p>
      <p n="21">&gt;START OF GRAPHIC&gt;</p>
      <p n="22">UNIÓN EUROPEA</p>
      <p n="23">DEN EUROPÆISKE UNION</p>
      <p n="24">EUROPÄISCHE UNION</p>
      <p n="25">ÅÕÑÙÐÁÚÊÇ ÅÍÙÓÇ</p>
      <p n="26">EUROPEAN UNION</p>
      <p n="27">UNION EUROPÉENNE</p>
      <p n="28">UNIONE EUROPEA</p>
      <p n="29">EUROPESE UNIE</p>
      <p n="30">UNIÃO EUROPEIA</p>
      <p n="31">EUROOPAN UNIONI</p>
      <p n="32">EUROPEISKA UNIONEN</p>
      <p n="33">SALVOCONDUCTO</p>
      <p n="34">PASSÉRSEDDEL</p>
      <p n="35">AUSWEIS</p>
      <p n="36">ÁÄÅÉÁ ÄÉÅËÅÕÓÅÙÓ</p>
      <p n="37">LAISSEZ-PASSER</p>
      <p n="38">LAISSEZ-PASSER</p>
      <p n="39">LASCIAPASSARE</p>
      <p n="40">LAISSEZ-PASSER</p>
      <p n="41">LIVRE-TRÂNSITO</p>
      <p n="42">KULKULUPA</p>
      <p n="43">PASSERSEDEL</p>
      <p n="44">El salvoconducto contiene 22 páginas</p>
      <p n="45">Passérsedlen omfatter 22 sider</p>
      <p n="46">Der Ausweis enthält 22 Seiten</p>
      <p n="47">Ç Üäåéá äéåëåýóåùò ðåñéëáìâÜíåé 22 óåëßäåò</p>
      <p n="48">The laissez-passer contains 22 pages</p>
      <p n="49">Le laissez-passer contient 22 pages</p>
      <p n="50">Il lasciapassare è composto di 22 pagine</p>
      <p n="51">Het laissez-passer bevat 22 bladzijden</p>
      <p n="52">O livre-trânsito é composto por 22 páginas</p>
      <p n="53">Tämä kulkulupa sisältää 22 sivua</p>
      <p n="54">Passersedeln innehåller 22 sidor</p>
      <p n="55">El presente salvoconducto se expide en virtud de las disposiciones del apartado 1 del artículo 7 del Protocolo sobre los privilegios y las inmunidades de las Comunidades Europeas anejo al Tratado por el que se constituye un Consejo único y una Comisión única de las Comunidades Europeas.</p>
      <p n="56">El titular de este salvoconducto goza de los privilegios e inmunidades previstos en este Protocolo.</p>
      <p n="57">Denne passérseddel er udstedt i medfør af bestemmelserne i artikel 7, stk. 1, i protokollen vedrørende De Europæiske Fællesskabers privilegier og immuniteter, der er knyttet til traktaten om oprettelse af et fælles Råd og en fælles Kommission for De Europæiske Fællesskaber som bilag.</p>
      <p n="58">Indehaveren af denne passérseddel nyder de i denne protokol fastsatte privilegier og immuniteter.</p>
      <p n="59">Dieser Ausweis ist ausgestellt aufgrund des Artikels 7 Absatz 1 des dem Vertrag zur Einsetzung eines gemeinsamen Rates und einer gemeinsamen Kommission der Europäischen Gemeinschaften beigefügten Protokolls über die Vorrechte und Befreiungen der Europäischen Gemeinschaften.</p>
      <p n="60">Der Inhaber dieses Ausweises genießt die in diesem Protokoll vorgesehenen Vorrechte und Befreiungen.</p>
      <p n="61">Ç ðáñïýóá Üäåéá äéåëåýóåùò åêäßäåôáé äõíÜìåé ôùí äéáôÜîåùí ôïõ Üñèñïõ 7 ðáñÜãñáöïò 1 ôïõ ðñùôïêüëëïõ ðåñß ôùí ðñïíïìßùí êáé áóõëéþí ôùí Åõñùðáúêþí ÊïéíïôÞôùí êáé åðéóõíÜðôåôáé óôç óõíèÞêç ðåñß éäñýóåùò åíéáßïõ Óõìâïõëßïõ êáé åíéáßáò ÅðéôñïðÞò ôùí Åõñùðáúêþí ÊïéíïôÞôùí.</p>
      <p n="62">Ï äéêáéïý÷ïò ôçò ðáñïýóáò Üäåéáò äéåëåýóåùò áðïëáýåé ôùí ðñïíïìßùí êáé áóõëéþí ðïõ ðñïâëÝðïíôáé óôï åí ëüãù ðñùôüêïëëï.</p>
      <p n="63">This laissez-passer is issued pursuant to Article 7 (1) of the Protocol on the Privileges and Immunities of the European Communities annexed to the Treaty establishing a Single Council and a Single Commission of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="64">The bearer of this laissez-passer shall enjoy the privileges and immunities provided for in that Protocol.</p>
      <p n="65">Le présent laissez-passer est délivré en vertu des dispositions de l'article 7 paragraphe 1 du protocole sur les privilèges et immunités des Communautés européennes annexé au traité instituant un Conseil unique et une Commission unique des Communautés européennes.</p>
      <p n="66">Le titulaire de ce laissez-passer jouit des privilèges et immunités prévus à ce protocole.</p>
      <p n="67">Il presente lasciapassare è rilasciato in virtù delle disposizioni dell'articolo 7, paragrafo 1, del protocollo sui privilegi e sulle immunità delle Comunità europee allegato al trattato che istituisce un Consiglio unico e una Commissione unica delle Comunità europee.</p>
      <p n="68">Il titolare del presente lasciapassare gode dei privilegi e delle immunità previste da tale protocollo.</p>
      <p n="69">Dit laissez-passer is afgegeven krachtens de bepalingen van artikel 7, lid 1, van het Protocol betreffende de voorrechten en immuniteiten van de Europese Gemeenschappen dat aan het Verdrag tot instelling van één Raad en één Commissie van de Europese Gemeenschappen is gehecht.</p>
      <p n="70">De houder van dit laissez-passer geniet de privileges en immuniteiten, voorzien in dit Protocol.</p>
      <p n="71">O presente livre-trânsito é emitido nos termos do disposto no No 1 do artigo 7º do Protocolo relativo aos Privilégios e Imunidades das Comunidades Europeias anexo ao Tratado que institui um Conselho único e uma Comissão única das Comunidades Europeias.</p>
      <p n="72">O titular deste livre-trânsito goza dos privilégios e imunidades previstos nesse protocolo.</p>
      <p n="73">Tämä kulkulupa on myönnetty Euroopan yhteisöjen yhteisen neuvoston ja yhteisen komission perustamisesta tehdyn sopimuksen liitteenä olevan Euroopan yhteisöjen erioikeuksista ja vapauksista tehdyn pöytäkirjan 7 artiklan 1 kohdan määräysten nojalla.</p>
      <p n="74">Kulkuluvan haltijalla on kyseisen pöytäkirjan mukaiset erioikeudet ja vapaudet.</p>
      <p n="75">Denna passersedel är utfärdad i enlighet med artikel 7.1 i protokollet om immunitet och privilegier för Europeiska gemenskaperna, vilket är fogat till Fördraget om upprättande av ett gemensamt råd och en gemensam kommission för Europeiska gemenskaperna.</p>
      <p n="76">Innehavaren av denna passersedel åtnjuter den immunitet och de privilegier som föreskrivs i ovan nämnda protokoll.</p>
      <p n="77">EL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="78">ruega a todas las autoridades de los Estados miembros de la Unión Europea dejen circular libremente al titular del presente salvoconducto y presten ayuda y protección en caso de necesidad.</p>
      <p n="79">FORMANDEN/PRÆSIDENTEN (1)</p>
      <p n="80">anmoder alle myndigheder i Den Europæiske Unions medlemsstater om at lade indehaveren af denne passérseddel rejse uhindret og i påkommende tilfælde at yde ham hjælp og beskyttelse.</p>
      <p n="81">DER PRÄSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="82">bittet alle Behörden der Mitgliedstaaten der Europäischen Union, den Inhaber dieses Ausweises ungehindert reisen zu lassen und ihm erforderlichenfalls in jeder Weise Schutz und Hilfe zu gewähren.</p>
      <p n="83">Ï ÐÑÏÅÄÑÏÓ (1)</p>
      <p n="84">ðáñáêáëåß üëåò ôéò áñ÷Ýò ôùí êñáôþí ìåëþí ôçò ÅõñùðáúêÞò ¸íùóçò íá åðéôñÝðïõí ôçí åëåýèåñç êõêëïöïñßá ôïõ äéêáéïý÷ïõ ôçò ðáñïýóáò Üäåéáò äéåëåýóåùò êáé íá ôïõ ðáñÝ÷ïõí, áí ÷ñåéáóèåß, âïÞèåéá êáé ðñïóôáóßá.</p>
      <p n="85">THE PRESIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="86">requests all authorities of Member States of the European Union to allow the bearer to pass freely and to afford the bearer such assistance and protection as may be necessary.</p>
      <p n="87">LE PRÉSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="88">prie toutes les autorités des États membres de l'Union européenne de laisser circuler librement le titulaire du présent laissez-passer et de lui porter aide et protection en cas de besoin</p>
      <p n="89">IL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="90">prega tutte le autorità degli Stati membri dell'Unione europea di lasciar liberamente circolare il titolare del presente lasciapassare e di prestargli, ove occorra, aiuto e protezione.</p>
      <p n="91">DE VOORZITTER (1)</p>
      <p n="92">verzoekt alle overheden van de Lid-Staten van de Europese Unie de houder van dit laissez-passer vrije doorgang te verlenen en hem zo nodig alle hulp en bijstand te verschaffen.</p>
      <p n="93">O PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="94">pede a todas as autoridades dos Estados-membros das Comunidades Europeias que deixem circular livremente o titular do presente livre-trânsito e que lhe prestem auxílio e protecção, em caso de necessidade. : n (1) PUHEENJOHTAJA</p>
      <p n="95">pyytää kaikkia Euroopan unionin jäsenvaltioiden viranomaisia sallimaan tämän kulkuluvan haltijan liikkua vapaasti sekä antamaan hänelle tarvittaessa apua ja suojelua.</p>
      <p n="96">ORDFÖRANDEN (1)</p>
      <p n="97">ber alla myndigheter i Europeiska unionens medlemsstater att tillåta innehavaren av denna passersedel att resa obehindrat, samt att ge denne hjälp och skydd vid behov.</p>
      <p n="98">(1) Indicación de la institución de que se trate. Angivelse af den pågældende institution. Angabe der betreffenden Institution. Ïíïìáóßá ôïõ ïñãÜíïõ. Name of institution concerned. Indication de l'institution concernée. Indicazione dell'istituzione di cui si tratta. Aanduiding van de betrokken Instelling. Indicação da instituição em causa. Toimielin. Ange institutionen i fråga.</p>
      <p n="99">Apellidos y nombre / Navn og fornavn / Name und Vorname / Ïíïìáôåðþíõìï / Name and forenames / Nom et prénoms / Cognome e nome / Naam en voornamen / Apelido e nome próprio / Sukunimi ja etunimet / Efternamn och förnamn: Fecha de nacimiento / Født den / Geboren am / Çìåñïìçíßá ãåííÞóåùò / Date of birth / Né le / Nato il / Geboren op / Nascido em / Syntymäaika / Född den: en / i / in / åéò / in / à / a / te / em/Syntymäpaikka/i:</p>
      <p n="100">Nacionalidad / Nationalitet / Staatsangehörigkeit / Õðçêïüôçôá / Nationality / Nationalité / Nazionalità / Nationaliteit / Nacionalidade / Kansallisuus / Nationalitet:</p>
      <p n="101">Función / Stilling / Funktion / ÅðÜããåëìá / Position held / Fonction / Funzione / Functie / Função / Virka / Befattning:</p>
      <p n="102">Dirección / Adresse / Adresse / Äéåýèõíóç / Address / Adresse / Indirizzo / Adres / Morada / Osoite / Adress:</p>
      <p n="103">RASGOS PERSONALES / SIGNALEMENT / PERSONENBESCHREIBUNG / ÐÅÑÉÃÑÁÖÇ ÊÁÔÏ×ÏÕ / DESCRIPTION / SIGNALEMENT / CONNOTATI / SIGNALEMENT / DADOS PESSOAIS / TUNTOMERKIT / SIGNALEMENT</p>
      <p n="104">Ojos / Øjne / Augen / Ïöèáëìïß / Eyes / Yeux / Occhi / Ogen / Olhos / Silmät / Ögon:</p>
      <p n="105">Cabello / Hår / Haare / Êüìç / Hair / Cheveux / Capelli / Haren / Cabelos / Hiukset / Hårfärg:</p>
      <p n="106">Talla / Højde / Größe / ÁíÜóôçìá / Height / Taille / Statura / Lengte / Altura / Pituus / Längd:</p>
      <p n="107">Señas particulares / Særlige kendetegn / Besondere Kennzeichen / Éäéáßôåñá ÷áñáêôçñéóôéêÜ / Special peculiarities / Signes particuliers / Segni particolari / Bijzondere kentekenen / Sinais particulares / Erityisiä tuntomerkkejä / Särskilda kännetecken: Firma del titular Fotografía</p>
      <p n="108">Indehaverens underskrift Fotografi</p>
      <p n="109">Unterschrift des Inhabers Lichtbild</p>
      <p n="110">ÕðïãñáöÞ êáôü÷ïõ Öùôïãñáößá</p>
      <p n="111">Usual signature of bearer Photograph</p>
      <p n="112">Signature du titulaire Photographie</p>
      <p n="113">Firma del titolare Fotografia</p>
      <p n="114">Handtekening van de houder Foto</p>
      <p n="115">Assinatura do titular Fotografia</p>
      <p n="116">Haltijan allekirjoitus Valokuva</p>
      <p n="117">Innehavarens namnteckning Foto</p>
      <p n="118">Este salvoconducto es válido para los territorios mencionados en los apartados 1 y 4 del artículo 227 del Tratado constitutivo de la Comunidad Europea así como para el territorio de los Estados terceros con los que la Comunidad haya celebrado acuerdos tal como se define en el párrafo segundo del apartado 1 del artículo 7 del Protocolo sobre los privilegios y las inmunidades de las Comunidades Europeas.</p>
      <p n="119">Denne passérseddel er gyldig i de områder, der er omhandlet i artikel 227, stk. 1 og 4, i traktaten om oprettelse af Det Europæiske Fællesskab, samt i de områder i tredjelande, med hvilke Kommissionen har indgået aftaler efter artikel 7, stk. 1, andet afsnit, i protokollen vedrørende De Europæiske Fællesskabers privilegier og immuniteter.</p>
      <p n="120">Dieser Ausweis gilt für die Hoheitsgebiete, die in Artikel 227 Absätze 1 und 4 des Vertrages zur Gründung der Europäischen Gemeinschaft genannt sind, sowie für das Hoheitsgebiet der dritten Staaten, mit denen die Kommission gemäß Artikel 7 Absatz 1 Unterabsatz 2 des Protokolls über die Vorrechte und Befreiungen der Europäischen Gemeinschaften Abkommen geschlossen hat.</p>
      <p n="121">Ç ðáñïýóá Üäåéá äéåëåýóåùò éó÷ýåé ãéá ôá åäÜöç ðïõ ðñïâëÝðïíôáé óôéò ðáñáãñÜöïõò 1 êáé 4 ôïõ Üñèñïõ 227 ôçò óõíèÞêçò ðåñß éäñýóåùò ôçò ÅõñùðáúêÞò Êïéíüôçôáò, êáèþò êáé ãéá ôá åäÜöç ôùí ôñßôùí ÷ùñþí, ìå ôéò ïðïßåò ç ÅðéôñïðÞ óõíÜðôåé óõìöùíßåò óýìöùíá ìå ôï Üñèñï 7 ðáñÜãñáöïò 1 äåýôåñï åäÜöéï ôïõ ðñùôüêïëëïõ ðåñß ôùí ðñïíïìßùí êáé áóõëéþí ôùí Åõñùðáúêþí ÊïéíïôÞôùí.</p>
      <p n="122">This laissez-passer is valid for the territories referred to in Article 227 (1) and (4) of the Treaty establishing the European Community and for the territory of the third countries with which the Commission has concluded agreements within the meaning of the second subparagraph of Article 7 (1) of the Protocol on the Privileges and Immunities of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="123">Ce laissez-passer est valable pour les territoires visés aux paragraphes 1 et 4 de l'article 227 du traité instituant la Communauté européenne ainsi que pour le territoire des États tiers avec lesquels la Commission aura conclu des accords au sens de l'article 7 paragraphe 1 deuxième alinéa du protocole sur les privilèges et immunités des Communautés européennes.</p>
      <p n="124">Il presente lasciapassare è valido per i territori di cui all'articolo 227, paragrafi 1 e 4, del trattato che istituisce la Comunità europea, nonché per il territorio degli Stati terzi con i quali la Commissione avrà concluso accordi ai sensi dell'articolo 7, paragrafo 1, secondo comma, del protocollo sui privilegi e sulle immunità delle Comunità europee.</p>
      <p n="125">Dit laissez-passer is geldig voor de grondgebieden bedoeld in artikel 227, leden 1 en 4, van het Verdrag tot oprichting van de Europese Gemeenschap alsmede voor het grondgebied van derde Staten waarmede de Commissie akkoorden zal hebben gesloten in de zin van artikel 7, lid 1, tweede alinea, van het Protocol betreffende de voorrechten en immuniteiten van de Europese Gemeenschappen.</p>
      <p n="126">Este livre-trânsito é válido nos territórios referidos nos nºs1 e 4 do artigo 227º do Tratado que institui a Comunidade Europeia, bem como nos territórios de Estados terceiros com que a Comissão tenha celebrado acordos na acepção do nº 1, segundo parágrafo, do artigo 7º do Protocolo relativo aos Privilégios e Imunidades das Comunidades Europeias.</p>
      <p n="127">Kulkulupa on voimassa Euroopan yhteisön perustamissopimuksen 227 artiklan 1 ja 4 kohdassa tarkoitetuilla alueilla sekä sellaisten kolmansien valtioiden alueella, joiden kanssa komissio on tehnyt Euroopan yhteisöjen erioikeuksista ja vapauksista tehdyn pöytäkirjan 7 artiklan 1 kohdan toisessa alakohdassa tarkoitettuja sopimuksia.</p>
      <p n="128">Denna passersedel är giltig inom de territorier som anges i artikel 227.1 och 227.4 i Fördraget om upprättandet av Europeiska gemenskapen samt inom de territorier som tillhör tredje länder med vilka kommissionen har slutit avtal enligt artikel 7.1 andra stycket i protokollet om immunitet och privilegier för Europeiska gemenskaperna.</p>
      <p n="129">Este salvoconducto expira el / Denne passérseddels gyldighed udløber den / Dieser Ausweis wird ungültig am / Ç ðáñïýóá Üäåéá äéåëåýóåùò ëÞãåé ôçí / This laissez-passer expires en / Il expire le / Scade il / De geldigheid van dit laissez-passer eindigt op / Este livre-trânsito é válido até / Kulkuluvan voimassaolo päättyy (ajankohta) / Denna passersedel är giltig till och med: ,</p>
      <p n="130">den/le/il EL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="131">FORMANDEN/PRÆSIDENTEN (1)</p>
      <p n="132">DER PRÄSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="133">Ï ÐÑÏÅÄÑÏÓ (1)</p>
      <p n="134">THE PRESIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="135">LE PRÉSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="136">IL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="137">DE VOORZITTER (1)</p>
      <p n="138">O PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="139">: n (1) PUHEENJOHTAJA ORDFÖRANDEN (1)</p>
      <p n="140">La validez del presente salvoconducto se prorroga</p>
      <p n="141">Denne passérseddels gyldighed forlænges</p>
      <p n="142">Die Gültigkeit dieses Ausweises wird verlängert</p>
      <p n="143">Ç éó÷ýò ôçò ðáñïýóçò áäåßáò äéåëåýóåùò ðáñáôåßíåôáé</p>
      <p n="144">The validity of this laissez-passer is extended</p>
      <p n="145">La validité du présent laissez-passer est prorogée</p>
      <p n="146">La validità del presente lasciapassare è prorogata</p>
      <p n="147">De geldigheidsduur van dit laissez-passer wordt verlengd</p>
      <p n="148">A validade deste livre-trânsito é prorrogada</p>
      <p n="149">Tämän kulkuluvan voimassaoloa pidennetään</p>
      <p n="150">Passersedelns giltighetstid förlängs</p>
      <p n="151">del / fra / vom / áðü ôçí / from / du / dal / van / de / (mistä) / från</p>
      <p n="152">al / til / bis / ìÝ÷ñé ôéò / to / au / al / tot / até / (mihin) / till , den / le / il EL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="153">FORMANDEN/PRÆSIDENTEN (1)</p>
      <p n="154">DER PRÄSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="155">Ï ÐÑÏÅÄÑÏÓ (1)</p>
      <p n="156">THE PRESIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="157">LE PRÉSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="158">IL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="159">DE VOORZITTER (1)</p>
      <p n="160">O PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="161">: n (1) PUHEENJOHTAJA ORDFÖRANDEN (1)</p>
      <p n="162">(1) Indicación de la institución de que se trate. Angivelse af den pågældende institution. Angabe der betreffenden Institution. Ïíïìáóßá ôïõ ïñãÜíïõ. Name of institution concerned. Indication de l'institution concernée. Indicazione dell'istituzione di cui si tratta. Aanduiding van de betrokken Instelling. Indicação da instituição em causa. Toimielin. Ange institutionen i fråga.</p>
      <p n="163">La validez del presente salvoconducto se prorroga</p>
      <p n="164">Denne passérseddels gyldighed forlænges</p>
      <p n="165">Die Gültigkeit dieses Ausweises wird verlängert</p>
      <p n="166">Ç éó÷ýò ôçò ðáñïýóçò áäåßáò äéåëåýóåùò ðáñáôåßíåôáé</p>
      <p n="167">The validity of this laissez-passer is extended</p>
      <p n="168">La validité du présent laissez-passer est prorogée</p>
      <p n="169">La validità del presente lasciapassare è prorogata</p>
      <p n="170">De geldigheidsduur van dit laissez-passer wordt verlengd</p>
      <p n="171">A validade deste livre-trânsito é prorrogada</p>
      <p n="172">Tämän kulkuluvan voimassaoloa pidennetään</p>
      <p n="173">Passersedelns giltighetstid förlängs</p>
      <p n="174">del / fra / vom / áðü ôçí / from / du / dal / van / de / (mistä) / från</p>
      <p n="175">al / til / bis / ìÝ÷ñé ôéò / to / au / al / tot / até / (mihin) / till , den / le / il EL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="176">FORMANDEN/PRÆSIDENTEN (1)</p>
      <p n="177">DER PRÄSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="178">Ï ÐÑÏÅÄÑÏÓ (1)</p>
      <p n="179">THE PRESIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="180">LE PRÉSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="181">IL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="182">DE VOORZITTER (1)</p>
      <p n="183">O PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="184">: n (1) PUHEENJOHTAJA ORDFÖRANDEN (1)</p>
      <p n="185">La validez del presente salvoconducto se prorroga</p>
      <p n="186">Denne passérseddels gyldighed forlænges</p>
      <p n="187">Die Gültigkeit dieses Ausweises wird verlängert</p>
      <p n="188">Ç éó÷ýò ôçò ðáñïýóçò áäåßáò äéåëåýóåùò ðáñáôåßíåôáé</p>
      <p n="189">The validity of this laissez-passer is extended</p>
      <p n="190">La validité du présent laissez-passer est prorogée</p>
      <p n="191">La validità del presente lasciapassare è prorogata</p>
      <p n="192">De geldigheidsduur van dit laissez-passer wordt verlengd</p>
      <p n="193">A validade deste livre-trânsito é prorrogada</p>
      <p n="194">Tämän kulkuluvan voimassaoloa pidennetään</p>
      <p n="195">Passersedelns giltighetstid förlängs</p>
      <p n="196">(1) Indicación de la institución de que se trate. Angivelse af den pågældende institution. Angabe der betreffenden Institution. Ïíïìáóßá ôïõ ïñãÜíïõ. Name of institution concerned. Indication de l'institution concernée. Indicazione dell'istituzione di cui si tratta. Aanduiding van de betrokken Instelling. Indicação da instituição em causa. Toimielin. Ange institutionen i fråga.</p>
      <p n="197">del / fra / vom / áðü ôçí / from / du / dal / van / de / (mistä) / från</p>
      <p n="198">al / til / bis / ìÝ÷ñé ôéò / to / au / al / tot / até / (mihin) / till , den / le / il EL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="199">FORMANDEN/PRÆSIDENTEN (1)</p>
      <p n="200">DER PRÄSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="201">Ï ÐÑÏÅÄÑÏÓ (1)</p>
      <p n="202">THE PRESIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="203">LE PRÉSIDENT (1)</p>
      <p n="204">IL PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="205">DE VOORZITTER (1)</p>
      <p n="206">O PRESIDENTE (1)</p>
      <p n="207">: n (1) PUHEENJOHTAJA ORDFÖRANDEN (1)</p>
      <p n="208">Páginas 7 a 18 inclusive en blanco</p>
      <p n="209">Siderne 7 til og med 18 er blanke</p>
      <p n="210">Seiten 7 bis einschließlich 18: leer</p>
      <p n="211">Óåëßäåò 7 Ýùò êáé 18 ëåõêÝò</p>
      <p n="212">Pages 7 to 18 inclusive blank</p>
      <p n="213">Pages 7 à 18 incluses en blanc</p>
      <p n="214">Pagine da 7 a 18 compresa in bianco</p>
      <p n="215">Bladzijden 7 tot en met 18 blanco</p>
      <p n="216">Páginas 7 a 18 inclusive em branco</p>
      <p n="217">Kulkulupa sisältää tyhjät sivut 7-18</p>
      <p n="218">Sidorna 7 till och med 18 är blanka</p>
      <p n="219">(1) Indicación de la institución de que se trate. Angivelse af den pågældende institution. Angabe der betreffenden Institution. Ïíïìáóßá ôïõ ïñãÜíïõ. Name of institution concerned. Indication de l'institution concernée. Indicazione dell'istituzione di cui si tratta. Aanduiding van de betrokken Instelling. Indicação da instituição em causa. Toimielin. Ange institutionen i fråga.</p>
      <p n="220">&gt;END OF GRAPHIC&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
