<TEI.2 id="jrc31995E0413-en" n="31995E0413" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31995E0413 English</title>
        <title>95/413/CFSP: Common Position of 2 October 1995 defined by the Council on the basis of Article J.2 of the Treaty on European Union on Angola</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995E0413:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995E0413:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">123</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1876</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2431</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3112</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4065</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">584</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31995E0413-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">95/413/CFSP: Common Position of 2 October 1995 defined by the Council on the basis of Article J.2 of the Treaty on European Union on Angola</head>
      <p n="2">COMMON POSITION</p>
      <p n="3">of 2 October 1995</p>
      <p n="4">defined by the Council on the basis of Article J.2 of the Treaty on European Union on Angola</p>
      <p n="5">(95/413/CFSP)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty on European Union and in particular Article J.2 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DEFINED THE FOLLOWING COMMON POSITION:</p>
      <p n="9">A. The European Union will pursue with regard to Angola the following objectives:</p>
      <p n="10">1. To support the effective implementation of the Lusaka Protocol, the Bicesse 'acordos de paz' and the relevant UN Security Council Resolutions.</p>
      <p n="11">2. To support the mission of the special representative of the Secretary General of the United Nations and of the observer Troika.</p>
      <p n="12">3. To accelerate the rhythm at which the agreements enshrined in the Lusaka Protocol and those reached by the Government of Angola and Unita subsequent to the signature of this document are being implemented by the parties and Unavem.</p>
      <p n="13">4. To support the dialogue initiated by recent meetings between the President of the Republic of Angola and the President of Unita, which constitutes a significant new step towards the climate of trust necessary for the consolidation of the peace process. It should permit the establishment of a framework for peaceful co-existence between all Angolans based on democratic principles, the rule of law, justice and full respect for Human Reights.</p>
      <p n="14">5. To support the coordinated efforts of the international community towards the reconstruction of Angola in the framework of the peace process.</p>
      <p n="15">B. In order to further those objectives the European Union, welcoming the positive outcome of the UNDP round table held in Brussels on 25 and 26 September 1995 to which the European Union has largely contributed, is prepared to:</p>
      <p n="16">1. Assist the government of Angola in the aim of strengthening democracy and the rule of law.</p>
      <p n="17">2. Continue its participation in the efforts to alleviate the suffering of refugees and displaced persons and expedite their social and economic reintegration.</p>
      <p n="18">3. Contribute to the efforts made towards social reintegration of the demobilized solidiers, including those made by Angola and the United Nations.</p>
      <p n="19">4. Assist Unavem III by taking part in the reinforcement of its Human Rights monitoring component proposed by the Secretary General of the United Nations in his report of July 1995.</p>
      <p n="20">5. Participate in the demining operations, including within the framework of joint action on anti-personnel mines (1).</p>
      <p n="21">6. Participate in initiatives undertaken by Angola and the international community aimed at the national reconciliation, rehabilitation and reconstruction of the country.</p>
      <p n="22">C. The Council and the Commission, acting within the framework of their respective competences, shall take the measures necessary for the implementation of this common position.</p>
      <p n="23">The follow-up of this common position shall be ensured by the competent groups of the Council.</p>
      <p n="24">D. This Common Position shall be published in the Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="25">Done at Luxembourg, 2 October 1995.</p>
      <p n="26">For the Council</p>
      <p n="27">The President</p>
      <p n="28">J. SOLANA</p>
      <p n="29">(1) Council Decision 95/170/CFSP of 12 May 1995 concerning the joint action adopted by the Council on the basis of Article J.3 of the Treaty on European Union on anti-personnel mines (OJ No L 115, 22. 5. 1995, p. 1).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
