<TEI.2 id="jrc31995R1620-en" n="31995R1620" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31995R1620 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1620/95 of 4 July 1995 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2427/93 laying down detailed rules for the application of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2075/92 with regard to the Community Fund for tobacco research and information</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R1620:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R1620:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1425</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2194</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2915</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4373</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">666</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">979</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31995R1620-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1620/95 of 4 July 1995 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2427/93 laying down detailed rules for the application of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2075/92 with regard to the Community Fund for tobacco research and information</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 1620/95 of 4 July 1995 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2427/93 laying down detailed rules for the application of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2075/92 with regard to the Community Fund for tobacco research and information</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2075/92 of 30 June 1992 on the common organization of the market in raw tobacco (1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 711/95 of 27 March 1995 (2), and in particular Article 13 (3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2427/93 (3), as amended by Regulation (EC) No 2678/94 (4), lays down detailed rules for the application of Regulation (EEC) No 2075/92 as regards the Community Fund for tobacco research and information; whereas experience indicates that the application of the accounting provisions laid down in Regulation (EEC) No 2427/93, as amended entails the national entry in the accounts of expenditure exceeding payments actually made and of revenues not collected; whereas this procedure is causing declaration problems for Member States; whereas the system should accordingly be revised;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas this change in accounting practice does not affect the recipients' rights;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Tobacco,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Article 10 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 2427/93 is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="12">'2. Pursuant to Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3478/92 of 1 December 1992 laying down detailed rules for the application of the premium system for raw tobacco, the amount to be withheld as referred to in paragraph 1 shall be deducted at the time of payment from the premium to be paid to producers and from the reimbursement to be made by Member States to processors.</p>
      <p n="13">The premium after deduction shall be declared by the Member States as expenditure by the Guarantee Section of the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund (EAGGF).`</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="16">The book-keeping laid down in Article 10 (2) shall apply to all of the premiums for the 1994 harvest.</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 4 July 1995.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission Franz FISCHLER Member of the Commission</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
