<TEI.2 id="jrc31995R2625-en" n="31995R2625" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31995R2625 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2625/95 of 10 November 1995 amending Regulation (EC) No 1591/95 by adding to it certain rules-for monitoring the systems of export refunds on glucose and glucose syrup used in certain products processed from fruit and vegetables</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>28 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R2625:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R2625:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1170</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">181</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2730</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2731</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3568</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4170</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31995R2625-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2625/95 of 10 November 1995 amending Regulation (EC) No 1591/95 by adding to it certain rules-for monitoring the systems of export refunds on glucose and glucose syrup used in certain products processed from fruit and vegetables</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 2625/95 of 10 November 1995 amending Regulation (EC) No 1591/95 by adding to it certain rules-for monitoring the systems of export refunds on glucose and glucose syrup used in certain products processed from fruit and vegetables</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 426/86 of 24 February 1986 on the common organization of the market in products processed from fruit and vegetables (1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 2314/95 (2), and in particular Articles 13 (8), 14 (5) and 14 (7) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EC) No 1591/95 of 30 June 1995 laying down detailed rules for the application of export refunds to glucose and glucose syrup used in certain products processed from fruit and vegetables (3) provides for a refund for glucose and glucose syrup used in certain products processed from fruit and vegetables;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, pursuant to Regulation (EEC) No 426/86, the Member States are obliged to check the accuracy of the declarations indicating the quantity of sugar used in the manufacturing process; whereas at least 5 % of the declarations should be checked to ensure the proper working of the system;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Products Processed from Fruit and Vegetables,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">In Regulation (EC) No 1591/95,</p>
      <p n="12">1. the following indent is inserted after Article 2, first indent:</p>
      <p n="13">'However, for the purpose of applying this Regulation, section 20 of the licence application and of the licence shall contain one of the following indications:</p>
      <p n="14">- "Glucosa utilizado en uno o varios productos enumerados en la letra b) del apartado 1 del artículo 1 del Reglamento (CEE) n° 426/86"</p>
      <p n="15">- »Glucose anvendt i et eller flere af de produkter, der er naevnt i artikel 1, stk. 1, litra b), i forordning (EOEF) nr. 426/86« - 'Glukose, einem oder mehreren der in Artikel 1 Absatz 1 Buchstabe b) der Verordnung (EWG) Nr. 426/86 genannten Erzeugnisse zugesetzt' - "Ãëõêueaeç ðïõ ÷ñçóéìïðïéaassôáé óaa Ýíá Þ ðaañéóóueôaañá ôùí ðñïúueíôùí ðïõ áðáñéèìïýíôáé óôï UEñèñï 1 ðáñUEãñáoeïò 1 óôïé÷aassï â) ôïõ êáíïíéóìïý (AAÏÊ) áñéè. 426/86"</p>
      <p n="16">- "Glucose used in one or more products as listed in Article 1 (1) (b) of Regulation (EEC) No 426/86"</p>
      <p n="17">- "Glucose mis en oeuvre dans un ou plusieurs produits énumérés à l'article 1er paragraphe 1 point b) du règlement (CEE) n° 426/86"</p>
      <p n="18">- "Glucosio incorporato in uno o più prodotti di cui all'articolo 1, paragrafo 1, lettera b) del regolamento (CEE) n. 426/86"</p>
      <p n="19">- "Glucose, verwerkt in een of meer van de in artikel 1, lid 1, onder b), van Verordening (EEG) nr. 426/86 genoemde produkten"</p>
      <p n="20">- "Glicose utilizado num ou mais produtos enumerados no nº 1, alínea b), do artigo 1º do Regulamento (CEE) nº 426/86"</p>
      <p n="21">- `Glukoosin tai useammassa asetuksen (ETY) N :o 426/86 1 artiklan 1 kohdan b alakohdassa luetellussa tuotteessa kaeytetty sokeri` - `Glukos som tillsaetts i en eller flera av produkterna i artikel 1.1 b i foerordning (EEG) nr 426/86``;</p>
      <p n="22">2. the following Article is inserted after Article 2:</p>
      <p n="23">'Article 2a The competent authorities of the Member States shall check the accuracy of the declarations referred to in Article 14a (3) of Regulation (EEC) No 426/86 on a sample of at least 5 % selected on the basis of a risk analysis. Such checks shall be carried out on the stock records kept by the manufacturer.`</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="26">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="27">Done at Brussels, 10 November 1995.</p>
      <p n="28">For the Commission Franz FISCHLER Member of the Commission</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
