<TEI.2 id="jrc31995R0839-en" n="31995R0839" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31995R0839 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 839/95 of 10 April 1995 amending the list of countries mentioned in Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 519/94</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>20 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R0839:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995R0839:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1567</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1631</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2300</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3591</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">646</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31995R0839-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 839/95 of 10 April 1995 amending the list of countries mentioned in Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 519/94</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC) No 839/95 of 10 April 1995 amending the list of countries mentioned in Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 519/94</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Council Regulation (EC) No 519/94 of 7 March 1994 on common rules for imports from certain third countries (1), applies inter alia, to imports originating in Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the Community has signed Free Trade Agreements with Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania, which have moreover embarked on a large-scale programme of economic reform aimed at ensuring their transition towards a market economy;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas provision should be made therefore that these countries are removed from the scope of Regulation (EC) No 519/94 with effect from the entry into force of the said Agreements,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania shall be removed from Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 519/94.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">It shall apply on the date of entry into force of the Free Trade Agreements concluded respectively between the countries referred to in Article 1 and the Community.</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Luxembourg, 10 April 1995.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">A. JUPPÉ</p>
      <p n="20">(1) OJ No L 67, 10. 3. 1994, p. 89.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
