<TEI.2 id="jrc41995D0001-en" n="41995D0001" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 41995D0001 English</title>
        <title>The Schengen acquis - Decision of the Executive Committee of 5 May 1995 on common visa policy. Decision contained in the minutes of the meeting of the Executive Committee held in Brussels on 28 April 1995 (SCH/Com-ex (95) PV 1 rev.)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>14 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41995D0001:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41995D0001:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4005</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5420</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5796</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc41995D0001-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">The Schengen acquis - Decision of the Executive Committee of 5 May 1995 on common visa policy. Decision contained in the minutes of the meeting of the Executive Committee held in Brussels on 28 April 1995 (SCH/Com-ex (95) PV 1 rev.)</head>
      <p n="2">DECISION OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE</p>
      <p n="3">of 5 May 1995</p>
      <p n="4">on common visa policy</p>
      <p n="5">Decision contained in the minutes of the meeting of the Executive Committee held in Brussels on 28 April 1995</p>
      <p n="6">(SCH/Com-ex (95) PV 1 rev.)</p>
      <p n="7">8. Other business</p>
      <p n="8">Visa policy with regard to Indonesia</p>
      <p n="9">The Executive Committee re-examined the item on visa policy with regard to Indonesia, which appeared on the agenda of the follow-up committee, and agreed on the following solution, which would apply temporarily and by way of exception.</p>
      <p n="10">1. Visa applications lodged by Indonesians who have stated that they intend to enter or transit through the national territory of Portugal</p>
      <p n="11">- shall be subject to prior consultation; Indonesians may only enter Portuguese territory if they have received official authorisation from the Portuguese State.</p>
      <p n="12">2. Visa applications lodged by Indonesians who have stated that they have no intention of entering or transiting through the national territory of Portugal</p>
      <p n="13">- do not require prior consultation. In such cases, to ensure Indonesian nationals cannot travel freely to Portugal, the other Schengen States shall issue such nationals a visa with limited territorial validity authorising the holder to enter the territory of one or several Contracting Parties with the exception of Portuguese territory.</p>
      <p n="14">The Executive Committee would examine this question again at the end of the year.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
