<TEI.2 id="jrc21999D0722_16-en" n="21999D0722(16)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21999D0722(16) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21999D0722(16):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21999D0722(16):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1474</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">177</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2527</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5334</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5618</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">616</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21999D0722_16-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">DECISION OF THE EEA JOINT COMMITTEE</p>
      <p n="3">No 97/98</p>
      <p n="4">of 25 September 1998</p>
      <p n="5">amending Annex XX (Environment) to the EEA Agreement</p>
      <p n="6">THE EEA JOINT COMMITTEE,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Agreement on the European Economic Area, as adjusted by the Protocol adjusting the Agreement on the European Economic Area, hereinafter referred to as "the Agreement", and in particular Article 98 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Annex XX to the Agreement was amended by Decision of the EEA Joint Committee No 76/98 of 31 July 1998(1);</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Council Decision 97/101/EC of 27 January 1997 establishing a reciprocal exchange of information and data from networks and individual stations measuring ambient air pollution within the Member States(2), is to be incorporated into the Agreement,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The following point shall be inserted after point 14a (Council Directive 96/62/EC) in Annex XX to the Agreement: "14b. 397 D 0101: Council Decision 97/101/EC of 27 January 1997 establishing a reciprocal exchange of information and data from networks and individual stations measuring ambient air pollution within the Member States (OJ L 35, 5.2.1997, p. 14)".</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">The texts of Decision 97/101/EC in the Icelandic and Norwegian languages, which are annexed to the respective language versions of this Decision, are authentic.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">This Decision shall enter into force on 26 September 1998, provided that all the notifications under Article 103(1) of the Agreement have been made to the EEA Joint Committee.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 4</p>
      <p n="18">This Decision shall be published in the EEA section of, and in the EEA Supplement to, the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 25 September 1998.</p>
      <p n="20">For the EEA Joint Committee</p>
      <p n="21">The President</p>
      <p n="22">N. v. LIECHTENSTEIN</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ L 172, 8.7.1999, p. 55.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ L 35, 5.2.1997, p. 14.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
