<TEI.2 id="jrc31999R0083-en" n="31999R0083" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999R0083 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 83/1999 of 13 January 1999 amending the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 on the registration of geographical indications and designations of origin under the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R0083:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R0083:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1425</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2734</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2735</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3173</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999R0083-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 83/1999 of 13 January 1999 amending the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 on the registration of geographical indications and designations of origin under the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 83/1999 of 13 January 1999 amending the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 on the registration of geographical indications and designations of origin under the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 of 14 July 1992 on the protection of geographical indications and designations of origin for agricultural products and foodstuffs (1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 1068/97 (2), and in particular Article 9 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, in accordance with Article 9 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92, the French Government has requested that the name 'Ossau-Iraty Brebis-Pyrénées`, registered as a protected designation of origin by Commission Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1549/98 (4), should be changed to 'Ossau-Iraty`;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas examination of the request for amendment has revealed that it is a minor amendment; whereas this is because, although an amendment to a registered name, which in principle should be considered a major amendment, it does not affect the rights of the holders of the name in question; whereas, furthermore, the amendment does not affect the rights of other producers;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, in accordance with the procedure provided for in Article 9 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92, the Commission decided in its Decision of 20 March 1998 not to apply the procedure provided for in Article 6 as it was a case of a minor amendment;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas it has also been concluded that this is an amendment in compliance with Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92; whereas, therefore, the change of the name 'Ossau-Iraty Brebis-Pyrénées` to 'Ossau-Iraty` should be registered and the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 should be amended accordingly;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, in accordance with Article 6(4) of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92, the amendment of the name 'Ossau-Iraty Brebis-Pyrénées` to 'Ossau-Iraty` should be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">In the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96, the protected designation of origin 'Ossau-Iraty Brebis-Pyrénées` is hereby replaced by 'Ossau-Iraty`.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 13 January 1999.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="20">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ L 208, 24. 7. 1992, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) OJ L 156, 13. 6. 1997, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="23">(3) OJ L 148, 21. 6. 1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="24">(4) OJ L 202, 18. 7. 1998, p. 25.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
