<TEI.2 id="jrc31999R0590-en" n="31999R0590" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999R0590 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 590/1999 of 18 March 1999 supplementing the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 on the registration of geographical indications and designations of origin under the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>32 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R0590:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R0590:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1425</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2734</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2735</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3173</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999R0590-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 590/1999 of 18 March 1999 supplementing the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 on the registration of geographical indications and designations of origin under the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 590/1999 of 18 March 1999 supplementing the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 on the registration of geographical indications and designations of origin under the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 of 14 July 1992 on the protection of geographical indications and designations of origin for agricultural products and foodstuffs (1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 1068/97 (2), and in particular Article 17(2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, for certain names notified by the Member States under Article 17 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92, additional information was requested in order to ensure that they complied with Articles 2 and 4 of that Regulation; whereas that additional information shows that the names comply with the said Articles; whereas they should therefore be registered and added to the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 1107/96 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 83/1999 (4);</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, following the accession of three new Member States, the six-month period provided for in Article 17 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 is to begin on the date of their accession; whereas some of the names notified by those Member States comply with Articles 2 and 4 of that Regulation and should therefore be registered;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Regulatory Committee on geographical indications and designations of origin,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The names in the Annex to this Regulation are hereby added to the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 1107/96.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 18 March 1999.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="17">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="18">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">(1) OJ L 208, 24. 7. 1992, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="20">(2) OJ L 156, 13. 6. 1997, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="21">(3) OJ L 148, 21. 6. 1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="22">(4) OJ L 8, 14. 1. 1999, p. 17.</p>
      <p n="23">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="24">A. PRODUCTS INTENDED FOR HUMAN CONSUMPTION LISTED IN ANNEX II TO THE TREATY</p>
      <p n="25">Fresh meat (and offal)</p>
      <p n="26">ITALY</p>
      <p n="27">- Cotechino Modena (PGI)</p>
      <p n="28">- Zampone Modena (PGI)</p>
      <p n="29">Fruits, vegetables, cereals</p>
      <p n="30">GERMANY</p>
      <p n="31">- Spreewälder Gurken (PGI)</p>
      <p n="32">- Spreewälder Meerrettich (PGI)</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
