<TEI.2 id="jrc31999D0875-en" n="31999D0875" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999D0875 English</title>
        <title>1999/875/EC: Council Decision of 21 December 1999 on the provisional application of the Agreement between the European Community and the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia on trade in textile products</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>20 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999D0875:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999D0875:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1642</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2783</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3591</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4680</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5403</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5713</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999D0875-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">1999/875/EC: Council Decision of 21 December 1999 on the provisional application of the Agreement between the European Community and the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia on trade in textile products</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="3">of 21 December 1999</p>
      <p n="4">on the provisional application of the Agreement between the European Community and the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia on trade in textile products</p>
      <p n="5">(1999/875/EC)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 133(2) thereof, in conjunction with Article 300(2), first sentence thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) The Commission has negotiated on behalf of the European Community an Agreement on trade in textile products with the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia;</p>
      <p n="11">(2) This Agreement should be applied on a provisional basis from 1 January 2000 pending the completion of the procedures for its conclusion, subject to reciprocal provisional application by the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Sole Article</p>
      <p n="14">The Agreement between the European Community and the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia on trade in textile products shall be applied on a provisional basis from 1 January 2000 pending the completion of the procedures for its conclusion, subject to reciprocal provisional application by the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia(1).</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 21 December 1999.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">T. HALONEN</p>
      <p n="20">(1) The date from which the agreement will apply on a provisional basis will be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities, C series.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
