<TEI.2 id="jrc31999D0762-en" n="31999D0762" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999D0762 English</title>
        <title>1999/762/EC: Council Decision of 15 November 1999 amending Decision 91/666/EEC establishing Community reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>33 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999D0762:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999D0762:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1598</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3660</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4281</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4635</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">994</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999D0762-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">1999/762/EC: Council Decision of 15 November 1999 amending Decision 91/666/EEC establishing Community reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="3">of 15 November 1999</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 91/666/EEC establishing Community reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines</p>
      <p n="5">(1999/762/EC)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 37 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(1),</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee(2),</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) in accordance with the provisions of Article 13(3) of Council Directive 85/511/EEC of 18 November 1985 introducing Community measures for the control of foot-and-mouth disease(3), a decision may be taken to introduce emergency vaccination in a limited area, in circumstances where slaughter of the entire herd may not be sufficient to eliminate the virus;</p>
      <p n="13">(2) by Council Decision 91/666/EEC(4) Community reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines were established, which are based on stocks of concentrated inactivated antigen capable of being quickly converted into vaccine for emergency use and stored at designated premises;</p>
      <p n="14">(3) since the adoption of the said Decision two antigen banks designated for maintaining part of the Community reserve of foot-and-mouth disease antigens have relinquished their commitments to provide these services to the Community;</p>
      <p n="15">(4) in order to comply with Article 3(3) of the aforementioned Decision the need may arise for various reasons to designate appropriate premises within the Community to which the foot-and-mouth disease antigen reserves shall be distributed or relocated for storage;</p>
      <p n="16">(5) according to Article 14(3) of Directive 85/511/EEC, the possibility for the Commission to propose to the Council to set up the Community reserves of anti-foot-and-mouth disease vaccines has expired since 1 April 1991;</p>
      <p n="17">(6) in order to allow immediate reaction to the need to distribute or relocate the Community reserves of foot-and-mouth disease antigen for storage at different sites, it is necessary to amend Decision 91/666/EEC in particular as regards the procedures laid down for the designation of antigen and vaccine banks,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">In paragraph 1 of Article 3 of Decision 91/666/EEC:</p>
      <p n="21">(a) the first and third indents shall be deleted;</p>
      <p n="22">(b) a new indent shall be added as follows:</p>
      <p n="23">"- any other establishment designated in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 10".</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="26">Done at Brussels, 15 November 1999.</p>
      <p n="27">For the Council</p>
      <p n="28">The President</p>
      <p n="29">K. HEMILÄ</p>
      <p n="30">(1) Opinion delivered on 6 October 1999 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="31">(2) Opinion delivered on 20 October 1999 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="32">(3) OJ L 315, 26.11.1985, p. 11. Directive as last amended by Decision 92/380/EEC (OJ L 198, 17.7.1992, p. 54).</p>
      <p n="33">(4) OJ L 368, 31.12.1991, p. 21.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
