<TEI.2 id="jrc31999R1167-en" n="31999R1167" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999R1167 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1167/1999 of 3 June 1999 amending Regulation (EC) No 831/97 laying down marketing standards applicable to avocados</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R1167:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R1167:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1119</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1120</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2081</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2871</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">87</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999R1167-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1167/1999 of 3 June 1999 amending Regulation (EC) No 831/97 laying down marketing standards applicable to avocados</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 1167/1999</p>
      <p n="3">of 3 June 1999</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 831/97 laying down marketing standards applicable to avocados</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 2200/96 of 28 October 1996 on the common organisation of the market in fruit and vegetables(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 857/1999(2), and in particular Article 2(2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">(1) Whereas the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 831/97(3) lays down the marketing standard applicable to avocados;</p>
      <p n="9">(2) Whereas UN/ECE (United Nations Economic Commission for Europe) Standard FFV-42 concerning the marketing and commercial quality control of avocados moving in international trade between and to UN/ECE member countries has been amended at recent meetings of the ECE Working Party on Standardisation of Perishable Produce and Quality Development; whereas Article 2(2) of Regulation (EC) No 2200/96 provides that account is to be taken of the UN/ECE standards recommended by that Working Party when standards are adopted on fruit and vegetables; whereas the Community standard for avocados should accordingly be brought into line with the corresponding UN/ECE standard;</p>
      <p n="10">(3) Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Fresh Fruit and Vegetables,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">The Annex to Regulation (EC) No 831/97 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="14">1. in Title II "PROVISIONS CONCERNING QUALITY", point A "Minimum requirements", second paragraph, first sentence, "firm at the point of dispatch, and" is added after "must be";</p>
      <p n="15">2. in Title V "PROVISIONS CONCERNING PRESENTATION", point A "Uniformity", the first paragraph is replaced by the following (including footnote (1)): "The contents of each package must be uniform and contain only avocados of the same origin, variety, quality, coloration(4) and size."</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 3 June 1999.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="22">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ L 297, 21.11.1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ L 108, 27.4.1999, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="25">(3) OJ L 119, 8.5.1997, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="26">(4) A change in the colour of the dark-skinned varieties is not considered as a defect, but the colouring of the fruit in each package must be uniform at the point of dispatch.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
