<TEI.2 id="jrc31999R1447-en" n="31999R1447" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999R1447 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 1447/1999 of 24 June 1999 establishing a list of types of behaviour which seriously infringe the rules of the common fisheries policy</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>59 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R1447:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R1447:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">13</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2455</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2718</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3489</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5228</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5229</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999R1447-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 1447/1999 of 24 June 1999 establishing a list of types of behaviour which seriously infringe the rules of the common fisheries policy</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC) No 1447/1999</p>
      <p n="3">of 24 June 1999</p>
      <p n="4">establishing a list of types of behaviour which seriously infringe the rules of the common fisheries policy</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 37 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission(1),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(2),</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) according to Article 31(2a) of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2847/93 of 12 October 1993 establishing a control system applicable to the common fisheries policy(3), the Council, acting on the basis of Article 37 of the Treaty, may draw up a list of types of behaviour which seriously infringe the rules of the common fisheries policy;</p>
      <p n="11">(2) in order to improve transparency in the common fisheries policy, Member States should provide the Commission with information on instances of such behaviour and action taken by Member States;</p>
      <p n="12">(3) Article 37 of Regulation (EEC) No 2847/93 provides for the protection of certain personal data in the framework of the control system applicable to the common fisheries policy;</p>
      <p n="13">(4) the abovementioned list is to be coherent with similar provisions adopted by international fisheries organisations;</p>
      <p n="14">(5) for certain measures laid down by this Regulation it is appropriate to provide for detailed rules of implementation,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">The types of behaviour which seriously infringe the rules of the common fisheries policy as referred to in Article 1 of Regulation (EEC) No 2847/93 shall be those listed in the Annex hereto.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">1. The Member States shall notify the Commission on a regular basis of the instances of behaviour referred to in Article 1 that have been discovered and shall provide it with all information regarding action taken by the administrative and/or judicial authorities.</p>
      <p n="20">2. The Commission shall make the information it receives pursuant to paragraph 1 available to the European Parliament, the Council and the Advisory Committee of Fisheries.</p>
      <p n="21">3. The information notified under paragraph 1 and made available under paragraph 2 shall be treated in accordance with the provisions of Article 37 of Regulation (EEC) No 2847/93.</p>
      <p n="22">4. Detailed rules for the implementation of this Article, shall be laid down in accordance with the procedure in Article 36 of Regulation (EEC) No 2847/93.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 3</p>
      <p n="24">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="26">Done at Luxembourg, 24 June 1999.</p>
      <p n="27">For the Council</p>
      <p n="28">The President</p>
      <p n="29">J. TRITTIN</p>
      <p n="30">(1) OJ C 105, 15.4.1999, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="31">(2) Opinion delivered on 4 May 1999 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="32">(3) OJ L 261, 20.10.1993, p. 1. Regulation as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2846/98 (OJ L 358, 31.12.1998, p. 5).</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="34">LIST OF TYPES OF BEHAVIOUR WHICH SERIOUSLY INFRINGE THE RULES OF THE COMMON FISHERIES POLICY</p>
      <p n="35">A. Failure to cooperate with the authorities responsible for monitoring</p>
      <p n="36">- Obstructing the work of fisheries inspectors in the exercise of their duties in inspecting for compliance with the applicable Community rules.</p>
      <p n="37">- Falsifying, concealing, destroying or tampering with evidence which could be used in the course of inquiries or judicial proceedings.</p>
      <p n="38">B. Failure to cooperate with observers</p>
      <p n="39">- Obstructing the work of observers in carrying out their duties, laid down by Community Law, of observing compliance with the applicable Community rules.</p>
      <p n="40">C. Failure to observe the conditions to be met when fishing</p>
      <p n="41">- Fishing without holding a fishing licence, a fishing permit or any other authorisation required for fishing and issued by the flag Member State or by the Commission.</p>
      <p n="42">- Fishing under cover of one of the abovementioned documents the content of which has been falsified.</p>
      <p n="43">- Falsifying, deleting or concealing the identification marks of the fishing vessel.</p>
      <p n="44">D. Failure to comply during fishing operations</p>
      <p n="45">- Using or keeping on board prohibited fishing gear or devices affecting the selectiveness of gear.</p>
      <p n="46">- Using prohibited fishing methods.</p>
      <p n="47">- Not lashing or stowing fishing gear the use of which is prohibited in a certain fishing zone.</p>
      <p n="48">- Directed fishing for, or keeping on board of species from, stocks subject to a moratorium or a prohibition of fishing.</p>
      <p n="49">- Unauthorised fishing in a given zone and/or during a specific period.</p>
      <p n="50">- Failure to comply with the rules on minimum sizes.</p>
      <p n="51">- Failure to comply with the rules and procedures relating to transhipment and fisheries operations involving joint action by two or more vessels.</p>
      <p n="52">E. Failure to comply in connection with resources for monitoring</p>
      <p n="53">- Falsifying or failing to record data in logbooks, landing declarations, sales notes, takeover declarations and transport documents or failure to keep or submit these documents.</p>
      <p n="54">- Tampering with the satellite-based vessel monitoring system.</p>
      <p n="55">- Deliberate failure to comply with the Community rules on remote transmission of movements of fishing vessels and of data of fishery products held on board.</p>
      <p n="56">- Failure of the master of the fishing vessel of a third country or his representative to comply with the applicable control rules when operating fishing in Community waters.</p>
      <p n="57">F. Failure to comply in connection with landing and marketing of fishery products</p>
      <p n="58">- Landing of fishery products not respecting the Community rules on control and enforcement.</p>
      <p n="59">- Stocking, processing, placing for sale and transporting fishery products not meeting the marketing standards in force and, in particular, those concerning minimum sizes.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
