<TEI.2 id="jrc31999R0101-en" n="31999R0101" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999R0101 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 101/1999 of 15 January 1999 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter and Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 on the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter intended for direct consumption in the Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R0101:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999R0101:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">20</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2741</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4667</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4860</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999R0101-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 101/1999 of 15 January 1999 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter and Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 on the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter intended for direct consumption in the Community</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 101/1999 of 15 January 1999 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter and Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 on the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter intended for direct consumption in the Community</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organisation of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1587/96 (2), and in particular Articles 6(6) and 7a(3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1802/95 (4), provides for the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the Community in the form of concentrated butter; whereas the scheme will continue to apply for as long as stocks of butter in intervention storage permit; whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 429/90 (5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 417/98 (6), provides for the granting by invitation to tender of an aid for concentrated butter obtained from butter or cream from the market and intended for direct consumption in the Community; whereas these Regulations and Commission Regulation (EC) No 2571/97 of 15 December 1997 on the sale of butter at reduced prices and the granting of aid for cream, butter and concentrated butter for use in the manufacture of pastry products, ice-cream and other foodstuffs (7), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1982/98 (8), provide for tracers to be added to concentrated butter to ensure the correct use of the final product; whereas provision should be made for the same limits and reference methods to apply where the content of the chemical tracers referred to in those Regulations is not observed;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">1. The second subparagraph of Article 9(2) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="11">'However, where, for example because of uneven distribution, the content of each of the products referred to in Article 5(2) is found to be more than 5 % but less than 30 % below the minimum quantities prescribed, 1,5 % of the processing security shall be forfeited for each percentage point below the prescribed minimum quantities.`</p>
      <p n="12">2. In Article 8(4) of Regulation (EEC) No 429/90, '20 %` is replaced by '30 %`.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 15 January 1999.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="18">Franz FISCHLER</p>
      <p n="19">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">(1) OJ L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="21">(2) OJ L 206, 16. 8. 1996, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="22">(3) OJ L 298, 12. 11. 1985, p. 9.</p>
      <p n="23">(4) OJ L 174, 26. 7. 1995, p. 27.</p>
      <p n="24">(5) OJ L 45, 21. 2. 1990, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="25">(6) OJ L 52, 21. 2. 1998, p. 18.</p>
      <p n="26">(7) OJ L 350, 20. 12. 1997, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="27">(8) OJ L 256, 18. 9. 1998, p. 9.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
