<TEI.2 id="jrc31999D0819-en" n="31999D0819" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31999D0819 English</title>
        <title>1999/819/Euratom: Commission Decision of 16 November 1999 concerning the accession to the 1994 Convention on Nuclear Safety by the European Atomic Energy Community (Euratom) (notified under document number C(1999) 3223)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>21 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999D0819:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31999D0819:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3468</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4042</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5344</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5420</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31999D0819-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">1999/819/Euratom: Commission Decision of 16 November 1999 concerning the accession to the 1994 Convention on Nuclear Safety by the European Atomic Energy Community (Euratom) (notified under document number C(1999) 3223)</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION</p>
      <p n="3">of 16 November 1999</p>
      <p n="4">concerning the accession to the 1994 Convention on Nuclear Safety by the European Atomic Energy Community (Euratom)</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(1999) 3223)</p>
      <p n="6">(1999/819/Euratom)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community and in particular the second paragraph of Article 101 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Council Decision of 7 December 1998 approving the accession of the European Atomic Energy Community to the Convention on Nuclear Safety,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas all Member States are Contracting Parties to the Convention on Nuclear Safety;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the European Atomic Energy Community should accede to the Convention on Nuclear Safety,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Accession to the Convention on Nuclear Safety is hereby approved on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Convention and the declaration by the European Atomic Energy Community according to the provisions of Article 30(4)(iii) of the Convention are attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The instruments of accession shall be deposited with the Director-General of the International Atomic Energy Agency, depositary of the Convention, the day following the adoption of this Decision.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 16 November 1999.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">Margot WALLSTRÖM</p>
      <p n="21">Member of the Commission</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
