<TEI.2 id="jrc31987R3986-en" n="31987R3986" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31987R3986 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3986/87 of 22 December 1987 amending various Regulations concerning the implementation of the common organization of the markets in poultrymeat as a consequence of the introduction of the combined nomenclature</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>80 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31987R3986:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31987R3986:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31987R3986-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3986/87 of 22 December 1987 amending various Regulations concerning the implementation of the common organization of the markets in poultrymeat as a consequence of the introduction of the combined nomenclature</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) N° 3986/87</p>
      <p n="3">of 22 December 1987</p>
      <p n="4">amending various Regulations concerning the implementation of the common organization of the markets in poultrymeat as a consequence of the introduction of the combined nomenclature</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) N° 2658/87 of 23 July 1987 on the tariff and statistical nomenclature and on the Common Customs Tariff (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) N° 3985/87 (2) and in particular the second subparagraph of Article 15 (1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) N° 3907/87 of 22 December 1987, amending Regulation (EEC) N° 2777/75 on the common organization of the markets in the poultrymeat sector (3), and in particular Article 2 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, in accordance with the second subparagraph of Article 15 (1) of Regulation (EEC) N° 2658/87, technical adaptations of Community acts referring to the combined nomenclature are carried out by the Commission; whereas amendments of substance are carried out in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 17 of Council Regulation (EEC) N° 2777/75 (4) pursuant to Article 2 of Regulation (EEC) N° 3907/87;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas numerous Regulations in the poultrymeat sector must be adapted technically and as regards certain points of substance to take account of the use of the new combined nomenclature based on the Harmonized Commodity Description and Coding System which is intended to replace the Convention of 15 December 1950 on Nomenclature for the Classification of Goods in Customs Tariffs;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, on account of the number and the content of the text calling for such adaptations, all the Regulations to be adapted should be grouped within a single amending Regulation;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Poultrymeat and Eggs,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1 of Commission Regulation (EEC) N° 565/68 of 24 April 1968 on the non-fixing of additional amounts for</p>
      <p n="16">slaughtered fowls, ducks and geese imported from Poland (5), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) N° 2039/73 (6), is herely replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="17">'Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">The levies fixed in accordance with Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) N° 2777/75 shall not be increased by an additional amount in respect of imports of the following products falling within subheading ex 2007 of the combined nomenclature originating in and coming from Poland:</p>
      <p n="19">(a) Fowls of the species Gallus domesticus, not cut in pieces:</p>
      <p n="20">- Plucked and gutted, with heads and feet, known as ''83 % chickens'',</p>
      <p n="21">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet but with necks, hearts, livers and gizzards, known as ''70 % chickens'',</p>
      <p n="22">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet and without necks, hearts, livers and gizzards, known as '65 % chickens', or otherwise presented;</p>
      <p n="23">(b) Ducks, not cut in pieces:</p>
      <p n="24">- Plucked, bled, gutted but not drawn, with heads and feet, known as ''85 % ducks'',</p>
      <p n="25">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet but with necks, hearts, livers and gizzards, known as ''70 % ducks'',</p>
      <p n="26">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet and without necks, hearts, livers and gizzards, known as ''63 % ducks'', or otherwise presented;</p>
      <p n="27">(c) Geese, not cut in pieces:</p>
      <p n="28">- Plucked, bled, not drawn, with heads and feet, known as ''82 % geese'',</p>
      <p n="29">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet, with or without hearts and gizzards, known as ''75 % geese'', or otherwise presented.</p>
      <p n="30">Article 2</p>
      <p n="31">Article 1 of Commission Regulation (EEC) N° 2261/69 of 13 November 1969 on the non-fixing of additional amounts for slaughtered ducks and geese imported from Romania (7) as last amended by Regulation (EEC) N° 2039/73, is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="32">'Article 1</p>
      <p n="33">The levies fixed in accordance with Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) N° 2777/75 shall not be increased by an additional amount in respect of imports of the following products falling within subheading ex 0207 of the combined nomenclature originating in and coming from Romania:</p>
      <p n="34">(a) Ducks, not cut in pieces:</p>
      <p n="35">- Plucked, bled, gutted but not drawn, with heads and feet, known as ''85 % ducks'',</p>
      <p n="36">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet but with necks, hearts, livers and gizzards, known as ''70 % ducks'',</p>
      <p n="37">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet and without necks, heats, livers and gizzards, known as ''63 % ducks'', or otherwise presented;</p>
      <p n="38">(b) Geese, not cut in pieces:</p>
      <p n="39">- Plucked, bled, not drawn, with heads and feet, known as ''82 % geese'',</p>
      <p n="40">- Plucked and drawn, without heads and feet, with or without hearts and gizzards, known as ''75 % geese'', or otherwise presented.'</p>
      <p n="41">Article 3</p>
      <p n="42">Article 1 of Commission Regulation (EEC) N° 2474/70 of 7 December 1970 on the non-fixing of an additional amount for slaughtered turkeys imported from Poland (1), is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="43">'Article 1</p>
      <p n="44">The levies fixed in accordance with Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) N° 2777/75 shall not be increased by an additional amount in respect of imports of slaughtered turkeys falling within subheadings 0207 10 31, 0207 10 39 and 0207 22 of the combined nomenclature, originating in and coming from Poland.'</p>
      <p n="45">Article 4</p>
      <p n="46">Annexes I and II to Council Regulation (EEC) N° 2778/75 of 29 October 1975 laying down rules for calculating the levy and the sluice-gate price for poultrymeat (2), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) N° 3233/86 (3) are hereby replaced by Annexes I and II to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="47">Article 5</p>
      <p n="48">The Annex to Commission Regulation (EEC) N° 3011/79 of 20 December 1979 fixing the coefficients for calculating levies on derived poultrymeat products and repealing Regulation N° 199/67/EEC (4), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) N° 1507/82 (5), is hereby replaced by Annex III to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="49">Article 6</p>
      <p n="50">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 January 1988.</p>
      <p n="51">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="52">Done at Brussels, 22 December 1987.</p>
      <p n="53">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="54">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="55">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="56">POR:L376UMBE05.98</p>
      <p n="57">FF: 4UEN; SETUP: 01; Hoehe: 906 mm; 155 Zeilen; 6626 Zeichen;</p>
      <p n="58">Bediener: MARL Pr.: A;</p>
      <p n="59">Kunde: L 376 engl. 05</p>
      <p n="60">(1) OJ N° L 256, 7. 9. 1987, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="61">(2) See page 1 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="62">(3) OJ N° L 370, 30. 12. 1987, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="63">(4) OJ N° L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 77.</p>
      <p n="64">(5) OJ N° L 107, 8. 5. 1968, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="65">(6) OJ N° L 207, 28. 7. 1973, p. 30.</p>
      <p n="66">(7) OJ N° L 286, 14. 11. 1969, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="67">(1) OJ N° L 265, 8. 12. 1970, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="68">(2) OJ N° L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 84.</p>
      <p n="69">(3) OJ N° L 301, 25. 10. 1986, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="70">(4) OJ N° L 337, 29. 12. 1979, p. 65.</p>
      <p n="71">(5) OJ N° L 168, 15. 6. 1982, p. 5.</p>
      <p n="72">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="73">'ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="74">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="75">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="76">'ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="77">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="78">ANNEX III</p>
      <p n="79">'ANNEX</p>
      <p n="80">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
