<TEI.2 id="jrc31987R4143-en" n="31987R4143" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31987R4143 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 4143/87 of 14 December 1987 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Republic of Mauritania on fishing off the coast of Mauritania and adopting provisions for its application</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31987R4143:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31987R4143:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31987R4143-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 4143/87 of 14 December 1987 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Republic of Mauritania on fishing off the coast of Mauritania and adopting provisions for its application</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) N° 4143/87</p>
      <p n="3">of 14 December 1987</p>
      <p n="4">concerning the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Republic of Mauritania on fishing off the coast of Mauritania and adopting provisions for its application</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Act of Accession of Spain and Portugal, and in particular Article 155 (2) (b) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Community and Mauritania have negotiated an Agreement, which was initialled on 14 May 1987, on fishing off the coast of Mauritania, which provides for fishing opportunities for fishermen from the enlarged Community in the waters over which Mauritania has sovereignty or jurisdiction;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, pursuant to Article 155 (2) (b) of the Act of Accession, the Council is required to determine the procedures appropriate to take into consideration all or part of the interests of the Canary Islands when it adopts decisions, case by case, in particular with a view to the conclusion of fisheries agreements with third countries; whereas the said procedures need to be determined in this particular case;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas it is in the Community's interest to approve this Agreement,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Islamic Republic of Mauritania on</p>
      <p n="16">fishing off the coast of Mauritania is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="17">The text of the Agreement is annexed to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">To take into consideration the interests of the Canary Islands, the Agreement and, to the extent necessary for its implementation, the provisions of the common fisheries policy on the conservation and management of fishery resources shall also apply to vessels sailing under the flag of Spain which are recorded on a permanent basis in the registers of the competent authorities at local level (registros de base) in the Canary Islands as such recording is defined in Note 6 of Annex I to Council Regulation (EEC) N° 570/86 of 24 February 1986 concerning the definition of the concept of 'originating products' and methods of administrative cooperation in the trade between the customs territory of</p>
      <p n="20">the Community, Ceuta and Melilla and the Canary Islands (3).</p>
      <p n="21">Article 3</p>
      <p n="22">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the persons empowered to sign the Agreement in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 4</p>
      <p n="24">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="26">Done at Brussels, 14 December 1987.</p>
      <p n="27">For the Council</p>
      <p n="28">The President</p>
      <p n="29">Lars P. GAMMELGAARD</p>
      <p n="30">POR:L999UMBE00.95</p>
      <p n="31">FF: 9UEN; SETUP: 01; Hoehe: 675 mm; 74 Zeilen; 3205 Zeichen;</p>
      <p n="32">Bediener: MARL Pr.: C;</p>
      <p n="33">Kunde: ................................</p>
      <p n="34">(1) OJ N° C 269, 8. 10. 1987, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="35">(2) OJ N° C 305, 16. 11. 1987.</p>
      <p n="36">(3) OJ N° L 56, 1. 3. 1986, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
