<TEI.2 id="jrc31987R1654-en" n="31987R1654" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31987R1654 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1654/87 of 12 June 1987 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2213/83 as regards the quality standards for onions</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>40 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31987R1654:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31987R1654:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31987R1654-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1654/87 of 12 June 1987 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2213/83 as regards the quality standards for onions</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1654/87</p>
      <p n="4">of 12 June 1987</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 2213/83 as regards the quality standards for onions</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72 of 18 May 1972 on the common organization of the market in fruit and vegetables (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1351/86 (2), and in particular the second subparagraph of Article 2 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3398/84 (3) introduced a derogation for a limited period from the quality standard for onions set in Annex I to Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2213/83 (4);</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the period of derogation was extended by Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2193/86 (5);</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, as a result, sufficient experience of the rules as there defined has been acquired and the quality standards for onions should now be altered on a permanent basis;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Fruit and Vegetables,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">In Annex I to Regulation (EEC) No 2213/83 the provisions of Title II, 'Provisions concerning quality', are amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. Under A, 'Minimum requirements', the first indent is replaced by:</p>
      <p n="17">'- intact,'</p>
      <p n="18">2. Under B, 'Classification':</p>
      <p n="19">(a) in (i) 'Class I', the last paragraph is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="20">'The following are, however, permitted:</p>
      <p n="21">- light staining which does not affect the last dried skin protecting the flesh, provided it does not cover more than one-fifth of the surface of the bulb,</p>
      <p n="22">- small cracks in the outer skins and the absence of part of the outer skins provided that the flesh is protected.';</p>
      <p n="23">(b) in (ii) 'Class II', the second sentence of the last paragraph is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="24">'The following, however, are permitted:</p>
      <p n="25">- staining which does not affect the last dried skin protecting the flesh provided it does not cover more than half the surface of the bulb,</p>
      <p n="26">- cracks in the outer skins and the absence of a part of the outer skins from not more than one-third of the surface of the bulb, provided the flesh remains intact.';</p>
      <p n="27">(c) in (iii) 'Class III', the following indent is added:</p>
      <p n="28">'- staining which does not affect the last dried skin protecting the flesh.'</p>
      <p n="29">Article 2</p>
      <p n="30">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 July 1987.</p>
      <p n="31">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="32">Done at Brussels, 12 June 1987.</p>
      <p n="33">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="34">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="35">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="36">(1) OJ No L 118, 20. 5. 1972, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="37">(2) OJ No L 119, 8. 5. 1986, p. 46.</p>
      <p n="38">(3) OJ No L 314, 4. 12. 1984, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="39">(4) OJ No L 213, 4. 8. 1983, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="40">(5) OJ No L 190, 12. 7. 1986, p. 57.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
