<TEI.2 id="jrc31975R2728-en" n="31975R2728" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31975R2728 English</title>
        <title>Regulation (EEC) No 2728/75 of the Council of 29 October 1975 on aids for the production of and trade in potato starch and potatoes for starch manufacture</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>22 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31975R2728:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31975R2728:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31975R2728-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Regulation (EEC) No 2728/75 of the Council of 29 October 1975 on aids for the production of and trade in potato starch and potatoes for starch manufacture</head>
      <p n="2">REGULATION (EEC) No 2728/75 OF THE COUNCIL of 29 October 1975 on aids for the production of and trade in potato starch and potatoes for starch manufacture</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 42 and 43 thereof;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission;</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Opinion of the European Parliament (1);</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the system of production refunds to be granted in respect of potato starch is governed by Council Regulation (EEC) No 2727/75 (2) of 29 October 1975 on the common organization of the market in cereals;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas operation of the system of prices and levies in respect of potato starch requires that the provisions of the Treaty which allow aids to be assessed and action to be taken against these which are incompatible with the common market be extended to aids granted for the production of and trade in potatoes for starch manufacture, without prejudice to the provisions which will be made for the common organization of the market in potatoes,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">If the system of levies on potato starch is applied, Articles 92, 93 and 94 of the Treaty shall apply to the production of and trade in potatoes for starch manufacture.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">1. Council Regulation No 56 (3) on aids for the production of and trade in potato starch and potatoes for starch manufacture, as amended by Regulation No 120/67/EEC (4), is hereby repealed.</p>
      <p n="14">2. References to the Regulation repealed by paragraph 1 shall be construed as references to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 November 1975.</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Luxembourg, 29 October 1975.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Council</p>
      <p n="20">The President</p>
      <p n="21">G. MARCORA</p>
      <p n="22">(1) Opinion delivered on 16 October 1975 (not yet published in the Official Journal). (2) See page 1 of this Official Journal. (3) OJ No 54, 2.7.1962, p. 1591/62. (4) OJ No 117, 19.6.1967, p. 2269/67.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
