<TEI.2 id="jrc21979A1101_01-en" n="21979A1101(01)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21979A1101(01) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>21 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21979A1101(01):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21979A1101(01):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21979A1101_01-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">PROTOCOL TO THE AGREEMENT ON IMPLEMENTATION OF ARTICLE VII OF THE GENERAL AGREEMENT ON TARIFFS AND TRADE</p>
      <p n="3">The Parties to the Agreement on implementation of Article VII of the General Agreement on tariffs and trade (hereinafter referred to as "the Agreement"),</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the multilateral trade negotiations and to the desire expressed by the Trade Negotiations Committee at its meeting of 11 and 12 April 1979 to arrive at a single text of an Agreement on implementation of Article VII of the General Agreement of tariffs and trade;</p>
      <p n="5">Recognizing that developing countries may have particular problems in applying the Agreement;</p>
      <p n="6">Considering that the provisions of Article 27 of the Agreement relating to amendments have not yet entered into force;</p>
      <p n="7">Hereby: I 1. Agree to the deletion of the provision of Article 1 (2) (b) (iv) of the Agreement;</p>
      <p n="8">2. Recognize that the five-year delay in the application of the provisions of the Agreement by developing countries provided for in Article 21 (1) may, in practice, be insufficient for certain developing countries. In such cases a developing country Party to the Agreement may request before the end of the period referred to in Article 21 (1) an extension of such period, it being understood that the Parties to the Agreement will give sympathetic consideration to such a request in cases where the developing country in question can show good cause;</p>
      <p n="9">3. Recognize that developing countries which currently value goods on the basis of officially established minimum values may wish to make a reservation to enable them to retain such values on a limited and transitional basis under such terms and conditions as may be agreed to by the Parties to the Agreement;</p>
      <p n="10">4. Recognize that developing countries which consider that the reversal of the sequential order at the request of the importer provided for in Article 4 of the Agreement may give rise to real difficulties for them may wish to make a reservation to Article 4 in the following terms:</p>
      <p n="11">"The Government of ... reserves the right to provide that the relevant provision of Article 4 of the Agreement shall apply only when the customs authorities agree to the request to reverse the order of Articles 5 and 6."</p>
      <p n="12">If developing countries make such a reservation, the Parties to the Agreement shall consent to it under Article 23 of the Agreement;</p>
      <p n="13">5. Recognize that developing countries may wish to make a reservation with respect to Article 5 (2) of the Agreement in the following terms:</p>
      <p n="14">"The Government of ... reserves the right to provide that Article 5 (2) of the Agreement shall be applied in accordance with the provisions of the relevant note thereto whether or not the importer so requests."</p>
      <p n="15">If developing countries make such a reservation, the Parties to the Agreement shall consent to it under Article 23 of the Agreement;</p>
      <p n="16">6. Recognize that certain developing countries have expressed concern that there may be problems in the implementation of Article 1 of the Agreement in so far as it relates to importations into their countries by sole agents, sole distributors and sole concessionaires. The Parties to the Agreement agree that, if such problems arise in practice in developing countries applying the Agreement, a study of this question shall be made, at the request of such countries, with a view to finding appropriate solutions;</p>
      <p n="17">7. Agree that Article 17 recognizes that in applying the Agreement, customs administrations may need to make enquiries concerning the truth or accuracy of any statement, document or declaration presented to them for customs valuation purposes. They further agree that the Article thus acknowledges that enquiries may be made which are, for example, aimed at verifying that the elements of value declared or presented to customs in connection with a determination of customs value are complete and correct. They recognize that Parties to the Agreement, subject to their national laws and procedures, have the right to expect the full cooperation of importers in these enquiries;</p>
      <p n="18">8. Agree that the price actually paid or payable includes all payments actually made or to be made as a condition of sale of the imported goods, by the buyer to the seller, or by the buyer to a third party to satisfy an obligation of the seller.</p>
      <p n="19">II 1. Upon the entry into force of the Agreement the provisions of this Protocol shall be deemed to be part of the Agreement.</p>
      <p n="20">2. This Protocol shall be deposited with the Director-General to the Contracting Parties to the GATT. It is open for acceptance, by signature or otherwise, by signatories of the Agreement on implementation of Article VII of the General Agreement on tariffs and trade and by other governments accepting or acceding to the Agreement pursuant to the provisions of Article 22 thereof.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Geneva this first day of November nineteen hundred and seventy-nine in a single copy in the English, French and Spanish languages, each text being authentic.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
