<TEI.2 id="jrc31979R1979-en" n="31979R1979" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979R1979 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1979/79 of 5 September 1979 amending, as regards their application by variety of Community produced tobacco, Regulations (EEC) No 1727/70, (EEC) No 1728/70, (EEC) No 2603/71, (EEC) No 638/74 and (EEC) No 410/76</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>47 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R1979:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R1979:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979R1979-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1979/79 of 5 September 1979 amending, as regards their application by variety of Community produced tobacco, Regulations (EEC) No 1727/70, (EEC) No 1728/70, (EEC) No 2603/71, (EEC) No 638/74 and (EEC) No 410/76</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1979/79 of 5 September 1979 amending, as regards their application by variety of Community produced tobacco, Regulations (EEC) No 1727/70, (EEC) No 1728/70, (EEC) No 2603/71, (EEC) No 638/74 and (EEC) No 410/76</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 727/70 of 21 April 1970 on the common organization of the market in raw tobacco (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1579/79 (2), and in particular the first subparagraph of Article 3 (3), and Articles 5 (6), 6 (10) and 7 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1697/71 of 26 July 1971 on the financing of intervention expenditure in respect of raw tobacco (3), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 330/74 (4), and in particular Article 6 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Council Regulation (EEC) No 1581/79 of 24 July 1979 fixing for the 1979 harvest the norm prices, intervention prices and premiums granted to purchasers of leaf tobacco and the derived intervention price of baled tobacco (5), amended the list of varieties of Community produced tobaccos and the definition of their reference qualities applied since the entry into force of the common organization of the market in raw tobacco in order to bring them more into line with the current reality of this market ; whereas, therefore, amendments must be made along these lines in the Regulations the provisions of which refer to the different varieties and reference qualities of tobacco namely: - Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1727/70 of 25 August 1970 on intervention procedure for raw tobacco (6), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1556/78 (7),</p>
      <p n="8">- Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1728/70 of 25 August 1970 fixing the scales of price increases and reductions for raw tobacco (8), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 784/77 (9),</p>
      <p n="9">- Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2603/71 of 6 December 1971 on detailed rules for the conclusion of contracts for first processing and market preparation of tobacco held by intervention agencies (10), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1018/79 (11),</p>
      <p n="10">- Commission Regulation (EEC) No 638/74 of 20 March 1974 fixing the maximum tolerance for quantity losses resulting from the storage of raw tobacco by intervention agencies (12),</p>
      <p n="11">- Commission Regulation (EEC) No 410/76 of 23 February 1976 fixing the maximum permissible weight losses in connection with the supervision of the first processing and market preparation of tobacco (13);</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Raw Tobacco,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Annexes I, II and IV to Regulation (EEC) No 1727/70 shall be replaced respectively by Annexes I, II and III to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">Annexes I and II to Regulation (EEC) No 1728/70 shall be replaced respectively by Annexes IV and V to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 3</p>
      <p n="19">The Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 2603/71 shall be replaced by Annex VI to this Regulation. (1)OJ No L 94, 28.4.1970, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 189, 27.7.1979, p. 1. (3)OJ No L 175, 4.8.1971, p. 8. (4)OJ No L 37, 9.2.1974, p. 5. (5)OJ No L 189, 27.7.1979, p. 6. (6)OJ No L 191, 27.8.1970, p. 5. (7)OJ No L 184, 6.7.1978, p. 11. (8)OJ No L 191, 27.8.1970, p. 18. (9)OJ No L 95, 19.4.1977, p. 16. (10)OJ No L 269, 8.12.1971, p. 11. (11)OJ No L 127, 24.5.1979, p. 11. (12)OJ No L 77, 22.3.1974, p. 30. (13)OJ No L 50, 26.2.1976, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 4</p>
      <p n="21">The Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 638/74 shall be replaced by Annex VII to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 5</p>
      <p n="23">The Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 410/76 shall be replaced by Annex VIII to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="24">Article 6</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="26">It shall be applicable for the first time to raw tobacco from the 1979 harvest.</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 5 September 1979.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">Finn GUNDELACH</p>
      <p n="31">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="32">ANNEX I QUALITY CLASSIFICATION OF LEAF TOBACCO VARIETIES Provided for in Article 7 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 1727/70</p>
      <p n="33">&gt;PIC FILE= "T9001121"&gt; &gt;PIC FILE= "T9001122"&gt; &gt;PIC FILE= "T9001123"&gt; &gt;PIC FILE= "T9001124"&gt; &gt;PIC FILE= "T9001125"&gt;</p>
      <p n="34">ANNEX II QUALITY CLASSIFICATION OF BALED TOBACCO provided for in Article 7 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 1727/70</p>
      <p n="35">&gt;PIC FILE= "T9001126"&gt; &gt;PIC FILE= "T9001127"&gt; &gt;PIC FILE= "T9001128"&gt;</p>
      <p n="36">ANNEX III Moisture to be taken into consideration when determining the net weight referred to in Article 6 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 1727/70</p>
      <p n="37">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0010620"&gt;</p>
      <p n="38">ANNEX IV</p>
      <p n="39">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0010621"&gt;</p>
      <p n="40">ANNEX V Scales of price increases and reductions for baled tobacco referred to in Article 1 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 1728/70 Price increases and reductions in relation to classification categories</p>
      <p n="41">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0010622"&gt;</p>
      <p n="42">ANNEX VI Amount referred to in Article 6 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 327/71</p>
      <p n="43">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0010623"&gt;</p>
      <p n="44">ANNEX VII Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 638/74 Tolerance limits as a percentage of the net weight</p>
      <p n="45">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0010624"&gt;</p>
      <p n="46">ANNEX VIII Maximum rate of weight losses referred to in Article 1 of Regulation (EEC) No 410/76</p>
      <p n="47">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0010625"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
