<TEI.2 id="jrc31979R2764-en" n="31979R2764" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979R2764 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 2764/79 of 6 December 1979 amending Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 300/76 determining the categories of officials entitled to allowances for shiftwork, and the rates and conditions thereof</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R2764:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R2764:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979R2764-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 2764/79 of 6 December 1979 amending Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 300/76 determining the categories of officials entitled to allowances for shiftwork, and the rates and conditions thereof</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (ECSC, EEC, EURATOM) No 2764/79 of 6 December 1979 amending Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 300/76 determining the categories of officials entitled to allowances for shiftwork, and the rates and conditions thereof</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 259/68 laying down the Staff Regulations of officials and conditions of employment of other servants of the European Communities (1), as last amended by Regulation (Euratom, ECSC, EEC) No 3085/78 (2), and in particular the second paragraph of Article 56a of the Staff Regulations,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission, submitted after consulting the Staff Regulations Committee,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas it is for the Council, acting on a proposal from the Commission submitted after consulting the Staff Regulations Committee, to determine the categories of officials entitled to allowances for shiftwork, and the rates and conditions thereof;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas staff employed in certain telex services do shiftwork within the meaning of Article 56a of the Staff Regulations ; whereas Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 300/76 (3) should be correspondingly amended,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">In Article 1 (1) of Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 300/76 the text of the part of the first subparagraph preceding the indents shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="11">"1. An official paid from research and investment appropriations and employed in an establishment of the Joint Research Centre or in indirect action, or paid from operating appropriations and employed in a computer centre, a security department or a telex service, who is engaged in shiftwork within the meaning of Article 56a of the Staff Regulations, shall be entitled to an allowance of:"</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">It shall apply from 1 January 1980.</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 6 December 1979.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">L. PRETI (1)OJ No L 56, 4.3.1968, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 369, 29.12.1978, p. 6. (3)OJ No L 38, 13.2.1976, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
