<TEI.2 id="jrc31979D0195-en" n="31979D0195" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979D0195 English</title>
        <title>79/195/EEC: Council Decision of 21 December 1978 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community, the Member States and the International Development Association</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>18 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979D0195:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979D0195:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979D0195-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">79/195/EEC: Council Decision of 21 December 1978 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community, the Member States and the International Development Association</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 21 December 1978 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community, the Member States and the International Development Association (79/195/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Member States, on the one hand, and the International Development Association, on the other hand, signed in Brussels on 2 May 1978, should be concluded,</p>
      <p n="7">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="8">Article 1</p>
      <p n="9">The Agreement between the European Economic Community, the Member States and the International Development Association is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="10">The text of the Agreement shall be attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">Approval of the Agreement shall be notified in accordance with Section 2 of Article V of the said Agreement (1).</p>
      <p n="13">Article 3</p>
      <p n="14">This Decision shall be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 21 December 1978.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Council</p>
      <p n="17">The President</p>
      <p n="18">Otto Graf LAMBSDORFF (1)This Agreement entered into force, in accordance with Title V, Article 3 thereof, on 1 January 1979.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
