<TEI.2 id="jrc31979R0546-en" n="31979R0546" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979R0546 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 546/79 of 22 March 1979 making the importation of embroidered household linen from Singapore and Malaysia subject to production of a certificate of origin</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R0546:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R0546:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979R0546-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 546/79 of 22 March 1979 making the importation of embroidered household linen from Singapore and Malaysia subject to production of a certificate of origin</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 546/79 of 22 March 1979 making the importation of embroidered household linen from Singapore and Malaysia subject to production of a certificate of origin</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 3059/78 of 21 December 1978 on common rules for imports of certain textile products originating in third countries (1), and in particular Article 2 (2) and Article 3 (4) of Annex III thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the origin of the products of Groups I and II listed in Annex I to Regulation (EEC) No 3059/78 is established by production of a certificate of origin ; whereas for products of Groups III to VI this may be established by a declaration of origin on the invoice or another commercial document relating to the products;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas it has been discovered that irregularities have taken place as regards imports of embroidered household linen (CCT subheading 62.02 B, category 39) from Singapore and Malaysia;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the Committee on Origin has examined, in accordance with the procedure laid down in the abovementioned Regulation, whether it is desirable to require the production of a certificate in respect of the products and the supplying countries concerned;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Committee on Origin,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">Imports into the Community of embroidered woven table linen, toilet and kitchen linen other than of cotton terry fabric, falling within subheading ex 62.02 B of the Common Customs Tariff (NIMEXE codes 62.02-41, 43, 47, 65, 73, 77), from Singapore and Malaysia, shall be accompanied by a certificate of origin conforming to the specimen given in Annex VI to Regulation (EEC) No 3059/78.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 45th day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 22 March 1979.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="18">Étienne DAVIGNON</p>
      <p n="19">Member of the Commission (1)OJ No L 365, 27.12.1978, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
