<TEI.2 id="jrc31979R2829-en" n="31979R2829" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979R2829 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2829/79 of 14 December 1979 amending Regulation (EEC) No 1963/79 laying down detailed rules for the application of the production refund on olive oil used in the manufacture of certain preserved foods</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>22 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R2829:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R2829:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979R2829-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2829/79 of 14 December 1979 amending Regulation (EEC) No 1963/79 laying down detailed rules for the application of the production refund on olive oil used in the manufacture of certain preserved foods</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 2829/79 of 14 December 1979 amending Regulation (EEC) No 1963/79 laying down detailed rules for the application of the production refund on olive oil used in the manufacture of certain preserved foods</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation No 136/66/EEC of 22 September 1966 on the establishment of a common organization of the market in oils and fats (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 590/79 (2),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 591/79 of 26 March 1979 laying down general rules concerning the production refund for olive oils used in the manufacture of certain preserved foods (3), and in particular Article 9 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 2 (1) of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1963/79 (4) provides that requests for the verification of oil must be submitted to the competent authority not later than five working days before the date envisaged for the commencement of the manufacture of the preserved foods in which it is to be used;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the object of this fixed period is to permit verification of the stock of olive oil by the competent authority ; whereas, since methods of carrying out this administrative check differ from one Member State to another, the Member States should themselves set the period which is necessary for them to carry out the check in question;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Oils and Fats,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 1963/79 is amended to read as follows:</p>
      <p n="13">"1. In order to qualify for the production refund, the manufacturer must submit a request for verification to the competent authority before the date envisaged for the commencement of manufacturing operations.</p>
      <p n="14">Such a request may not be submitted until the oil is in the manufacturing premises.</p>
      <p n="15">The Member State concerned shall, if necessary, specify a minimum period which must elapse between the submission of the request for verification and the date specified in the first subparagraph."</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 14 December 1979.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Finn GUNDELACH</p>
      <p n="22">Vice-President (1)OJ No 172, 30.9.1966, p. 3025/66. (2)OJ No L 78, 30.3.1979, p. 1. (3)OJ No L 78, 30.3.1979, p. 2. (4)OJ No L 227, 7.9.1979, p. 10.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
