<TEI.2 id="jrc31979D0491-en" n="31979D0491" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979D0491 English</title>
        <title>79/491/EEC: Commission Decision of 17 May 1979 laying down a code and standard rules for the transcription into a machine-readable form of the data of the basic surveys of areas under vines</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>53 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979D0491:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979D0491:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979D0491-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">79/491/EEC: Commission Decision of 17 May 1979 laying down a code and standard rules for the transcription into a machine-readable form of the data of the basic surveys of areas under vines</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 17 May 1979 laying down a code and standard rules for the transcription into a machine-readable form of the data of the basic surveys of areas under vines (79/491/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 of 5 February 1979 on statistical surveys of areas under vines (1), and in particular Article 4 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Article 4 (4) of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 provides that Member States which process the results of their basic surveys electronically shall submit the results in a machine-readable form;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the equipment which the Commission has available for analyzing the results of the statistical surveys of the areas under vines and the need for its rational use require that a standard format be prescribed for the transcription of the data into a machine-readable form to be determined in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 8 of the said Regulation;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The machine-readable form for submission of the data provided for in Articles 2 and 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 by those Member States which process their survey results electronically shall be magnetic tape.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">The codes and rules governing the transcription on to magnetic tape of the data provided for in Article 2 of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 shall be as set out in the Annexes hereto.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 17 May 1979.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="18">François-Xavier ORTOLI</p>
      <p n="19">Vice-President (1)OJ No L 54, 5.3.1979, p. 124.</p>
      <p n="20">ANNEX I MAGNETIC TAPE SPECIFICATION FOR THE DELIVERY TO EUROSTAT OF THE DATA OF THE BASIC SURVEYS OF THE AREAS UNDER VINES (Council Regulation (EEC) No 357/79)</p>
      <p n="21">GENERAL PROVISIONS</p>
      <p n="22">I. The information recorded in accordance with the characteristics referred to in Article 2 of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 is to be delivered to Eurostat in the following form by those Member States which process their survey information electronically: 1. The information shall refer to summaries of holdings if the survey is exhaustive (or to raised summaries of holdings if the survey is based on random sampling) and not to individual holdings.</p>
      <p n="23">2. The information shall be delivered on nine-track magnetic tape / 1 600 BPI (630 bytes/cm) standard label.</p>
      <p n="24">3. The information shall be of fixed record length consisting of 308 positions, and shall be recorded in EBCDIC.</p>
      <p n="25">4. The first two fields of each record shall contain information to permit identification. The first field (three positions) identifies the geographical unit, the codification of which is given in the detailed provisions and in Annex II.</p>
      <p n="26">5. The second field (two positions) identifies the table in the schedule of tables provided for in Council Regulation (EEC) No 357/79. The codification of these tables is given in the detailed provisions.</p>
      <p n="27">6. The number and size of the fields in each record vary according to the table. If all the 308 positions are not filled in the case of certain tables, the record shall be completed by blanks.</p>
      <p n="28">7. The information shall be entered right justified in each field.</p>
      <p n="29">8. Surface area data shall be given in ha to two decimal places with a virtual point.</p>
      <p n="30">9. Member States shall have a choice as to blocking factor and Eurostat must be informed as to what blocking factor has been used.</p>
      <p n="31">10. The records shall be sorted according to geographical unit, table, and size classes or variety, in that order.</p>
      <p n="32">11. Standard administrative procedures governing the transmission of the magnetic tape files to Eurostat shall be established jointly by Eurostat and the Member States.</p>
      <p n="33">II. The following pages give for each table and for the various items of a record: (a) the codes which are to be used;</p>
      <p n="34">(b) the maximum number of digits required for the item in question;</p>
      <p n="35">(c) the consecutive numbering of the positions for the various items.</p>
      <p n="36">DETAILED PROVISIONS</p>
      <p n="37">The first two fields of each record contain the following information: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0014699"&gt;</p>
      <p n="38">The following list gives the record specifications by tables: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0014700"&gt;</p>
      <p n="39">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014701"&gt;</p>
      <p n="40">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014702"&gt;</p>
      <p n="41">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014703"&gt;</p>
      <p n="42">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014704"&gt;</p>
      <p n="43">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014705"&gt;</p>
      <p n="44">The zones for each variety in the record must always be completed by zeros when all the classes are not used.</p>
      <p n="45">If there is only one variety (or two varieties) in the last record, the information relating to the missing variety (varieties) is to be indicated by zeros (bytes 107-308, or 208-308).</p>
      <p n="46">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014706"&gt;</p>
      <p n="47">ANNEX II GEOGRAPHICAL UNITS PROVIDED FOR IN ARTICLE 4 (3) OF COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 357/79</p>
      <p n="48">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014707"&gt;</p>
      <p n="49">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014708"&gt;</p>
      <p n="50">ANNEX III CODES FOR SPECIFIED VARIETIES OF WINE GRAPES FOR THE TRANSMISSION TO EUROSTAT OF THE RESULTS OF THE STATISTICAL SURVEYS OF THE AREAS UNDER VINES (Council Regulation (EEC) No 357/79)</p>
      <p n="51">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014709"&gt;</p>
      <p n="52">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0014710"&gt;</p>
      <p n="53">Member states shall specify the code of the varieties on the transmission documents.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
