<TEI.2 id="jrc31979R0936-en" n="31979R0936" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31979R0936 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 936/79 of 11 May 1979 on the classification of meat of bovine animals under subheading 02.01 A II a) 4 aa) of the Common Customs Tariff</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R0936:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31979R0936:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31979R0936-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 936/79 of 11 May 1979 on the classification of meat of bovine animals under subheading 02.01 A II a) 4 aa) of the Common Customs Tariff</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 936/79 of 11 May 1979 on the classification of meat of bovine animals under subheading 02.01 A II a) 4 aa) of the Common Customs Tariff</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 97/69 of 16 January 1969 on measures to be taken for uniform application of the nomenclature of the Common Customs Tariff (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 280/77 (2), and in particular Article 3 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, in order to ensure uniform application of the nomenclature of the Common Customs Tariff, provisions must be laid down concerning the tariff classification of separated forequarters of bovine animals, in a fresh or chilled state, from which the atlas bone has been removed;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas subheading 02.01 A II a) 4 aa) of the Common Customs Tariff annexed to Council Regulation (EEC) No 950/68 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 882/79 (4), refers to meat of bovine animals, fresh or chilled, unboned (bone-in);</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Note 1 A e) to Chapter 2 of the Common Customs Tariff precisely defines separated forequarters, indicating in particular that they are the front part of a half-carcass comprising all the bones ; whereas such products which do not include the atlas bone cannot therefore be considered to be separated forequarters;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the products in question are to be classified as meat of bovine animals, fresh or chilled, other, unboned (bone-in) under subheading 02.01 A II a) 4 aa);</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the measures proved for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Committee on Common Customs Tariff Nomenclature,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">Separated forequarters of bovine animals in a fresh or chilled state, from which the atlas bone has been removed, fall to be classified under the following subheading of the Common Customs Tariff:</p>
      <p n="14">02.01 Meat and edible offals of the animals falling within heading No 01.01, 01.02, 01.03 or 01.04, fresh, chilled or frozen:</p>
      <p n="15">A. Meat:</p>
      <p n="16">II. Of bone animals:</p>
      <p n="17">a) Fresh or chilled:</p>
      <p n="18">4. Other:</p>
      <p n="19">aa) Unboned (bone-in)</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 21st day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Brussels, 11 May 1979.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">Étienne DAVIGNON</p>
      <p n="26">Member of the Commission (1)OJ No L 14, 21.1.1969, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 40, 11.2.1977, p. 1. (3)OJ No L 172, 22.7.1968, p. 1. (4)OJ No L 111, 4.5.1979, p. 14.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
