<TEI.2 id="jrc31972L0275-en" n="31972L0275" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31972L0275 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 72/275/EEC of 20 July 1972 amending the Directive on the introduction of Community methods of sampling and analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31972L0275:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31972L0275:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31972L0275-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 72/275/EEC of 20 July 1972 amending the Directive on the introduction of Community methods of sampling and analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DIRECTIVE of 20 July 1972 amending the Directive on the introduction of Community methods of sampling and analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs (72/275/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 43 and 100 thereof;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission;</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Opinion of the European Parliament;</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Opinion of the Economic and Social Committee;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Article 4 of the Council Directive of 20 July 1970 1 on the introduction of Community methods of sampling and analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs provides that the procedure for this introduction laid down in Article 3 of that Directive must terminate within eighteen months following the date on which a matter is first referred to the Standing Committee for Feedingstuffs either under Article 3 (1) or under any other corresponding provision;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas two draft Commission Directives were first placed before the Committee at its meeting on 15 and 16 December 1970 ; whereas, therefore, this procedure should have terminated on 16 June 1972;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, however, this procedure has proved entirely satisfactory in the past and should therefore be retained beyond the period originally set;</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">Article 4 of the Council Directive of 20 July 1970 is hereby repealed with effect from 16 June 1972.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 20 July 1972.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">T. WESTERTERP 1OJ No L 170, 3.8.1970, p. 2.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
