<TEI.2 id="jrc31972D0279-en" n="31972D0279" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31972D0279 English</title>
        <title>72/279/EEC: Council Decision of 31 July 1972 setting up a Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>18 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31972D0279:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31972D0279:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31972D0279-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">72/279/EEC: Council Decision of 31 July 1972 setting up a Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 31 July 1972 setting up a Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics (72/279/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the draft decision submitted by the Commission;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, for the purpose of facilitating their implementation, provision is made in acts adopted by the Council relating to agricultural statistics for a procedure establishing close cooperation between Member States and the Commission ; whereas, in order to achieve such cooperation, a Committee should be set up to carry out the duties assigned to it by such acts;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas it is desirable that this Committee should consider any other question arising in connection with such acts,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">A Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics (hereinafter called the "Committee") is hereby set up ; it shall consist of representatives of the Member States with a representative of the Commission as Chairman.</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">The Committee shall carry out the duties assigned to it by the provisions adopted by the Council in the field of agricultural statistics in the cases and under the conditions provided for therein. It may, moreover, consider any other question arising in connection with such provisions and referred to it by the Chairman either on his own initiative or at the request of a Member State.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 3</p>
      <p n="14">The Committee shall adopt its own rules of procedure.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 31 July 1972.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Council</p>
      <p n="17">The President</p>
      <p n="18">T. WESTERTERP</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
