<TEI.2 id="jrc31993L0056-en" n="31993L0056" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993L0056 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 93/56/EEC of 29 June 1993 amending Council Directive 82/471/EEC concerning certain products used in animal nutrition</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993L0056:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993L0056:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993L0056-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 93/56/EEC of 29 June 1993 amending Council Directive 82/471/EEC concerning certain products used in animal nutrition</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE 93/56/EEC of 29 June 1993 amending Council Directive 82/471/EEC concerning certain products used in animal nutrition</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 82/471/EEC of 30 June 1982 concerning certain products used in animal nutrition (1), as last amended by Commission Directive 93/26/EEC (2), and in particular Article 6 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Directive 82/471/EEC provides for the content of the Annexes to be regularly adapted to take account of advances in scientific and technical knowledge;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the study of the non-protein nitrogenous compound 'ammonium sulfate' and of hydroxyanalogue of methionine and its calcium salt has permitted a beneficial effect in ruminants to be established; whereas authorization for the use of the products in question should therefore be extended to this category of animal;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the Standing Committee on Feedingstuffs,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The Annex to Directive 82/471/EEC is hereby amended as set out in the Annex to this Directive.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations or administrative provisions necessary to comply with Article 1 by 30 June 1994 at the latest. They shall immediately inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="14">When Member States adopt these provisions, these shall contain a reference to this Directive or shall be accompanied by such reference at the time of their official publication. The procedure for such reference shall be adopted by Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 29 June 1993.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="20">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ No L 213, 21. 7. 1982, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) OJ No L 179, 22. 7. 1993, p. 2.</p>
      <p n="23">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="24">1. In group 2, 'Non-protein nitrogenous compounds', under point 2.2, 'Ammonium salts', the following product is added:</p>
      <p n="25">/* Tables: see OJ */</p>
      <p n="26">'Hydroxy analogue of methionine' and 4.1.2, 'Calcium salt of hydroxyanalogue of methionine'.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
