<TEI.2 id="jrc31993R2090-en" n="31993R2090" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993R2090 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2090/93 of 27 July 1993 amending Regulation (EEC) No 563/82 laying down detailed rules for the application of Regulation (EEC) No 1208/81 for establishing the market prices of adult bovine animals on the basis of the Community scale for the classification of carcases</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>28 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993R2090:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993R2090:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993R2090-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2090/93 of 27 July 1993 amending Regulation (EEC) No 563/82 laying down detailed rules for the application of Regulation (EEC) No 1208/81 for establishing the market prices of adult bovine animals on the basis of the Community scale for the classification of carcases</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 2090/93 of 27 July 1993 amending Regulation (EEC) No 563/82 laying down detailed rules for the application of Regulation (EEC) No 1208/81 for establishing the market prices of adult bovine animals on the basis of the Community scale for the classification of carcases</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 805/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in beef and veal (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 125/93 (2),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1208/81 of 28 April 1981 determining the Community scale for the classification of carcases of adult bovine animals (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1026/91 (4), and in particular Article 2 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 1 (3) of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 563/82 (5), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3402/85 (6), fixes the corrective factors applicable to carcase weights when carcase presentation differs from the reference presentation; whereas, for certain degrees of fat cover, the corrective factors relating to the removal of external fat should be adjusted in order to bring them more into line with practice; whereas, also, the methods for calculating such corrective factors should be specified according to whether they are identical in all Member States or differ from one slaugterhouse to another;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Beef and Veal,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Regulation (EEC) No 563/92 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="12">1. The following paragraph is added to Article 1:</p>
      <p n="13">'4. Where the adjustments referred to in the previous paragraph are the same throughout the territory of a Member State they shall be calculated on a national basis; where such adjustments vary from one slaughterhouse to another, they shall be calculated individually.'</p>
      <p n="14">2. In the Annex, the corrective factors laid down for the removal of external fat of fat classes 3 and 4 are replaced by the percentage increases +2 and +3 respectively.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="17">It shall apply from 1 September 1993.</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 27 July 1993.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="22">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ No L 18, 27. 1. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="25">(3) OJ No L 123, 7. 5. 1981, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="26">(4) OJ No L 106, 26. 4. 1991, p. 2.</p>
      <p n="27">(5) OJ No L 67, 11. 3. 1982, p. 23.</p>
      <p n="28">(6) OJ No L 322, 3. 12. 1985, p. 14.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
