<TEI.2 id="jrc31993D0623-en" n="31993D0623" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993D0623 English</title>
        <title>93/623/EEC: Commission Decision of 20 October 1993 establishing the identification document (passport) accompanying registered equidae</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>149 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0623:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0623:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993D0623-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">93/623/EEC: Commission Decision of 20 October 1993 establishing the identification document (passport) accompanying registered equidae</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 20 October 1993 establishing the identification document (passport) accompanying registered equidae (93/623/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 90/427/EEC of 26 June 1990 on the zootechnical and genealogical conditions governing intra-Community trade in equidae (1), and in particular the first subparagraph of Article 8 (1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas an identification document accompanying registered equidae must permit the origin of the animals to be traced and must contain all details of the pedigrees of equidae;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas on 26 June 1990 the Council adopted Directive 90/426/EEC on animal health conditions governing the movement and import from third countries of equidae (2), as last amended by Directive 92/36/EEC (3), whereas, in accordance with that Directive, special health certificates have been drawn up for imports of registered horses; whereas such certificates refer to the identification document (passport);</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, pursuant to Directive 90/426/EEC, the identification document is to be issued by the breeding authority or any other competent authority of the country of origin of the animal which manages the studbook or register for that breed of animal or any international association or organization which manages horses for competition or racing; whereas the identification document must contain certain information on health affording a guarantee of the health status of equidae;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, with a view to ensuring that registered equidae are identified and that all health information necessary is available, in particular as regards vaccinations and laboratory examinations, an identification document should be established;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Zootechnics,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">Identifications documents accompanying registered equidae must be in conformity with the provisions of the Annex.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">Identification documents as referred to in Article 1:</p>
      <p n="16">- may accompany registered equidae born before 1 January 1998,</p>
      <p n="17">- must accompany registered equidae born on or after 1 January 1998.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 3</p>
      <p n="19">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 20 October 1993.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="23">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ No L 224, 18. 8. 1990, p. 55.</p>
      <p n="25">(2) OJ No L 224, 18. 8. 1990, p. 42.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) OJ No L 157, 10. 6. 1992, p. 28.</p>
      <p n="27">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="28">IDENTIFICATION DOCUMENT FOR REGISTERED EQUIDAE PASSPORT General - Instructions</p>
      <p n="29">I. Passports must contain all instructions needed for their use and the details of the competent authority which issued them.</p>
      <p n="30">II. Information shown on passports</p>
      <p n="31">A. Passports must contain the following information:</p>
      <p n="32">1. Section I:</p>
      <p n="33">Owner</p>
      <p n="34">The name of the owner or his agent must be stated.</p>
      <p n="35">2. Sections II and III:</p>
      <p n="36">Identification</p>
      <p n="37">The equid must be identified by the competent authority.</p>
      <p n="38">3. Section IV:</p>
      <p n="39">Recording of identity checks</p>
      <p n="40">Whenever laws and regulations so require, checks conducted on the identity of the equid must be recorded by the competent authority.</p>
      <p n="41">4. Sections V and VI:</p>
      <p n="42">Vaccination record</p>
      <p n="43">All vaccinations must be recorded in Section V (equine influenza only) and in Section VI (all other vaccinations).</p>
      <p n="44">5. Section VII:</p>
      <p n="45">Laboratory health tests</p>
      <p n="46">The results of all tests carried out to detect transmissible diseases must be recorded.</p>
      <p n="47">B. Passports may contain the following information:</p>
      <p n="48">Section VIII:</p>
      <p n="49">Basic health requirements</p>
      <p n="50">Section VIII states the basic health requirements.</p>
      <p n="51">It lists the diseases which must be noted on the health certificate.</p>
      <p n="52">SECTION I Détails de droit de propriété</p>
      <p n="53">1. Pour les compétitions, la nationalité du cheval est celle de son propriétaire.</p>
      <p n="54">2. En cas de changement de propriétaire, le passeport doit être immédiatement déposé auprès de l'organisation, l'association ou le service officiel l'ayant délivré avec le nom et l'adresse du nouveau propriétaire afin de le lui transmettre après réenregistrement.</p>
      <p n="55">3. S'il y a plus d'un propriétaire ou si le cheval appartient à une société, le nom de la personne responsable pour le cheval doit être inscrit dans le passeport ainsi que sa nationalité. Si les propriétaires sont de nationalités différentes, ils doivent préciser la nationalité du cheval.</p>
      <p n="56">4. Lorsque la Fédération équestre internationale approuve la location d'un cheval par une Fédération équestre nationale, les détails de ces transactions doivent être enregistrés par la Fédération équestre nationale intéressée. Details of ownership</p>
      <p n="57">1. For competitive purposes, the nationality of the horse is that of its owner.</p>
      <p n="58">2. On change of ownership the passport must immediately be lodged with the issuing organization, association or official agency, giving the name and address of the new owner, for re-registration and forwarding to the new owner.</p>
      <p n="59">3. If there is more than one owner or the horse is owned by a company, then the name of the individual responsible for the horse must be entered in the passport together with his nationality. If the owners are of different nationalties, they have to determine the nationality of the horse.</p>
      <p n="60">4. When the Fédération équestre internationale approves the leasing of a horse by a national equestrian federation, the details of these transactions must be recorded by the national equestrian federation concerned.</p>
      <p n="61">SECTION II (1) No d'identification:</p>
      <p n="62">Identification No:</p>
      <p n="63">(2) Nom: Name: (3) Sexe: Sex: (4) Robe: Colour:</p>
      <p n="64">(5) Race:</p>
      <p n="65">Breed:</p>
      <p n="66">(6) par: by: (7 a) et: and:</p>
      <p n="67">(7 b) par: by:</p>
      <p n="68">(8) Date de naissance:</p>
      <p n="69">Date of foaling:</p>
      <p n="70">(9) Lieu d'élevage:</p>
      <p n="71">Place where bred:</p>
      <p n="72">(10) Naisseur(s):</p>
      <p n="73">Breeder(s):</p>
      <p n="74">(11) Certificat d'origine validé le:</p>
      <p n="75">par:</p>
      <p n="76">Origin certificate validated on:</p>
      <p n="77">by:</p>
      <p n="78">- Nom de l'autorité compétente:</p>
      <p n="79">Name of the competent authority</p>
      <p n="80">- Adresse:</p>
      <p n="81">Address</p>
      <p n="82">- No de téléphone:</p>
      <p n="83">Telephone No:</p>
      <p n="84">- No de télécopie:</p>
      <p n="85">Fax number:</p>
      <p n="86">- Signature:</p>
      <p n="87">(nom en lettres capitales et qualité du signataire)</p>
      <p n="88">Signature:</p>
      <p n="89">(Name in capital letters and capacity of signatory)</p>
      <p n="90">- Cachet</p>
      <p n="91">Stamp</p>
      <p n="92">SECTION III (2) Nom - Name: (5) Race - Breed: (3) Sexe - Sex: (4) Robe - Colour:</p>
      <p n="93">(19) Signalement relevé sous la mère par:</p>
      <p n="94">Description taken with dam by:</p>
      <p n="95">Tête:</p>
      <p n="96">Head:</p>
      <p n="97">Ant. G:</p>
      <p n="98">Foreleg L:</p>
      <p n="99">Ant. D:</p>
      <p n="100">Foreleg R:</p>
      <p n="101">Post G:</p>
      <p n="102">Hindleg L:</p>
      <p n="103">Post D:</p>
      <p n="104">Hindleg R:</p>
      <p n="105">Corps:</p>
      <p n="106">Body:</p>
      <p n="107">Marques:</p>
      <p n="108">Markings:</p>
      <p n="109">Le:</p>
      <p n="110">On:</p>
      <p n="111">(20) Circonscription:</p>
      <p n="112">District:</p>
      <p n="113">(21) Signature et cachet du vétérinaire agréé</p>
      <p n="114">(ou de l'autorité compétente)</p>
      <p n="115">Signature and stamp of qualified veterinary surgeon</p>
      <p n="116">(or competent authority)</p>
      <p n="117">(en lettres capitales)</p>
      <p n="118">(in capital letters)</p>
      <p n="119">SECTION IV Contrôles d'identité du cheval décrit dans ce passeport</p>
      <p n="120">L'identité du cheval doit être contrôlée chaque fois que les lois et règlements l'exigent: signer cette page signifie que le signalement du cheval présenté est conforme à celui de la page du signalement. Identification of the horse described in this passport</p>
      <p n="121">The identity of the horse must be checked each time this is required by rules and regulations and certified that it conforms with the description given on the diagram page of its passport.</p>
      <p n="122">SECTION V Grippe équine seulement</p>
      <p n="123">Enregistrement des vaccinations</p>
      <p n="124">Toute vaccination subie par le cheval doit être portée dans le cadre ci-dessous de façon lisible et précise avec le nom et la signature du vétérinaire. Equine influenza only</p>
      <p n="125">Vaccination record</p>
      <p n="126">Details of every vaccination which the horse undergoes must be entered clearly and in detail, and certified with the name and signature of veterinarian.</p>
      <p n="127">SECTION VI Maladies autres que la grippe équine</p>
      <p n="128">Enregistrement des vaccinations</p>
      <p n="129">Toute vaccination subie par le cheval doit être portée dans le cadre ci-dessous de façon lisible et précise avec le nom et la signature du vétérinaire. Diseases other than equine influenza</p>
      <p n="130">Vaccination record</p>
      <p n="131">Details of every vaccination which the horse undergoes must be entered clearly and in detail, and certified with the name and signature of veterinarian.</p>
      <p n="132">SECTION VII Contrôles sanitaires effectués par des laboratoires</p>
      <p n="133">Le résultat de tout contrôle effectué par un vétérinaire pour une maladie transmissible ou par un laboratoire agréé par le service vétérinaire gouvernemental du pays doit être noté clairement et en détails par le vétérinaire qui représente l'autorité demandant le contrôle. Laboratory health test</p>
      <p n="134">The result of every test carried out for a transmissible disease by a veterinarian or a laboratory authorized by the government veterinary service of the country must be entered clearly and in detail by the veterinarian acting on behalf of the authority requesting the test.</p>
      <p n="135">SECTION VIII Exigences sanitaires de base Les exigences ne sont pas valables pour l'introduction dans la Communauté Basic health requirements These requirements are not valid to enter the Community Je soussigné (1) certifie que l'équidé décrit dans le passeport no .................... délivré par satisfait aux conditions suivantes:</p>
      <p n="136">I, the undersigned (1), hereby certify that the equid described in passport No .................... issued by satisfies the following conditions:</p>
      <p n="137">(a) il a été examiné ce jour, ne présente aucun signe clinique de maladie et est apte au transport;</p>
      <p n="138">it has been examined this day, presents no clinical sign of disease and is fit for transport;</p>
      <p n="139">(b) il n'est pas destiné à l'abattage dans le cadre d'un programme national d'éradication d'une maladie transmissible;</p>
      <p n="140">it is not intended for slaughter under a national eradication programme for a transmissible disease;</p>
      <p n="141">(c) il ne provient pas d'une exploitation faisant l'objet de mesures de restriction pour des motifs de police sanitaire et n'a pas été en contact avec des équidés d'une telle exploitation;</p>
      <p n="142">it does not come from a holding subject to restrictions for animal health reasons and has not been in contact with equidae on such a holding;</p>
      <p n="143">(d) à ma connaissance, il n'a pas été en contact avec des équidés atteints d'une maladie transmissible au cours des 15 jours précédant l'embarquement.</p>
      <p n="144">to the best of my knowledge, it has not been in contact with equidae affected by a transmissible disease during the 15 days prior to loading.</p>
      <p n="145">LA PRÉSENTE CERTIFICATION EST VALABLE 10 JOURS À COMPTER DE LA DATE DE SA SIGNATURE PAR LE VÉTÉRINAIRE OFFICIEL.</p>
      <p n="146">THIS CERTIFICATION IS VALID FOR 10 DAYS FROM THE DATE OF SIGNATURE BY THE OFFICIAL VETERINARIAN.</p>
      <p n="147">"" ID="3"&gt;Oui/non (barrer la mention inutile) Yes/no (delete as appropriate)"&gt; ID="3"&gt;Oui/non (barrer la mention inutile) Yes/no (delete as appropriate)"&gt; ID="3"&gt;Oui/non (barrer la mention inutile) Yes/no (delete as appropriate)"&gt; ID="3"&gt;Oui/non (barrer la mention inutile) Yes/no (delete as appropriate)"&gt; ID="3"&gt;Oui/non (barrer la mention inutile) Yes/no (delete as appropriate)"&gt; ID="3"&gt;Oui/non (barrer la mention inutile) Yes/no (delete as appropriate) "&gt;</p>
      <p n="148">Maladies dont l'inclusion dans le certificat zoosanitaire joint au passeport doit être envisagée Diseases for which an endorsement must be made on the health certificate attached to the passport 1. Peste équine - African horse sickness 2. Stomatite vésiculeuse - vesicular stomatitis 3. Dourine - dourine 4. Morve - glanders 5. Encéphalomyélites équines (tous types) - equine encephalomyelitis (all types) 6. Anémie infectieuse - infectious anaemia 7. Rage - rabies 8. Fièvre charbonneuse - anthrax</p>
      <p n="149">(1) Ce document doit être signé dans les 48 heures précédant le déplacement international de l'équidé. (2) This document must be signed within 48 hours prior to international transport of the equid.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
