<TEI.2 id="jrc31993D0590-en" n="31993D0590" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993D0590 English</title>
        <title>93/590/EC: Commission Decision of 5 November 1993 for the purchase by the Community of foot-and-mouth disease antigens within the framework of the Community action concerning reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>45 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0590:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0590:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993D0590-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">93/590/EC: Commission Decision of 5 November 1993 for the purchase by the Community of foot-and-mouth disease antigens within the framework of the Community action concerning reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 5 November 1993 for the purchase by the Community of foot-and-mouth disease antigens within the framework of the Community action concerning reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines</p>
      <p n="3">(93/590/EC)THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Decision 90/424/EEC of 26 June 1990 on expenditure in the veterinary field (1), as last amended by Commission Decision 93/439/EEC (2), and in particular Article 14 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Decision 91/666/EEC of 11 December 1991 establishing Community reserves of foot-and-mouth disease vaccines (3), and, in particular, Articles 5 and 7 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, in conformity with Decision 91/666/EEC, the purchase of antigens is a part of the Community action to establish Community reserves of foot and mouth disease vaccines;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the Commission has issued a call for tenders for the supply of antigens;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Commission has examined the submitted tenders taking into account the following factors:</p>
      <p n="10">- the technical requirements of Annex II to Decision 91/666/EEC and other criteria mentioned in Article 5 of that Decision,</p>
      <p n="11">- that some establishments are unable to supply the full number of doses of some antigens,</p>
      <p n="12">- the need for the producing establishment to be in full conformity with the guidelines for good manufacturing practices (GMP);</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the Commission has selected Rhône-Mérieux to supply five million doses of each of subtypes A5, A22, O1 European strain and O1 Middle East strain as a first step; whereas the establishments which will supply the other strains in Annex I to Decision 91/666/EEC will be decided after a further call for tenders;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas financial provisions should be made to allow the Commission to purchase these strains from Rhône-Mérieux;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas, under the provisions of Article 7 of Decision 91/666/EEC, it is necessary to lay down the rules for the distribution of antigen reserves between the antigen banks, nominated in Article 1 of the said Decision;</p>
      <p n="16">Whereas it is appropriate that each strain should be divided equally between two banks; whereas the strains stored in each bank should be related geographically to the most likely area of risk;</p>
      <p n="17">Whereas in accordance with Article 40 of Council Decision 90/424/EEC, checks provided for in Articles 8 and 9 of Council Regulation (EEC) No 729/70 of 21 April 1970 concerning the financing of the common agricultural policy (4) shall apply; whereas, moreover, certain particular provisions should be made;</p>
      <p n="18">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="19">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="20">Article 1</p>
      <p n="21">1. The Community shall purchase five million doses of each of the following strains of foot-and-mouth disease antigen:</p>
      <p n="22">- A5 European,</p>
      <p n="23">- A22 Middle East,</p>
      <p n="24">- O1 Middle East,</p>
      <p n="25">- O1 European,</p>
      <p n="26">up to a maximum cost of ECU 4 065 million.</p>
      <p n="27">2. The antigen mentioned in paragraph 1 shall be supplied by Rhône-Mérieux, Pirbright Laboratory, Ash Road, Surrey, United Kingdom.</p>
      <p n="28">Article 2</p>
      <p n="29">1. To meet the objectives of Article 1, the Commission shall conclude a contract, in the name of the European Community, with Rhône-Mérieux.</p>
      <p n="30">2. The Director General of Directorate General for Agriculture shall be authorized to sign the contract on behalf of the Commission of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="31">3. Payment to Rhône-Mérieux shall be made in accordance with the terms of the contract provided for in paragraph 1.</p>
      <p n="32">Article 3</p>
      <p n="33">The antigen shall be divided between the four antigen banks as follows:</p>
      <p n="34">(a) Bayer, Cologne and the Institute for Animal health, Pirbright: 2,5 million doses of each of O1 European strain and A5 in each bank;</p>
      <p n="35">(b) LNPB, Lyon and 1ZP, Brescia: 2,5 million doses of each of O1 Middle East strain and A22 in each bank.</p>
      <p n="36">Article 4</p>
      <p n="37">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="38">Done at Brussels, 5 November 1993.</p>
      <p n="39">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="40">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="41">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="42">(1) OJ No L 224, 18. 8. 1990, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="43">(2) OJ No L 203, 13. 8. 1993, p. 34.</p>
      <p n="44">(3) OJ No L 368, 31. 12. 1991, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="45">(4) OJ No L 94, 28. 4. 1970, p. 13.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
