<TEI.2 id="jrc31993D0052-en" n="31993D0052" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993D0052 English</title>
        <title>93/52/EEC: Commission Decision of 21 December 1992 recording the compliance by certain Member States or regions with the requirements relating to brucellosis (B. melitensis) and according them the status of a Member State or region officially free of the disease</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0052:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0052:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993D0052-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">93/52/EEC: Commission Decision of 21 December 1992 recording the compliance by certain Member States or regions with the requirements relating to brucellosis (B. melitensis) and according them the status of a Member State or region officially free of the disease</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 21 December 1992 recording the compliance by certain Member States or regions with the requirements relating to brucellosis (B. melitensis) and according them the status of a Member State or region officially free of the disease</p>
      <p n="3">(93/52/EEC)THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 91/68/EEC of 28 January 1991 on animal health conditions governing intra-Community trade on ovine and caprine animals (1), and in particular Annex A, Chapter 1.II thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, in the United Kingdom, Ireland, the Netherlands, Belgium, Luxembourg, the Federal Republic of Germany and certain regions in France, brucellosis (B. melitensis) has been a notifiable disease for at least five years; whereas no case has been confirmed officially there for at least five years and vaccination has been banned there for at least three years; whereas it should therefore be put on record that they comply with the conditions laid down in Annex A, Chapter 1.II (1) (b);</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, in addition, the Member States or regions referred to above undertake to satisfy the provisions laid down in Annex A, Chapter 1.II (2); whereas, consequently, the Member States and regions in question should be accorded officially brucellosis (B. melitensis) free status;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The Member States and regions referred to respectively in Annexes I and II satisfy the conditions laid down in Directive 91/68/EEC, Annex A, Chapter 1.II (1) (b).</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">The Member States and regions referred to respectively in Annexes I and II are recognized as officially free of brucellosis (B. melitensis).</p>
      <p n="14">Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 21 December 1992.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="18">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="19">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">(1) OJ No L 46, 19. 2. 1991, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="21">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="22">MEMBER STATE - United Kingdom,</p>
      <p n="23">- Federal Republic of Germany,</p>
      <p n="24">- Ireland,</p>
      <p n="25">- Luxembourg,</p>
      <p n="26">- Belgium,</p>
      <p n="27">- Netherlands.</p>
      <p n="28">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="29">REGIONS In France: Ain, Aisne, Allier, Ardennes, Aube, Charente, Charente-Maritime, Cher, Côte-d'Or, Côtes-d'Amor, Creuse, Dordogne, Doubs, Eure, Eure-et-Loire, Finistère, Ille-et-Vilaine, Indre, Indre-et-Loire, Jura, Loir-et-Cher, Loire, Loire-Atlantique, Loiret, Lot et Garonne, Maine-et-Loire, Manche, Marne, Mayenne, Nièvre, Nord, Oise, Orne, Pas-de-Calais, Rhône, Haute-Saône, Saône-et-Loire, Sarthe, Ville de Paris, Seine-maritime, Seine-et-Marne, Yvelines, Deux-Sèvres, Vendée, Vienne, Haute-Vienne, Yonne, Territoire de Belfort, Essonne, Hauts-de-Seine, Seine-Saint-Denis, Val-de-Marne, Val-d'Oise.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
