<TEI.2 id="jrc31993R3179-en" n="31993R3179" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993R3179 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 3179/93 of 16 November 1993 amending Regulation No 136/66/EEC on the establishment of a common organization of the market in oils and fats</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993R3179:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993R3179:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993R3179-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 3179/93 of 16 November 1993 amending Regulation No 136/66/EEC on the establishment of a common organization of the market in oils and fats</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC) No 3179/93 of 16 November 1993 amending Regulation No 136/66/EEC on the establishment of a common organization of the market in oils and fats</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal of the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas pursuant to Article 12 of Regulation No 136/66/EEC of the Council (3), the buying in of olive oil is restricted to the last four months of the marketing year; whereas experience shows that certain Community markets may be in a critical situation before intervention is initiated; whereas, to overcome such difficulties, provision should be made for deciding at Community level intervention measures suited to such circumstances,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The following Article is hereby added to Regulation No 136/66/EEC.</p>
      <p n="11">'Article 12a</p>
      <p n="12">1. Where the market in certain regions of the Community is seriously disturbed before the intervention period referred to in Article 12 has begun, specific intervention measures may be decided upon.</p>
      <p n="13">2. The nature and application of the specific measures referred to in paragraph 1 as well as the conditions and procedures of sale or those established with a view to any other use of the product subject to these measures, shall be decided in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 38.'</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day of following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 16 November 1993.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Council</p>
      <p n="19">The President</p>
      <p n="20">A. BOURGEOIS</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ No C 259, 23. 9. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) Opinion delivered on 29 October 1993 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="23">(3) OJ No 172, 30. 9. 1966, p. 3025/66. Regulation as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2046/92 (OJ No L 215, 30. 7. 1992, p. 1).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
