<TEI.2 id="jrc31993R0286-en" n="31993R0286" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993R0286 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regualtion (EEC) No 286/93 of 9 February 1993 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2342/92 on imports of pure-bred breeding animals of the bovine species from third countries and the granting of export refunds thereon</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>25 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993R0286:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993R0286:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993R0286-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regualtion (EEC) No 286/93 of 9 February 1993 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2342/92 on imports of pure-bred breeding animals of the bovine species from third countries and the granting of export refunds thereon</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 286/93 of 9 February 1993 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2342/92 on imports of pure-bred breeding animals of the bovine species from third countries and the granting of export refunds thereon</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 805/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in beef and veal (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 125/93 (2), and in particular Article 10 (5) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, pursuant to Article 2 (5) of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2342/92 of 7 August 1992 on imports of pure-bred breeding animals of the bovine species from third countries and the granting of export refunds thereon and repealing Regulation (EEC) No 1544/79 (3), imports of pure-bred breeding animals originating in and coming from the EFTA countries are exempted from certain obligations specified in Article 2 (3) of that Regulation; whereas this does not affect the applicability of Article 7, second paragraph of Council Directive 77/504/EEC of 25 July 1977 on pure-bred breeding animals of the bovine species (4), as last amended by Directive 91/174/EEC (5); whereas, in order to ensure that the existing version of the said Article 2 (5) does not cause problems in the practical application of that Directive, it should be clarified on a declaratory basis;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Beef and Veal,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">Regulation (EEC) No 2342/92 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="11">1. In Article 2 (3) (a), the words 'and has been registered or entered in a herd book' are deleted;</p>
      <p n="12">2. In Article 2 the following paragraph is inserted:</p>
      <p n="13">'6. This Article shall not affect the application of Article 7, second paragraph, of Directive 77/504/EEC.'</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 9 February 1993.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="20">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) OJ No L 18, 27. 1. 1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="23">(3) OJ No L 227, 11. 8. 1992, p. 12.</p>
      <p n="24">(4) OJ No L 206, 12. 8. 1977, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="25">(5) OJ No L 85, 5. 4. 1991, p. 37.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
