<TEI.2 id="jrc31993D0455-en" n="31993D0455" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31993D0455 English</title>
        <title>93/455/EEC: Commission Decision of 23 July 1993 approving certain contingency plans for the control of foot-and-mouth disease</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>32 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0455:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31993D0455:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31993D0455-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">93/455/EEC: Commission Decision of 23 July 1993 approving certain contingency plans for the control of foot-and-mouth disease</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 23 July 1993 approving certain contingency plans for the control of foot-and-mouth disease</p>
      <p n="3">(93/455/EEC)THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 90/423/EEC of 26 June 1990, amending Directive 85/511/EEC introducing Community measures for the control of foot-and-mouth disease, Directive 64/432/EEC on animal health problems affecting intra-Community trade in bovine animals and swine and Directive 72/462/EEC on health and veterinary inspection problems upon importation of bovine animals and swine and fresh meat products from third countries (1), and in particular Article 5 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Commission has already laid down criteria to be applied when drawing up contingency plans for the control of foot-and-mouth disease by Decision 91/42/EEC (2);</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas certain Member States have submitted for approval national contingency plans; whereas, after examination these plans permit the desired objective to be attained and fulfil all the criteria laid down in Decision 91/42/EEC;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The contingency plans for the control of foot-and-mouth disease submitted by Member States listed in Annex 1 are approved.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Brussels, 23 July 1993.</p>
      <p n="15">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="16">René STEICHEN</p>
      <p n="17">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="18">(1) OJ No L 224, 13. 8. 1990, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="19">(2) OJ No L 23, 29. 1. 1991, p. 29.</p>
      <p n="20">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="21">The contingency plans for the control of foot-and-mouth disease of the following Member States are approved:</p>
      <p n="22">Belgium</p>
      <p n="23">Denmark</p>
      <p n="24">Germany</p>
      <p n="25">Greece</p>
      <p n="26">Spain</p>
      <p n="27">France</p>
      <p n="28">Ireland</p>
      <p n="29">Italy</p>
      <p n="30">Luxembourg</p>
      <p n="31">Portugal</p>
      <p n="32">United Kingdom</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
