<TEI.2 id="jrc41993D0014-en" n="41993D0014" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 41993D0014 English</title>
        <title>The Schengen acquis - Decision of the Executive Committee of 14 December 1993 on improving practical judicial cooperation for combating drug trafficking (SCH/Com-ex (93) 14)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>14 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41993D0014:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41993D0014:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc41993D0014-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">The Schengen acquis - Decision of the Executive Committee of 14 December 1993 on improving practical judicial cooperation for combating drug trafficking (SCH/Com-ex (93) 14)</head>
      <p n="2">DECISION OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE</p>
      <p n="3">of 14 December 1993</p>
      <p n="4">on improving practical judicial cooperation for combating drug trafficking</p>
      <p n="5">(SCH/Com-ex (93)14)</p>
      <p n="6">THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Article 132 of the Convention implementing the Schengen Agreement, hereinafter "the Schengen Convention",</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Articles 48 to 53 and 70 to 76 of the abovementioned Convention,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="10">So as to improve practical judicial cooperation in combating drug trafficking, the Contracting Parties undertake that should the requested party not intend to enforce a request for mutual assistance, or intend to enforce it only in part, it will inform the requesting party of the reasons for its refusal and, where possible, of the conditions to be met before such a request can be enforced.</p>
      <p n="11">This Decision shall enter into force once all the States party to the Schengen Convention have notified that the procedures required by their legal systems for these decisions to be binding on their territory have been completed.</p>
      <p n="12">Paris, 14 December 1993.</p>
      <p n="13">The Chairman</p>
      <p n="14">A. Lamassoure</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
