<TEI.2 id="jrc31971R0912-en" n="31971R0912" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31971R0912 English</title>
        <title>Regulation (EEC) No 912/71 of the Commission of 30 April 1971 amending the French and Italian texts of Regulation (EEC) No 391/68 laying down detailed rules for intervention buying-in in pigmeat</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31971R0912:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31971R0912:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31971R0912-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Regulation (EEC) No 912/71 of the Commission of 30 April 1971 amending the French and Italian texts of Regulation (EEC) No 391/68 laying down detailed rules for intervention buying-in in pigmeat</head>
      <p n="2">REGULATION (EEC) No 912/71 OF THE COMMISSION of 30 April 1971 amending the French and Italian texts of Regulation (EEC) No 391/68 laying down detailed rules for intervention buying-in in pigmeat</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation No 121/67/EEC 1 of 13 June 1967 on the common organisation of the market in pigmeat, as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 777/71, 2 and in particular Article 4 (6) and 5 (3) thereof;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 391/68 3 of 1 April 1968 laying down detailed rules for intervention buying-in in pigmeat, as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2665/70, 4 laid down detailed rules for the buying-in, storage and sale of pigmeat by the intervention agencies of the Member States;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Regulation (EEC) No 2665/70 supplemented those rules, particularly as regards refrigeration temperature, storage temperature and packaging;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas there is a discrepancy between the French and Italian texts and the texts in the other Community languages as regards the supplementary rules, which thus do not correspond to the measures adopted by the procedure provided for in Article 24 of Regulation No 121/67/EEC ; whereas it is therefore necessary to amend the relevant texts of Regulation (EEC) No 391/68;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation arc in accordance with the Opinion of the Management Committee for Pigmeat;</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The following shall be substituted for the French text of the first subparagraph of Article 1 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 391/68:</p>
      <p n="13">"Les États membres prennent toutes mesures aptes à assurer la bonne conservation des produits stockés. La température de congélation doit être égale ou inférieure à moins 30º Celsius, permettant d'obtenir une température à coeur égale ou inférieure à moins 15º Celsius. La température de stockage doit être égale ou inférieure à moins 20º Celsius."</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">The following shall be substituted for the Italian text of Article 1 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 391/68:</p>
      <p n="16">"Gli Stati membri adottano tutte le misure indonee ad assicurare la buona conservazione dei prodotti ammassati. La temperatura di congelamento deve essere uguale o inferiore a meno 30º Celsius per permettere di ottenere una temperatura al centro della massa uguale o inferiore a meno 15º Celsius. La temperatura di conservazione in ammasso deve essere uguale o inferiore a meno 20º Celsius.</p>
      <p n="17">I suini macellati, in carcasse o mezzene, sono imballati, dopo congelazione, in polietilene, idoneo all'imballaggio di prodotti alimentari, di 1OJ No 117, 19.6.1967, p. 2283/67. 2OJ No L 85, 15.4.1971, p. 30. 3OJ No L 80, 2.4.1968, p. 5. 4OJ No L 284, 30.12.1970, p. 55.</p>
      <p n="18">0 705 mm di spessore ed in sacchi di cotone (stockinettes).</p>
      <p n="19">Le pancette (ventresche) ed il lardo sono imballati dopo congelazione, in polietilene, idoneo all'imballaggio di prodotti alimentari, di 0 705 mm di spessore."</p>
      <p n="20">Article 3</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="22">It shall apply from 26 April 1971.</p>
      <p n="23">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="24">Done at Brussels, 30 April 1967.</p>
      <p n="25">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">The President</p>
      <p n="27">Franco M. MALFATTI</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
