<TEI.2 id="jrc31970R0538-en" n="31970R0538" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31970R0538 English</title>
        <title>Regulation (EEC) No 538/70 of the Commission of 23 March 1970 amending Regulation (EEC) No 315/68 as regards the size of anemone coronaria</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31970R0538:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31970R0538:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31970R0538-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Regulation (EEC) No 538/70 of the Commission of 23 March 1970 amending Regulation (EEC) No 315/68 as regards the size of anemone coronaria</head>
      <p n="2">REGULATION (EEC) No 538/70 OF THE COMMISSION of 23 March 1970 amending Regulation (EEC) No 315/68 as regards the size of anemone coronaria</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 234/68 (1) of 27 February 1968 on the establishment of a common organisation of the market in live trees and other plants, bulbs, roots and the like, cut flowers and ornamental foliage, and in particular Article 4 thereof;</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas experiments by an experimental station have shown that under present production techniques good quality anemone coronaria can be obtained from tubers of a size smaller than that provided for by the common quality standards ; whereas, therefore, those standards should be adjusted;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the Opinion of the Management Committee for Live Plants;</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">In the Table appearing in Section III of the Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 315/68, as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 448/69, (2) the text in the Annex to this Regulation shall be substituted for the text referring to "anemone coronaria".</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Brussels, 23 March 1970.</p>
      <p n="15">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="16">The President</p>
      <p n="17">Jean REY (1)OJ No L 55, 2.3.1968, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 61, 12.3.1969, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="18">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="19">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0002320"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
