<TEI.2 id="jrc32001R2193-en" n="32001R2193" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32001R2193 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2193/2001 of 12 November 2001 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>75 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001R2193:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001R2193:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1264</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1873</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2709</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3275</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32001R2193-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2193/2001 of 12 November 2001 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2193/2001</p>
      <p n="3">of 12 November 2001</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation No 136/66/EEC of 22 September 1966 on the establishment of a common organisation of the market in oils and fats(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1513/2001(2),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 of 17 July 1984 laying down general rules on the granting of aid for the production of olive oil and of aid to olive oil producer organisations(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1639/98(4), and in particular Article 19 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Article 18 of Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 stipulates that olive yields and oil yields are to be fixed by homogenous production zones on the basis of the figures supplied by producer Member States.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) The production zones are delimited in the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 of 30 October 1997 delimiting the homogeneous olive oil production zones(5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1979/2001(6). For administrative and structural reasons the homogeneous production zones in Spain should be amended for the 2001/02 marketing year.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Oils and Fats,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">In the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2138/97, in Point D, the section headed "Comunidad autónoma Andalucía" is amended in accordance with the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="18">It shall apply from 1 November 2001.</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 12 November 2001.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="23">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ 172, 30.9.1966, p. 3025/66.</p>
      <p n="25">(2) OJ L 201, 26.7.2001, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) OJ L 208, 3.8.1984, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="27">(4) OJ L 210, 28.7.1998, p. 38.</p>
      <p n="28">(5) OJ L 297, 31.10.1997, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="29">(6) OJ L 270, 11.10.2001, p. 12.</p>
      <p n="30">ANEXO/BILAG/ANHANG/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ/ANNEX/ANNEXE/ALLEGATO/BIJLAGE/ANEXO/LIITE/BILAGA</p>
      <p n="31">"Comunidad Autónoma: Andalucía</p>
      <p n="32">Almería: 1 (*)</p>
      <p n="33">Cádiz: 1 (*)</p>
      <p n="34">Córdoba:</p>
      <p n="35">1. Valle de los Pedroches: Alcaracejos, Añora, Belalcázar, Belmez, Blázquez (Los), Cardeña, Conquista, Dos Torres, Fuente la Lancha, Fuente Obejuna, Granjuela (La), Guijo (El), Hinojosa del Duque, Pedroche, Peñarroya-Pueblonuevo, Santa Eufemia, Torrecampo, Valsequillo, Villanueva del Duque, Villaralto, Viso (El).</p>
      <p n="36">2. Sierra: Espiel, Obejo, Pozoblanco, Villaharta, Villanueva de Córdoba, Villanueva del Rey, Villaviciosa de Córdoba.</p>
      <p n="37">3. Valle del Guadalquivir: Adamuz, Almodóvar del Río, Carpio (El), Córdoba, Hornachuelos, Montoro, Palma del Río, Posadas, Villafranca de Córdoba.</p>
      <p n="38">4. Las Colonias: Carlota (La), Guadalcázar, Fuente Palmera, Victoria (La).</p>
      <p n="39">5. Río Genil: Puente Genil, Santaella.</p>
      <p n="40">6. Campiña Baja: Bujalance, Cañete de las Torres, Pedro Abad, Villa del Río.</p>
      <p n="41">7. Penibétical: Almedinilla, Carcabuey, Fuente-Tójar, Iznájar, Luque, Priego de Córdoba, Rute, Zuheros.</p>
      <p n="42">8. Campiña Alta: Aguilar, Baena, Benamejí, Castro del Río, Doña Mencía, Encinas Reales, Espejo, Fernán-Núñez, Lucena, Montalbán, Montemayor, Montilla, Monturque, Moriles, Nueva Carteya, Palenciana, Rambla (La), San Sebastián de los Ballesteros, Valenzuela.</p>
      <p n="43">Granada:</p>
      <p n="44">1. Alhama - Temple: Agrón, Alhama de Granada, Arenas del Rey, Cacín, Chimeneas, Escúzar, Jayena, Malahá (La), Santa Cruz de Alhama, Ventas de Huelma, Zafarraya.</p>
      <p n="45">2. Noroeste: Albuñán, Aldeire, Alicún de Ortega, Alquife, Baza, Beas de Guadix, Benalúa de Guadix, Benamaurel, Calahorra (La), Caniles, Castilléjar, Castril, Cogollos de Guadix, Cortes de Baza, Cortes y Graena, Cuevas del Campo, Cúllar Baza, Darro, Dehesas de Guadix, Diezma, Dólar, Ferreira, Fonelas, Freila, Galera, Gor, Gorafe, Guadix, Huélago, Huéneja, Huéscar, Jerez del Marquesado, Lanteira, Lugros, Marchal, Orce, Peza (La), Polícar, Puebla de Don Fadrique, Purullena, Valle del Zalabí, Villanueva de las Torres, Zújar.</p>
      <p n="46">3. Alpujarra - Costa - Valle de Lecrín: Albondón, Albuñol, Albuñuelas, Almegíjar, Almuñécar, Alpujarra de la Sierra, Bérchules, Bubión, Busquístar, Cádiar, Cáñar, Capileira, Carataunas, Cástaras, Dúrcal, Guajares (Los) (G. Faraguit), Gualchos, Itrabo, Jete, Juviles, Lanjarón, Lecrín, Lentegí, Lobras, Lújar, Molvízar, Motril, Murtas, Nevada, Nigüelas, Órgiva, Otívar, Padul, Pampaneira, Pinar (El), Polopos, Pórtugos, Rubite, Salobreña, Soportújar, Sorvilán, Taha (La), Torvizcón, Trevélez, Turón, Ugíjar, Válor, Valle (El), Vélez de Benaudalla, Villamena.</p>
      <p n="47">4. Montes: Alamedilla, Algarinejo, Benalúa de las Villas, Compotéjar, Colomera, Deifontes, Gobernador, Guadahortuna, Illora, Iznalloz, Moclín, Montefrío, Montejícar, Montillana, Morelábor, Pedro Martínez, Píñar, Torre-Cardela.</p>
      <p n="48">5. Vega occidental: Huétor Tájar, Loja, Moraleda de Zafayona, Salar, Villanueva Mesía, Zagra.</p>
      <p n="49">6. Vega oriental: Albolote, Alfacar, Alhendín, Armilla, Atarfe, Beas de Granada, Cájar, Calicasas, Cenes de la Vega, Cijuóela, Cogollos de la Vega, Cúllar Vega, Chauchina, Churriana de la Vega, Dílar, Dúdar, Fuente Vaqueros, Gabias (Las), Gójar, Granada, Güejar Sierra, Güevéjar, Huétor de Santillán, Huétor Vega, Jun, Láchar, Maracena, Monachil, Nívar, Ogíjares, Otura, Peligros, Pinos Genil, Pinos Puente, Pulianas, Quéntar, Santa Fe, Vegas del Genil, Víznar, Zubia (La).</p>
      <p n="50">Huelva:</p>
      <p n="51">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="52">2. Almonte, Hinojos, Lucena del Puerto, Moguer, Palos de la Frontera, Beas, Bollullos Par del Condado, Bonares, Chucena, Escacena del Campo, Manzanilla, Niebla, Palma del Condado (La), Paterna del Campo, Rociana del Condado, San Juan del Puerto, Trigueros, Villalba del Alcor, Villarrasa, Aljaraque, Cartaya, Gibraleón, Huelva, Isla Cristina, Lepe, Punta Umbría.</p>
      <p n="53">Jaén:</p>
      <p n="54">1. Sierra Morena: Aldeaquemada, Carolina (La), Santa Elena, Carboneros, Guarromán, Baños de la Encina.</p>
      <p n="55">2. El Condado: Montizón, Chiclana de Segura, Castellar, Sorihuela del Guadalimar, Santisteban del Puerto, Navas de San Juan, Arquillos, Vilches.</p>
      <p n="56">3. Sierra de Segura: Villarrodrigo, Génave, Torres de Albánchez, Siles, Benatae, Puente de Génave, Puerta de Segura (La), Orcera, Segura de la Sierra, Beas de Segura, Hornos, Santiago-Pontones.</p>
      <p n="57">4. Campiña Norte: Andújar, Marmolejo, Lopera, Porcuna, Higuera de Calatrava, Arjonilla, Arjona, Higuera de Arjona, Escañuela, Villanueva de la Reina, Fuerte del Rey, Cazalilla, Espeluy, Mengíbar, Jabalquinto, Bailén, Linares, Torreblascopedro, Villatorres, Santiago de Calatrava.</p>
      <p n="58">5. La Loma: Baeza, Begíjar, Canena, Ibros, Iznatoraf, Lupión, Rus, Sabiote, Torreperogil, Úbeda, Villacarillo, Villanueva del Arzobispo.</p>
      <p n="59">6. Campiña Sur: Alcaudete, Jaén, Jamilena, Mancha Real, Martos, Torre del Campo, Torredonjimeno, Villardompardo, Fuensanta de Martos.</p>
      <p n="60">7. Mágina: Albánchez de Úbeda, Bedmar y Garcíez, Bélmez de la Moraleda, Cabra del Santo Cristo, Cambil, Huelma-Solera, Jimena, Jódar, Larva, Torres.</p>
      <p n="61">8. Sierra de Cazorla: Hinojares, Huesa, Quesada, Pozo Alcón, Cazorla, Iruela (La), Chilluévar, Santo Tomé, Peal de Becerro.</p>
      <p n="62">9. Sierra Sur: Alcalá la Real, Campillo de Arenas, Cárcheles, Castillo de Locubín, Frailes, Guardia (La), Noalejo, Pegalajar, Valdepeñas de Jaén, Villares (Los).</p>
      <p n="63">Málaga:</p>
      <p n="64">1. Norte: Antequerra, Colmenar, Alfarnate, Alfarnatejo, Villanueva del Rosario, Villanueva del Trabuco, Archidona, Villanueva de Algaidas, Villanueva de Tapia, Cuevas de San Marcos, Cuevas Bajas, Alameda, Mollina, Humilladero, Fuente de Piedra, Sierra de Yeguas, Campillos, Teba, Ardales, Yunquera, Burgo (El), Cuevas del Becerro, Cañete la Real, Almargen.</p>
      <p n="65">2. Axarquía Oeste: Periana, Alcaucín, Riogordo, Viñuela, Canillas de Aceituno, Comares, Cútar, Benamargosa, Almáchar, Borge (El), Totalán, Moclinejo, Macharaviaya, Iznate, Benamocarra, Arenas, Sayalonga, Algarrobo, Rincón de la Victoria, Vélez-Málaga.</p>
      <p n="66">3. Axarquía Este: Nerja, Frigiliana, Torrox, Cómpeta, Árchez, Canillas de Albaida, Salares, Sedella.</p>
      <p n="67">4. Serranía de Ronda: Ronda, Arriate, Montejaque, Benaoján, Jimera de Líbar, Atajate, Alpandeire, Faraján, Cortes de la Frontera, Cartajima, Parauta, Igualeja, Pujerra, Jubrique, Benadalid, Júzcar, Benalauría, Algatocín, Benarrabá, Gaucín.</p>
      <p n="68">5. Centro Sur: Álora, Alozaina, Casarabonela, Carratraca, Tolox, Pizarra, Almogía, Valle de Abdalajís, Málaga, Cártama, Alhaurín de la Torre, Alhaurín el Grande, Coín, Guaro, Monda, Torremolinos, Casabermeja, Benalmádena, Fuengirola, Mijas, Ojén, Istán, Marbella, Benahavís, Estepona, Casares, Manilva.</p>
      <p n="69">Sevilla:</p>
      <p n="70">1. Estepa: Aguadulce, Badolatosa, Casariche, Estepa, Gilena, Herrera, Lora de Estepa, Marinaleda, Pedrera, Roda de Andalucía (La), Martín de la Jara.</p>
      <p n="71">2. Campiña Norte: Alcalá de Guadaira, Cañada del Rosal, Carmona, Écija, Viso del Alcor (El), Fuentes de Andalucía, Campana (La), Luisiana (La), Mairena del Alcor.</p>
      <p n="72">3. Aljarafe y Marisma: Albaida del Aljarafe, Almensilla, Benacazón, Bollullos de la Mitación, Bormujos, Carrión de los Céspedes, Castilleja del Campo, Castilleja de la Cuesta, Castilleja de Guzmán, Espartinas, Gines, Huévar, Mairena del Aljarafe, Olivares, Pilas, Salteras, Sanlúcar la Mayor, Tomares, Umbrete, Valencina de la Concepción, Villanueva del Ariscal, Palomares del Río, San Juan de Aznalfarache, Camas, Santiponce, Aznalcóllar, Gerena, Aznalcázar, Puebla del Río (La), Villamanrique de la Condesa, Isla Mayor.</p>
      <p n="73">4. Sierra Norte: Alanís, Almadén de la Plata, Castilblanco de los Arroyos, Castillo de las Guardas (El), Cazalla de la Sierra, Constantina, Garrobo (El), Guadalcanal, Madroño (El), Navas de la Concepción (Las), Pedroso (El), Real de la Jara (La), Ronquillo (El), San Nicolás del Puerto.</p>
      <p n="74">5. La Vega: Guillena, Puebla de los Infantes (La), Alcalá del Río, Alcolea del Río, Algaba (La), Brenes, Burguillos, Cantillana, Coria del Río, Dos Hermanas, Gelves, Lora del Río, Palacios y Villafranca (Los), Peñaflor, Rinconada (La), Sevilla, Tocina, Villanueva del Río y Minas, Villaverde del Río.</p>
      <p n="75">6. Sierra Sur y Campiña Sur: Osuna, Rubio (El), Lantejuela (La), Marchena, Paradas, Arahal, Utrera, Molares (Los), Coronil (El), Cabezas de San Juan (Las), Lebrija, Cuervo (El), Corrales (Los), Saucejo (El), Algámitas, Pruna, Villanueva de San Juan, Morón de la Frontera, Coripe, Montellano, Puebla de Cazalla (La)."</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
