<TEI.2 id="jrc32001R1979-en" n="32001R1979" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32001R1979 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1979/2001 of 10 October 2001 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>98 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001R1979:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001R1979:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1264</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2709</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5283</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32001R1979-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1979/2001 of 10 October 2001 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1979/2001</p>
      <p n="3">of 10 October 2001</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation No 136/66/EEC of 22 September 1966 on the common organisation of the market in oils and fats(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1513/2001(2),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 of 17 July 1984 laying down general rules on the granting of aid for the production of olive oil and of aid to olive oil producer organisations(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1639/98(4), and in particular Article 19 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Article 18 of Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 stipulates that the olive yields and oil yields are to be fixed by homogeneous production zones on the basis of the figures supplied by producer Member States.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) The production zones are set out in the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 of 30 October 1997 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones(5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2461/2000(6). For administrative and structural reasons, amendments must be made to the homogeneous production zones for the 2000/01 marketing year, in particular in Spain, Greece and Italy.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Oils and Fats,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Annex of Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. in point A, the provinces "Roma", "Caserta", "Consenza" and "Vibo Valentia" are amended in accordance with the Annex hereto;</p>
      <p n="17">2. in point C:</p>
      <p n="18">(a) "Αμυγδαλιά" is added to the nomos "Κοζάνης";</p>
      <p n="19">(b) the homogeneous zones of the nomos "Ρεθύμνου" are replaced by the following: "- zone 1:</p>
      <p n="20">Δήμοι και Κοινότητες: Αδελέ, Αμνάτους, Κυριάννας, Μαρουλά, Μέσης, Παγκαλοχωρίου, Πρασσών, Πηγής, Δ. Ρεθύμνης, Ρουσσοσπητίου, Χρωμοναστηρίου, Χαμαλευρίου, Χαρακίων.</p>
      <p n="21">- zone 2:</p>
      <p n="22">Δήμοι και Κοινότητες: Αρμένων, Γουλεδιανών, Καρές, Καττέλλους, Κούμων, Όρους, Σελλίου.</p>
      <p n="23">- zone 3:</p>
      <p n="24">Δήμοι και Κοινότητες: Αγίου Κωνσταντίνου, Άνω Βαλσαμόνερου, Αργυρούπολης, Ατσιποπούλου, Βιλανδρέδους, Γερανίου, Γωνιάς, Ζουριδίου, Καλονυκτίου, Κάτω Βαλσαμόνερου, Κάτω Πόρου, Μούνδρους, Μυριοκεφάλων, Πρινών, Ρουστίκων, Σαϊτούρων, Φρατζ. Μετοχίων, Μαλακίου.</p>
      <p n="25">- zone 4:</p>
      <p n="26">Δήμος: Επισκοπής Ρεθύμνης.</p>
      <p n="27">- zone 5:</p>
      <p n="28">Κοινότητες: Ασωμάτου, Λευκογείων, Μαριούς, Μυρθίου.</p>
      <p n="29">- zone 6:</p>
      <p n="30">Κοινότητες: Αγίου Βασιλείου, Αγίου Ιωάννη, Αγκουσελιανών, Καξαρές.</p>
      <p n="31">- zone 7:</p>
      <p n="32">Κοινότητες: Λαμπινής, Μυξορρούματος, Σπηλίου, Μουρνές.</p>
      <p n="33">- zone 8:</p>
      <p n="34">Κοινότητες: Αρδάκτος, Δρυμίσκου, Κεντροχωρίου, Κισσού, Αγίας Γαλήνης, Ακουμίων, Κρύας Βρύσης, Κεραμέ, Μέλαμπε, Ορνέ, Σακτουρίων.</p>
      <p n="35">- zone 9:</p>
      <p n="36">Κοινότητες: Ροδακίνου, Σελλιών</p>
      <p n="37">- zone 10:</p>
      <p n="38">Κοινότητες: Αγίας Παρασκευής, Αποδούλου, Λοχριάς, Νίθαυρης, Πλατάνου, Αγίου Ιωάννη, Αμαρίου, Κουρούτων.</p>
      <p n="39">- zone 11:</p>
      <p n="40">Κοινότητες: Φουρφουρά, Βιζαρίου, Πετροχωρίου, Άνω Μέρους, Λαμπιωτών.</p>
      <p n="41">- zone 12:</p>
      <p n="42">Κοινότητες: Πλατανίων, Βισταγής, Μοναστηρακίου, Αμαρίου, Μέρωνα, Ελενών, Γερακαρίου, Βρυσσών, Αποστόλων, Θρόνου, Καλογέρου</p>
      <p n="43">- zone 13:</p>
      <p n="44">Κοινότητες: Παντάνασσας, Βολιώνων, Πατσού, Καρίνων.</p>
      <p n="45">- zone 14:</p>
      <p n="46">Κοινότητες: Αγγελιανών, Πανόρμου, Περάματος, Ρουμελίου, Αχλαδέ, Σκεπαστής, Μελιδονίου, Σισσών, Πρίνου, Έρφων, Σκουλουφίων.</p>
      <p n="47">- zone 15:</p>
      <p n="48">Κοινότητες: Ελευθέρνων, Μαργαριτών, Αλφών, Ορθέ, Πασσαλιτών, Μελισσουργακίου, Καλανδαρέ, Χουμερίου, Αρχαίων Ελευθέρνων, Αγίου Ιωάννου Μυλοποτάμου.</p>
      <p n="49">- zone 16:</p>
      <p n="50">Κοινότητες: Αγίου Μάμα, Καλύβου, Λιβαδίων, Ζωνιανών, Ανωγείων.</p>
      <p n="51">- zone 17:</p>
      <p n="52">Κοινότητες: Βενίου, Αξού, Γαράζου, Επισκοπής Μυλοποτάμου, Δαμαβόλου, Θεοδώρας, Χώνους, Αλοϊδων, Κρυονερίου, Απλαδιανών, Αγίας, Αίμονα, Δοξαρού.";</p>
      <p n="53">(c) in the nomos Χανίων:</p>
      <p n="54">- Δρακώνας Κυδωνίας and Πλατυβόλας are transferred from zone 3 to zone 5,</p>
      <p n="55">- Σούδων, Τσικαλαριών and Χανίων are transferred from zone 11 to zone 13,</p>
      <p n="56">- Αλικιανού, Βατόλακου and Φουρνών are transferred from zone 13 to zone 6,</p>
      <p n="57">- Καντάνου and Πλεμελιανών are transferred from zone 14 to zone 17,</p>
      <p n="58">- the Φωτακάδου district in Βουκολιών is moved from zone 16 to zone 14;</p>
      <p n="59">3. in point D, under the Comunidad autónoma Aragón:</p>
      <p n="60">(a) in the province Zaragoza:</p>
      <p n="61">- Pinseque is added to zone 1,</p>
      <p n="62">- Villar de los Navarros is added to zone 2,</p>
      <p n="63">- Plenas is added to zone 3,</p>
      <p n="64">- Erla is added to zone 4,</p>
      <p n="65">- Bujaraloz and La Almonda are added to zone 6;</p>
      <p n="66">(b) in the province Huesca:</p>
      <p n="67">- Banastas is added to zone 2,</p>
      <p n="68">- Aguas, Castillonroy and Junzano are added to zone 5.</p>
      <p n="69">Article 2</p>
      <p n="70">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="71">It shall apply from 1 November 2000.</p>
      <p n="72">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="73">Done at Brussels, 10 October 2001.</p>
      <p n="74">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="75">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="76">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="77">(1) OJ 172, 30.9.1966, p. 3025/66.</p>
      <p n="78">(2) OJ L 201, 26.7.2001, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="79">(3) OJ L 208, 3.8.1984, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="80">(4) OJ L 210, 28.7.1998, p. 38.</p>
      <p n="81">(5) OJ L 297, 31.10.1997, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="82">(6) OJ L 283, 9.11.2000, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="83">ANEXO/BILAG/ANHANG/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ/ANNEX/ANNEXE/ALLEGATO/BIJLAGE/ANEXO/LIITE/BILAGA</p>
      <p n="84">"Roma:</p>
      <p n="85">1. Affile, Agosta, Allumiere, Anticoli Corrado, Arcinazzo Romano, Arsoli, Camerata Nuova, Canterano, Capranica Prenestina, Carpineto Romano, Castel San Pietro Romano, Cerreto Laziale, Cervara di Roma, Ciciliano, Cineto Romano, Gerano, Gorga, Jenne, Licenza, Mandela, Marano Equo, Montelanico, Percile, Pisoniano, Riofreddo, Rocca Canterano, Rocca Priora, Rocca Santo Stefano, Rocca di Cave, Rocca di Papa, Roccagiovine, Roiate, Roviano, Sambuci, Saracinesco, Segni, Subiaco, Tolfa, Vallepietra, Vallinfreda, Vicovaro, Vivaro Romano.</p>
      <p n="86">2. Albano Laziale, Anguillara Sabazia, Anzio, Ardea, Ariccia, Artena, Bellegra, Bracciano, Campagnano di Roma, Canale Monterano, Capena, Castel Gandolfo, Castelnuovo di Porto, Cave, Cerveteri, Ciampino, Civitavecchia, Civitella San Paolo, Colleferro, Colonna, Fiano Romano, Filacciano, Fiumicino, Formello, Frascati, Gallicano nel Lazio, Gavignano, Genazzano, Genzano di Roma, Grottaferrata, Labico, Ladispoli, Lanuvio, Lariano, Magliano Romano, Manziana, Marino, Mazzano Romano, Monte Porzio Catone, Montecompatri, Morlupo, Nazzano, Nemi, Nettuno, Olevano Romano, Palestrina, Pomezia, Ponzano Romano, Riano, Rignano Flaminio, Roma, Sacrofano, San Cesareo, San Vito Romano, Sant'Oreste, Santa Marinella, Torrita Tiberina, Trevignano Romano, Valmontone, Velletri, Zagarolo.</p>
      <p n="87">3. Casape, Castel Madama, Guidonia Montecelio, Marcellina, Mentana, Monteflavio, Montelibretti, Monterotondo, Montorio Romano, Moricone, Nerola, Palombara Sabina, Poli, San Gregorio da Sassola, San Polo dei Cavalieri, Sant'Angelo Romano, Tivoli."</p>
      <p n="88">"Caserta:</p>
      <p n="89">1. Arienzo, Bellona, Caiazzo, Calvi Risorta, Camigliano, Capua, Carinola, Casagiove, Casapulla, Caserta, Castel Campagnano, Castel Morrone, Castel di Sasso, Cellole, Cervino, Falciano del Massico, Francolise, Galluccio, Giano Vetusto, Maddaloni, Mondragone, Pastorano, Piana di Monte Verna, Pignataro Maggiore, Pontelatone, Rocca d'Evandro, San Felice a Cancello, San Prisco, Santa Maria a Vico, Sessa Aurunca, Sparanise, Teano, Vitulazio.</p>
      <p n="90">2. Ailano, Alife, Alvignano, Aversa, Baia e Latina, Caianello, Cancello ed Arnone, Capodrise, Capriati a Volturno, Carinaro, Casal di Principe, Casaluce, Casapesenna, Castel Volturno, Castello del Matese, Cesa, Ciorlano, Conca della Campania, Curti, Dragoni, Fontegreca, Formicola, Frignano, Gallo, Gioia Sannitica, Grazzanise, Gricignano di Aversa, Letino, Liberi, Lusciano, Macerata Campania, Marcianise, Marzano Appio, Mignano Monte Lungo, Orta di Atella, Parete, Piedimonte Matese, Pietramelara, Pietravairano, Portico di Caserta, Prata Sannita, Pratella, Presenzano, Raviscanina, Recale, Riardo, Roccamonfina, Roccaromana, Rocchetta e Croce, Ruviano, San Cipriano d'Aversa, San Gregorio Matese, San Marcellino, San Marco Evangelista, San Nicola la Strada, San Pietro Infine, San Potito Sannitico, San Tammaro, Sant'Angelo d'Alife, Sant'Arpino, Santa Maria Capua Vetere, Santa Maria la Fossa, Succivo, Teverola, Tora e Piccilli, Trentola-Ducenta, Vairano Patenora, Valle Agricola, Valle di Maddaloni, Villa Literno, Villa di Briano."</p>
      <p n="91">"Cosenza:</p>
      <p n="92">1. Amendolara, Calopezzati, Caloveto, Cariati, Cassano allo Ionio, Cerchiara di Calabria, Corigliano Calabro, Cropalati, Crosia, Mandatoriccio, Montegiordano, Paludi, Pietrapaola, Rocca Imperiale, Roseto Capo Spulico, Rossano, San Cosmo Albanese, San Demetrio Corone, San Giorgio Albanese, Santa Sofia d'Epiro, Scala Coeli, Terravecchia, Trebisacce, Vaccarizzo Albanese, Villapiana.</p>
      <p n="93">2. Acquaformosa, Acri, Albidona, Alessandria del Carretto, Altilia, Altomonte, Aprigliano, Belsito, Bianchi, Bisignano, Bocchigliero, Campana, Canna, Carolei, Carpanzano, Casole Bruzio, Castiglione Cosentino, Castrolibero, Castroregio, Castrovillari, Celico, Cellara, Cerisano, Cervicati, Cerzeto, Civita, Colosimi, Cosenza, Dipignano, Domanico, Fagnano Castello, Figline Vegliaturo, Firmo, Francavilla Marittima, Frascineto, Grimaldi, Laino Borgo, Laino Castello, Lappano, Lattarico, Longobucco, Lungro, Luzzi, Malito, Malvito, Mangone, Marano Marchesato, Marano Principato, Marzi, Mendicino, Mongrassano, Montalto Uffugo, Morano Calabro, Mormanno, Mottafollone, Nocara, Oriolo, Panettieri, Papasidero, Parenti, Paterno Calabro, Pedace, Pedivigliano, Piane Grati, Pietrafitta, Plataci, Rende, Roggiano Gravina, Rogliano, Rose, Rota Greca, Rovito, San Basile, San Benedetto Ullano, San Donato di Ninea, San Fili, San Giovanni in Fiore, San Lorenzo Bellizzi, San Lorenzo del Vallo, San Marco Argentano, San Martino di Finita, San Pietro in Guarano, San Sosti, San Vincenzo la Costa, Sant'Agata di Esaro, Santa Caterina Albanese, Santo Stefano di Rogliano, Saracena, Scigliano, Serra Pedace, Spezzano Albanese, Spezzano Piccolo, Spezzano della Sila, Tarsia, Terranova da Sibari, Torano Castello, Trenta, Zumpano.</p>
      <p n="94">3. Acquappesa, Aiello Calabro, Aieta, Amantea, Belmonte Calabro, Belvedere Marittimo, Bonifati, Buonvicino, Cetraro, Cleto, Diamante, Falconara Albanese, Fiumefreddo Bruzio, Fuscaldo, Grisolia, Guardia Piemontese, Lago, Longobardi, Maierà, Orsomarso, Paola, Praia a Mare, San Lucido, San Nicola Arcella, San Pietro in Amantea, Sangineto, Santa Domenica Talao, Santa Maria del Cedro, Scalea, Serra d'Aiello, Tortora, Verbicaro."</p>
      <p n="95">"Vibo Valentia:</p>
      <p n="96">1. Brognaturo, Fabrizia, Filadelfia, Francavilla Angitola, Mongiana, Pizzo, Polia, Serra San Bruno, Spadola.</p>
      <p n="97">2. Acquaro, Arena, Capistrano, Dasà, Dinami, Filogaso, Gerocarne, Maierato, Monterosso Calabro, Nardodipace, Pizzoni, San Nicola da Crissa, Simbario, Sorianello, Soriano Calabro, Vallelonga, Vazzano.</p>
      <p n="98">3. Briatico, Cessaniti, Drapia, Filandari, Francica, lonadi, Joppolo, Limbadi, Mileto, Nicotera, Parghelia, Ricadi, Rombiolo, San Calogero, San Costantino Calabro, San Gregorio d'Ippona, Sant'Onofrio, Spilinga, Stefanaconi, Tropea, Vibo Valentia, Zaccanopoli, Zambrone, Zungri."</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
