<TEI.2 id="jrc32001D0762-en" n="32001D0762" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32001D0762 English</title>
        <title>2001/762/Euratom: Commission Decision of 28 September 2001 on the conclusion of two cooperation agreements between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Russian Federation in the field of nuclear safety and in the field of controlled nuclear fusion (notified under document number C(2001) 2901)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001D0762:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001D0762:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32001D0762-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2001/762/Euratom: Commission Decision of 28 September 2001 on the conclusion of two cooperation agreements between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Russian Federation in the field of nuclear safety and in the field of controlled nuclear fusion (notified under document number C(2001) 2901)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 28 September 2001</p>
      <p n="4">on the conclusion of two cooperation agreements between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Russian Federation in the field of nuclear safety and in the field of controlled nuclear fusion</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2001) 2901)</p>
      <p n="6">(2001/762/Euratom)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular Article 101(2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the approval of the Council(1),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">The two agreements between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Russian Federation in the field of nuclear safety and in the field of nuclear fusion must be concluded,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Sole Article</p>
      <p n="14">The two agreements between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Russian Federation in the field of nuclear safety and in the field of controlled nuclear fusion are hereby concluded on behalf of the European Atomic Energy Community.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 28 September 2001.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="17">Pascal Lamy</p>
      <p n="18">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">(1) See page 21 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
