<TEI.2 id="jrc32001E0542-en" n="32001E0542" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32001E0542 English</title>
        <title>Council Common Position of 16 July 2001 concerning a visa ban against extremists in FYROM</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>28 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001E0542:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001E0542:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3588</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4005</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4045</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5634</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5713</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5796</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32001E0542-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Common Position of 16 July 2001 concerning a visa ban against extremists in FYROM</head>
      <p n="2">Council Common Position</p>
      <p n="3">of 16 July 2001</p>
      <p n="4">concerning a visa ban against extremists in FYROM</p>
      <p n="5">(2001/542/CFSP)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty on European Union, and in particular Article 15 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) In its conclusions of 11 June 2001, the Council expressed its growing concern at the serious deterioration of the security situation in the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (FYROM) and condemned the continued terrorist actions by ethnic Albanian extremists.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) In its conclusions of 25 June 2001, the Council continued to condemn all forms of terrorism in the Western Balkans region and remained committed to preventing such actions from undermining the democratic processes, including through restrictive measures such as a visa ban against extremists.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) No visas should be issued to extremists endangering peace and stability in FYROM and threatening the sovereignty and territorial integrity of FYROM.</p>
      <p n="12">(4) The EU considers the alignment of the Central and Eastern European countries associated with the EU, the associated countries Cyprus, Malta and Turkey, and the EFTA countries, members of the European Economic Area, to be important in order to maximise the impact of this Common Position,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS COMMON POSITION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">1. No visas shall be issued to extremists who endanger peace and stability in FYROM and threaten the sovereignty and territorial integrity of FYROM.</p>
      <p n="16">2. The list of persons falling within the scope of paragraph 1 shall be drawn up and updated by means of a Council implementing decision on the basis of recommendations by the HR.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">The Presidency will ask the Central and Eastern European countries associated with the EU, the associated countries Cyprus, Malta and Turkey, and the EFTA countries, members of the European Economic Area, to align themselves with this Common Position in order to maximise the impact of the visa ban.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 3</p>
      <p n="20">This Common Position will be kept under constant review.</p>
      <p n="21">Article 4</p>
      <p n="22">This Common Position shall take effect on the date of its adoption.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 5</p>
      <p n="24">This Common Position shall be published in the Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="25">Done at Brussels, 16 July 2001.</p>
      <p n="26">For the Council</p>
      <p n="27">The President</p>
      <p n="28">L. Michel</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
