<TEI.2 id="jrc32001R1455-en" n="32001R1455" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32001R1455 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 1455/2001 of 28 June 2001 amending Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999 on the common organisation of the market in beef and veal</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001R1455:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001R1455:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2173</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2194</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4638</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4682</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">976</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32001R1455-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 1455/2001 of 28 June 2001 amending Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999 on the common organisation of the market in beef and veal</head>
      <p n="2">Council Regulation (EC) No 1455/2001</p>
      <p n="3">of 28 June 2001</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999 on the common organisation of the market in beef and veal</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 37 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(1),</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) In order to enable traditional cattle-rearing activities to be maintained, Council Regulations (EC) No 1452/2001(2), (EC) No 1453/2001(3) and (EC) No 1454/2001(4), introducing specific measures for certain agricultural products for the French overseas departments, the Azores and Madeira and the Canary Islands respectively provide for the introduction of specific limits on the number of animals eligible for special premiums, suckler-cow premiums and slaughter premiums.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999(5) lays down regional ceilings per Member State as regards the special premiums. Annex II to that Regulation lays down national ceilings as regards the suckler-cow premiums. Those ceilings must not affect the introduction of the specific limits mentioned above. As a consequence it should be stipulated as of now that in the case of France, Portugal and Spain those ceilings are to include sub-ceilings that are based on the number of premiums paid in respect of a reference year to producers in the French overseas departments, the Azores and Madeira and the Canary Islands and are intended exclusively for producers in those regions. The remaining eligible animals making up the specific limits for the special premiums and the suckler-cow premiums introduced by Regulations (EC) No 1452/2001, (EC) No 1453/2001 and (EC) No 1454/2001 are to be added to those in Annexes I and II to Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="15">1. Annex I shall be replaced by the text in Annex I hereto;</p>
      <p n="16">2. Annex II shall be replaced by the text in Annex II hereto.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Luxembourg, 28 June 2001.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">B. Rosengren</p>
      <p n="24">(1) Opinion delivered on 14 June 2001 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="25">(2) See page 11 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) See page 26 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="27">(4) See page 45 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="28">(5) OJ L 160, 26.6.1999, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="29">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="30">SPECIAL PREMIUM</p>
      <p n="31">Regional ceilings of the Member States referred to in Article 4(4) of Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999</p>
      <p n="32">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="34">SUCKLER COW PREMIUM</p>
      <p n="35">National ceilings referred to in Article 7(2) of Regulation (EC) No 1254/1999 applicable from 1 January 2000</p>
      <p n="36">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
