<TEI.2 id="jrc21973A1221_01-en" n="21973A1221(01)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21973A1221(01) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21973A1221(01):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21973A1221(01):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21973A1221_01-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="3">Your Excellency,</p>
      <p n="4">I would like to draw to your attention an error of form in Article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway. This Article provides for a special timetable for the reduction of customs duties on imports into the Community as originally constituted and Ireland of products of subheading No 76.01 A and of heading No 76.02 or 76.03 of the Common Customs Tariff.</p>
      <p n="5">Owing to the error, the timetable of Article 3 of Protocol No 1 contains only the schedule of tariff reductions based on the basic duties - as defined in Article 5 (1) of the Agreement - applied on 1 January 1972 by the Community as originally constituted. The basic duties applied by Ireland on 1 January 1972 being different, the schedule of tariff reductions for Ireland ought to be mentioned separately, as has been done for other products in Article 1 (2) and Article 2 (1) of Protocol No 1.</p>
      <p n="6">The Irish duty applied on 1 January 1972 to products of subheading No 76.01 A and of certain subheadings of heading Nos 76.02 or 76.03 was zero (Annex). According to Article 3 (1) of the Agreement these duties will remain zero.</p>
      <p n="7">Consequently, it is the understanding of the Community that the timetable of Article 3 should read as follows in respect of those subheadings of heading Nos 76.02 and 76.03 where a positive basic duty on imports into Ireland was in force on 1 January 1972: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0005433"&gt;</p>
      <p n="8">Further proof that this form of timetable corresponds to the intention of the negotiators is given in Article 4 (f) of Protocol No 1, which determines the duties that can be reimposed when a ceiling has been reached. As far as the new Member States are concerned this Article takes account of the progressive realignment of their customs tariff with the Common Customs Tariff:</p>
      <p n="9">"In this event, prior to 1 July 1977: - Ireland shall reimpose customs duties applicable to third countries."</p>
      <p n="10">I should be grateful if you would confirm the agreement of the Government of the Kingdom of Norway with the content of this letter.</p>
      <p n="11">Please accept, Sir, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="12">In the name of the Council of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="13">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="14">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0005434"&gt;</p>
      <p n="15">Sir, Your letter received today contained the following communication:</p>
      <p n="16">"I would like to draw to your attention an error of form in Article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway. This Article provides for a special timetable for the reduction of customs duties on imports into the Community as originally constituted and Ireland of products of subheading No 76.01 A and of heading No 76.02 or 76.03 of the Common Customs Tariff.</p>
      <p n="17">Owing to the error, the timetable of Article 3 of Protocol No 1 contains only the schedule of tariff reductions based on the basic duties - as defined in Article 5 (1) of the Agreement - applied on 1 January 1972 by the Community as originally constituted. The basic duties applied by Ireland on 1 January 1972 being different, the schedule of tariff reductions for Ireland ought to be mentioned separately, as has been done for other products in Article 1 (2) and Article 2 (1) of Protocol No 1.</p>
      <p n="18">The Irish duty applied on 1 January 1972 to products of subheading No 76.01 A and of certain subheadings of heading Nos 76.02 or 76.03 was zero (Annex). According to Article 3 (1) of the Agreement these duties will remain zero.</p>
      <p n="19">Consequently, it is the understanding of the Community that the timetable of Article 3 should read as follows in respect of those subheadings of heading Nos 76.02 and 76.03 where a positive basic duty on imports into Ireland was in force on 1 January 1972: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0005435"&gt;</p>
      <p n="20">Further proof that this form of timetable corresponds to the intention of the negotiators is given in Article 4 (f) of Protocol No 1, which determines the duties that can be reimposed when a ceiling has been reached. As far as the new Member States are concerned this Article takes account of the progressive realignment of their customs tariff with the Common Customs Tariff:</p>
      <p n="21">"In this event, prior to 1 July 1977: - Ireland shall reimpose customs duties applicable to third countries."</p>
      <p n="22">I should be grateful if you would confirm the agreement of the Government of the Kingdom of Norway with the content of this letter."</p>
      <p n="23">I have the honour to acknowledge receipt of your letter and to confirm the agreement of my Government to its content.</p>
      <p n="24">Please accept, Sir, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="25">For the Government of the Kingdom of Norway</p>
      <p n="26">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="27">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0005436"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
