<TEI.2 id="jrc31973R3476-en" n="31973R3476" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31973R3476 English</title>
        <title>Regulation (EEC) No 3476/73 of the Council of 3 December 1973 approving the exchange of letters rectifying article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>17 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31973R3476:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31973R3476:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31973R3476-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Regulation (EEC) No 3476/73 of the Council of 3 December 1973 approving the exchange of letters rectifying article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway</head>
      <p n="2">REGULATION (EEC) No 3476/73 OF THE COUNCIL of 3 December 1973 approving the exchange of letters rectifying Article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof;</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the recommendation of the Commission;</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Agreement signed on 14 May 1973 between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway should be rectified and the exchange of letters to this effect between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway on 21 December 1973 approved,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The exchange of letters of 21 December 1973 between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway for the purpose of rectifying Article 3 of Protocol No 1 to the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway is hereby approved on behalf of the Community. The text of the letters is annexed to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Brussels, 3 December 1973.</p>
      <p n="15">For the Council</p>
      <p n="16">The President</p>
      <p n="17">I. NØRGAARD</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
