<TEI.2 id="jrc31978R0913-en" n="31978R0913" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31978R0913 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (Euratom, ECSC, EEC) No 913/78 of 2 May 1978 amending Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 260/68 laying down the conditions and procedure for applying the tax for the benefit of the European Communities</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>18 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31978R0913:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31978R0913:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31978R0913-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (Euratom, ECSC, EEC) No 913/78 of 2 May 1978 amending Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 260/68 laying down the conditions and procedure for applying the tax for the benefit of the European Communities</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EURATOM, ECSC, EEC) No 913/78 of 2 May 1978 amending Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 260/68 laying down the conditions and procedure for applying the tax for the benefit of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing a single Council and a single Commission of the European Communities,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the Protocol on the privileges and immunities of the European Communities, and in particular Article 13 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Council Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 260/68 of 29 February 1968 laying down the conditions and procedure for applying the tax for the benefit of the European Communities (1), as last amended by Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 1544/73 (2), should be amended to take account of Council Regulation (Euratom, ECSC, EEC) No 912/78 of 2 May 1978 amending the Staff Regulations of officials of the European Communities and the conditions of employment of other servants of the European Communities (3),</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The following indent shall be added to Article 6 (1) (a) of Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 260/68:</p>
      <p n="11">"- under Article 70a of the Staff Regulations."</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 2 May 1978.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Council</p>
      <p n="17">The President</p>
      <p n="18">K.B. ANDERSEN (1)OJ No L 56, 4.3.1968, p. 8. (2)OJ No L 155, 11.6.1973, p. 6. (3)See page 1 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
