<TEI.2 id="jrc31978R2991-en" n="31978R2991" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31978R2991 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 2991/78 of 18 December 1978 amending Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 fixing quality standards for fresh cut flowers and fresh ornamental foliage</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>18 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31978R2991:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31978R2991:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31978R2991-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 2991/78 of 18 December 1978 amending Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 fixing quality standards for fresh cut flowers and fresh ornamental foliage</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 2991/78 of 18 December 1978 amending Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 fixing quality standards for fresh cut flowers and fresh ornamental foliage</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 234/68 of 27 February 1968 on the establishment of a common organization of the market in live trees and other plants, bulbs, roots and the like, cut flowers and ornamental foliage (1), and in particular Article 3 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the first indent of Article 2 (1) of Council Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 of 12 March 1968 fixing quality standards for fresh cut flowers and fresh ornamental foliage (2) as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1155/76 (3), lays down that the produce specified in Article 1 which does not comply with quality standards may not, within the Community, be put on sale or sold at the wholesale stage either by traders or directly by the producers ; whereas the above provision should be supplemented in order also to permit inspection during transport,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The first indent of Article 2 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 316/68 shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="11">"- within the Community, be displayed for sale, put on sale, sold, delivered or otherwise marketed at the wholesale stage either by traders or directly by the producers."</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="15">Done at Brussels, 18 December 1978.</p>
      <p n="16">For the Council</p>
      <p n="17">The President</p>
      <p n="18">J. ERTL (1)OJ No L 55, 2.3.1968, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 71, 21.3.1968, p. 8. (3)OJ No L 130, 19.5.1976, p. 26.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
