<TEI.2 id="jrc31978L0583-en" n="31978L0583" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31978L0583 English</title>
        <title>Ninth Council Directive 78/583/EEC of 26 June 1978 on the harmonization of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31978L0583:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31978L0583:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31978L0583-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Ninth Council Directive 78/583/EEC of 26 June 1978 on the harmonization of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes</head>
      <p n="2">NINTH COUNCIL DIRECTIVE of 26 June 1978 on the harmonization of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes (78/583/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 99 and 100 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (2),</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Article 1 of the Sixth Council Directive 77/388/EEC of 17 May 1977 on the harmonization of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes - Common system of value added tax : uniform basis of assessment (3) lays down 1 January 1978 as the latest date for the implementation of its provisions in Member States;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Directive 77/388/EEC lays down common provisions for all fields covered by value added tax ; whereas, in many cases, it is incumbent upon the Member States to determine the conditions under which these provisions shall apply ; whereas, since the scope of Directive 77/388/EEC is so wide as to encompass a very large number of national regulations, several Member States have been unable to carry out the necessary adaptions in time to comply with Directive 77/388/EEC ; whereas these Member States have thus been unable to complete the legislative procedure necessary to adapt their legislation on value added tax within the time limit laid down;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Member States concerned have requested an extension of the time limit for the entry into force of Directive 77/388/EEC ; whereas in this context an extension for a maximum of 12 months should be sufficient,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">By way of derogation from Article 1 of Directive 77/388/EEC, Denmark, Germany, France, Ireland, Italy, Luxembourg and the Netherlands are hereby authorized to implement the said Directive by 1 January 1979 at the latest.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Directive is addressed to Denmark, Germany, France, Ireland, Italy, Luxembourg and the Netherlands.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Luxembourg, 26 June 1978.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">K.B. ANDERSEN (1)OJ No C 163, 10.7.1978, p. 68. (2)Opinion delivered on 20/21 June 1978 (not yet published in the Official Journal). (3)OJ No L 145, 13.6.1977, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
