<TEI.2 id="jrc31989R0439-en" n="31989R0439" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989R0439 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 439/89 of 22 February 1989 amending Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 on the method to be used and the interest rates to be applied for the calculation of the cost of financing intervention in the form of buying in, storage and disposal</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>34 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R0439:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R0439:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989R0439-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 439/89 of 22 February 1989 amending Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 on the method to be used and the interest rates to be applied for the calculation of the cost of financing intervention in the form of buying in, storage and disposal</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 439/89</p>
      <p n="4">of 22 February 1989</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 on the method to be used and the interest rates to be applied for the calculation of the cost of financing intervention in the form of buying in, storage and disposal</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 of 2 August 1978 laying down general rules for the financing of interventions by the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund, Guarantee Section (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2050/88 (2), and in particular Article 5 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the first paragraph of Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 provides for fixing for the Community of a uniform interest rate, representative of the interest rates actually borne; whereas the second paragraph entitles the Commission to set the uniform interest rate at a lower level than its representative level until 1992; whereas the Commission has made use of this possibility, setting the uniform interest rate at 7 % since 1986; whereas, in view of the evolution of the Member States' interest rates it is necessary to increase this interest rate;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the second paragraph of Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 confers upon the Commission the power to set the uniform interest rates at a lower level for those Member States having interest costs lower than those deriving from the application of the uniform interest rate for the calculation of the fiancing costs;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the conditions laid down in the said Article 5 are met in certain Member States; whereas, in fact, interest rates below the level of the uniform interest rate have been recorded in these Member States since 1986;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas it is appropriate to establish for the Member States concerned the special interest rate to be applied in these Member States from 1 January 1989 onwards and to amend Commission Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 (3) accordingly;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the EAGGF Committee has not delivered an opinion within the time limit set by its chairman,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 is hereby amended follows:</p>
      <p n="17">1. Article 3 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="18">'Article 3</p>
      <p n="19">The interest rate mentioned in Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 shall be 7,7 %.'</p>
      <p n="20">2. In Article 4, the second paragraph is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="21">'2. For the period 1 January to 30 September 1989, the specific interest rate shall be:</p>
      <p n="22">- 6 % for Germany,</p>
      <p n="23">- 6,5 % for the Netherlands and for Luxembourg.'</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="26">It shall apply with effect from 1 January 1989.</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 22 February 1989.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="31">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ No L 216, 5. 8. 1978, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="33">(2) OJ No L 185, 15. 7. 1988, p. 6.</p>
      <p n="34">(3) OJ No L 40, 13. 2. 1988, p. 25.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
