<TEI.2 id="jrc31989R1644-en" n="31989R1644" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989R1644 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1644/89 of 12 June 1989 amending Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 on the method and the rate of interest to be used for calculating the costs of financing intervention measures comprising buying-in, storage and disposal</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>66 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R1644:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R1644:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989R1644-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1644/89 of 12 June 1989 amending Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 on the method and the rate of interest to be used for calculating the costs of financing intervention measures comprising buying-in, storage and disposal</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1644/89</p>
      <p n="4">of 12 June 1989</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 on the method and the rate of interest to be used for calculating the costs of financing intervention measures comprising buying-in, storage and disposal</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 of 2 August 1978 laying down general rules for the financing of interventions by the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund, Guarantee Section (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 787/89 (2), and in particular Article 5 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 provides that interest charges to be financed by the EAGGF Guarantee Section for funds used for the buying-in of products are, in the case of funds originating in the Member States, to be calculated using a method and an interest rate uniform throughout the Community and whereas that interest rate must be representative of interest rates actually paid;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 (3), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 439/89 (4), lays down the method and the interest rate to be applied for the calculation of the financing costs mentioned above;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the interest rates for short-term and long-term financing vary considerably depending on the Member State; whereas a weighting of those interest rates used hitherto has not given satisfactory results;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the interest rates recorded in recent years for the ecu increasingly reflect the interest rates, subject to a weighting, for currencies which make up the ecu and whereas the interest rates for the ecu may thus be considered representative of interest charges in the Community;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas, in view of the time limits for the financing of capital invested in intervention stocks, the uniform interest rate should reflect the three months' and 12 months' forward rates;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas Article 4 of that Regulation should stipulate the specific rules to be applied for a Member State bearing interest charges lower than those resulting from the application of the uniform interest rates;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas the EAGGF Committee has not delivered an opinion within the time limit set by the chairman,</p>
      <p n="16">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="17">Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">Regulation (EEC) No 411/88 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="19">1. Article 3 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="20">'Article 3</p>
      <p n="21">The interest rate referred to in Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 1883/78 shall correspond to the interest rates for the ecu for three months' and 12 months' forward rates recorded by the Statistical Office of the European Communities on the Euromarkets with a weighting of one-third and two-thirds respectively.</p>
      <p n="22">The interest rate shall be fixed before the beginning of each EAGGF Guarantee Section accounting year on the basis of the rates recorded in the six months preceding fixing.'</p>
      <p n="23">2. In Article 4 the following paragraph 1a is hereby inserted:</p>
      <p n="24">'1a. The interest costs borne by a Member State shall be notified to the Commission no later than 20 days before the end of the financial year. It shall relate to the six months preceding such notification.</p>
      <p n="25">Where no interest rate is notified, the interest costs to be applied are determined on the basis of the reference interest rates set out in the Annex.'</p>
      <p n="26">3. The Annex to this Regulation is added.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 2</p>
      <p n="28">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="29">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="30">Done at Brussels, 12 June 1989.</p>
      <p n="31">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="32">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="33">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="34">(1) OJ No L 216, 5. 8. 1978, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="35">(2) OJ No L 85, 30. 3. 1989, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="36">(3) OJ No L 40, 13. 2. 1988, p. 25.</p>
      <p n="37">(4) OJ No L 51, 23. 2. 1989, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="38">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="39">'ANNEX</p>
      <p n="40">Reference interest rates referred to in Article 4 (1a) (1)</p>
      <p n="41">1. Belgium:</p>
      <p n="42">Brussels interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="43">2. Denmark:</p>
      <p n="44">Yield on issue of 12-month Treasury bonds</p>
      <p n="45">3. Germany:</p>
      <p n="46">Frankfurt interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="47">4. Greece:</p>
      <p n="48">Yield on issue of three-month Treasury bonds</p>
      <p n="49">5. France:</p>
      <p n="50">Paris interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="51">6. Spain:</p>
      <p n="52">Madrid interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="53">7. Ireland:</p>
      <p n="54">Dublin interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="55">8. Italy:</p>
      <p n="56">Yield on issue of three month Treasury bonds</p>
      <p n="57">9. Luxembourg:</p>
      <p n="58">Interbank rate three months</p>
      <p n="59">10. Netherlands:</p>
      <p n="60">Amsterdam interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="61">11. Portugal:</p>
      <p n="62">Lisbon interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="63">12. United Kingdom:</p>
      <p n="64">London interbank borrowing offered rate three months</p>
      <p n="65">NB: These rates will be increased by one percentage point, corresponding to banking margin.</p>
      <p n="66">(1) Net interest rates concerned, i.e. interest rates after setting off the possible part that corresponds to fiscal charges (withholding tax, etc.).'</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
