<TEI.2 id="jrc31989D1031-en" n="31989D1031" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989D1031 English</title>
        <title>Decision of the President of the Court establishing a Court of First Instance of the European Communities</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>14 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989D1031:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989D1031:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989D1031-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Decision of the President of the Court establishing a Court of First Instance of the European Communities</head>
      <p n="2">DECISION OF THE PRESIDENT OF THE COURT</p>
      <p n="3">THE PRESIDENT OF THE COURT OF JUSTICE,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to Article 32d of the Treaty establishing the European Coal and Steel Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Article 168a of the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Article 140a of the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Council Decision of 24 October 1988 establishing a Court of First Instance of the European Communities, and in particular Article 13 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the Members of the Court of First Instance, appointed by common accord of the Governments of the Member States, have taken the oath before the Court of Justice;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Court of First Instance is in a position to exercise the judicial functions entrusted to it,</p>
      <p n="10">HEREBY DECLARES:</p>
      <p n="11">The Court of First Instance of the European Communities is constituted in accordance with law.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 3 of the Council Decision of 24 October 1988 establishing a Court of First Instance of the European Communities shall enter into force on the day of the publication of this Decision in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="13">Luxembourg, 11 October 1989.</p>
      <p n="14">The President of the Court of Justice</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
