<TEI.2 id="jrc31989R3172-en" n="31989R3172" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989R3172 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 3172/89 of 16 October 1989 on the application of Decision No 2/89 of the EEC-Egypt Cooperation Council amending, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal to the European Communities, the Protocol concerning the definition of the concept of 'originating products' and methods of administrative cooperation</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>10 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R3172:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R3172:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989R3172-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 3172/89 of 16 October 1989 on the application of Decision No 2/89 of the EEC-Egypt Cooperation Council amending, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal to the European Communities, the Protocol concerning the definition of the concept of 'originating products' and methods of administrative cooperation</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 3172/89 of 16 October 1989 on the application of Decision No 2/89 of the EEC-Egypt Cooperation Council amending, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal to the European Communities, the Protocol concerning the definition of the concept of 'originating products' and methods of administrative cooperation</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES, Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof, Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2573/87 of 11 August 1987 laying down the arrangements for trade between Spain and Portugal on the one hand and Algeria, Egypt, Jordan, Lebanon, Tunisia and Turkey on the other (1), and in particular Article 23 thereof, Having regard to the proposal from the Commission, Whereas Article 7 of Decision 87/456/ECSC of the representatives of the Governments of the Member States, meeting within the Council of 11 August 1987, laying down the arrangements for trade between Spain and Portugal on the one hand and Algeria, Egypt, Jordan, Lebanon and Tunisia on the other in products falling under the ECSC Treaty (2) lays down that the necessary changes to the origin rules adopted by the Cooperation Councils following the accession of Spain and Portugal shall apply to the products covered by the said Decision; Whereas, by virtue of Article 25 of the Protocol concerning the definition of the concept of 'originating products' and methods of administrative cooperation, the EEC-Egypt Cooperation Council has adopted Decision No 2/89 amending the said Protocol to take account of the accession of Spain and Portugal to the European Communities; Whereas the said Decision should be made to apply in the Community, HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="4">Article 1</p>
      <p n="5">Decision No 2/89 of the EEC-Egypt Cooperation Council shall be applied in the Community. The text of the Decision is attached to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="6">Article 2</p>
      <p n="7">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities. It shall apply with effect from 1 September 1987.</p>
      <p n="8">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States. Done at Luxembourg, 16 October 1989. For the Council The President M. DELEBARRE</p>
      <p n="9">(1) OJ No L 250, 1. 9. 1987, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) OJ No L 250, 1. 9. 1987, p. 112.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
