<TEI.2 id="jrc31989R0989-en" n="31989R0989" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989R0989 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 989/89 of 17 April 1989 relating to classification criteria applicable to anoraks (including ski-jackets), wind-cheaters, wind- jackets and similar articles of CN codes 6101, 6102, 6201 and 6202</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R0989:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R0989:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989R0989-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 989/89 of 17 April 1989 relating to classification criteria applicable to anoraks (including ski-jackets), wind-cheaters, wind- jackets and similar articles of CN codes 6101, 6102, 6201 and 6202</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 989/89</p>
      <p n="4">of 17 April 1989</p>
      <p n="5">relating to classification criteria applicable to anoraks (including ski-jackets), wind-cheaters, wind-jackets and similar articles of CN codes 6101, 6102, 6201 and 6202</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2658/87 of 23 July 1987on the tariff and statistical nomenclature and on the Common Customs tariff (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 20/89 (2), and, in particular, its Article 9,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas in order to ensure the uniform application of the combined nomenclature annexed to Regulation (EEC) No 2658/87, with regard to the tariff classification of anoraks (including ski-jackets), wind-cheaters, wind-jackets and similar articles falling within, amongst others, CN codes 6101, 6102, 6201 and 6202, it is necessary to specify certain characteristics of the said garments;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas these articles fall in a category of garments generally worn over other clothing and they ensure a protection against the weather;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas such protection cannot be ensured by garments without sleeves or with short sleeves; for this reason it is necessary to specify that the anoraks, wind-cheaters and similar articles mentioned above must have long sleeves;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the Nomenclature Committee has not delivered an opinion within the time limit set by its chairman,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Only garments which have long sleeves are classified as anoraks (including ski-jackets), wind-cheaters, wind-jackets and similar articles falling within CN codes 6101, 6102, 6201 and 6202.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall enter into force 21 days after its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 17 April 1989.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Christiane SCRIVENER</p>
      <p n="22">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 256, 7. 9. 1987, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ No L 4, 6. 1. 1989, p. 19.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
