<TEI.2 id="jrc31989R2067-en" n="31989R2067" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989R2067 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2067/89 of 11 July 1989 establishing the date of implementation in the Community of the system of certificates of origin provided for under the International Coffee Agreement 1983, when quotas are suspended</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>21 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R2067:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R2067:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989R2067-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2067/89 of 11 July 1989 establishing the date of implementation in the Community of the system of certificates of origin provided for under the International Coffee Agreement 1983, when quotas are suspended</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 2067/89</p>
      <p n="4">of 11 July 1989</p>
      <p n="5">establishing the date of implementation in the Community of the system of certificates of origin provided for under the International Coffee Agreement 1983, when quotas are suspended</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 678/87 of 26 January 1987 on the application of the system of certificates of origin provided for under the International Coffee Agreement 1983 (1), and in particular Article 4 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Council of the International Coffee Organization decided at its meeting of 3 July 1989 to suspend quotas from 4 July 1989;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas it is therefore appropriate to implement the above provisions,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">For the implementation of the International Coffee Agreement 1983, the provisions of Regulation (EEC) No 678/87 shall apply from 4 July 1989.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 11 July 1989.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">Christiane SCRIVENER</p>
      <p n="20">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ No L 69, 12. 3. 1987, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
