<TEI.2 id="jrc31989D0195-en" n="31989D0195" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989D0195 English</title>
        <title>89/195/EEC: Council Decision of 13 March 1989 on the conclusion of the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Tunisia on the import into the Community of preserved fruit salads originating in Tunisia</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989D0195:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989D0195:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989D0195-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">89/195/EEC: Council Decision of 13 March 1989 on the conclusion of the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Tunisia on the import into the Community of preserved fruit salads originating in Tunisia</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 13 March 1989</p>
      <p n="5">on the conclusion of the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Tunisia on the import into the Community of preserved fruit salads originating in Tunisia</p>
      <p n="6">(89/195/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Tunisia (1) was signed on 25 April 1976 and entered into force on 1 November 1978;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Tunisia on the import into the Community of preserved fruit salads originating in Tunisia should be approved,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The Agreement in the form of an Exchange of Letters between the European Economic Community and the Republic of Tunisia on the import into the Community of preserved fruit salads originating in Tunisia is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the Agreement for the purpose of binding the Community.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 3</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall take effect on the day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 13 March 1989.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">C. SOLCHAGA CATALAN</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ No L 265, 27. 9. 1978, p. 2.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
