<TEI.2 id="jrc31989R0790-en" n="31989R0790" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31989R0790 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 790/89 of 20 March 1989 fixing the level of additional flat-rate aid for the formation of producers' organizations and the maximum amount applied to aid for quality and marketing improvement in the nut-and locust bean-growing sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>30 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R0790:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31989R0790:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31989R0790-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 790/89 of 20 March 1989 fixing the level of additional flat-rate aid for the formation of producers' organizations and the maximum amount applied to aid for quality and marketing improvement in the nut-and locust bean-growing sector</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 790/89</p>
      <p n="4">of 20 March 1989</p>
      <p n="5">fixing the level of additional flat-rate aid for the formation of producers' organizations and the maximum amount applied to aid for quality and marketing improvement in the nut- and locust bean-growing sector</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72 of 18 May 1972 on the common organization of the market in fruit and vegetables (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 789/89 (2), and in particular Articles 14b (4) and 14d (3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the level of the additional flat-rate aid aimed at encouraging the formation of organizations of nut and/or locust bean producers should be fixed in such a way as to provide a genuine incentive, taking account of both the very low percentage of production marketed through producers' organizations and the small size of existing organizations;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, in the case of the quality and marketing improvement aid provided for in Article 14d of Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72, the maximum amount placed on the financial contributions from the Member State and the Community must be set at a realistic level which takes account of the main aim of genetic and cultural improvement and of the area of orchards which may be converted annually,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The additional flat-rate for the formation of organizations of nut and/or locust bean producters provided for in Article 14b of Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72 is hereby fixed as follows:</p>
      <p n="15">- 60 ecus/t for the tranche up to 1 000 tonnes.</p>
      <p n="16">- 70 ecus/t for the tranche from 1 000 to 2 000 tonnes.</p>
      <p n="17">- 75 ecus/t for the tranche above 2 000 tonnes</p>
      <p n="18">of nuts and/or locust beans marketed by producers' organizations during their first marketing year.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">The maximum amount per hectare referred to in Article 14d (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72 is hereby fixed at ECU 300 for the first five years and at ECU 210 for the following five years.</p>
      <p n="21">Article 3</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="23">It shall apply from 1 September 1989.</p>
      <p n="24">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="25">Done at Brussels, 20 March 1989.</p>
      <p n="26">For the Council</p>
      <p n="27">The President</p>
      <p n="28">C. ROMERO HERRERA</p>
      <p n="29">(1) OJ No L 118, 20. 5. 1972, p. 91.</p>
      <p n="30">(2) See page 3 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
