<TEI.2 id="jrc31997D0784-en" n="31997D0784" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31997D0784 English</title>
        <title>97/784/EC: Council Decision of 22 April 1997 concerning the conclusion of an Agreement on telecommunications procurement and an Agreement in the form of a memorandum concerning the procurement of private telecommunications operators between the European Community and the Republic of Korea</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31997D0784:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31997D0784:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1474</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1810</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">235</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4424</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5403</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31997D0784-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">97/784/EC: Council Decision of 22 April 1997 concerning the conclusion of an Agreement on telecommunications procurement and an Agreement in the form of a memorandum concerning the procurement of private telecommunications operators between the European Community and the Republic of Korea</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 22 April 1997 concerning the conclusion of an Agreement on telecommunications procurement and an Agreement in the form of a memorandum concerning the procurement of private telecommunications operators between the European Community and the Republic of Korea (97/784/EC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 113, in conjunction with Article 228 (2), first sentence thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas the Agreement on telecommunications procurement and the Agreement in the form of a memorandum concerning the procurement of private telecommunications operators between the European Community and the Republic of Korea should be approved;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the conclusion of the Agreement on telecommunications procurement and the Agreement in the form of a memorandum should be based on Article 113 of the Treaty because the Agreements apply only to products and services which are incidental to the procurement of these products;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas it is appropriate that the Council should authorize the Commission, in consultation with a special committee to be appointed by the Council, to approve modifications on behalf of the Community of Annex I to the Agreement on telecommunications procurement; whereas, however, such authorization will be limited to the modifications resulting from the application of the procedure of Article 8 of Council Directive 93/38/EEC of 14 June 1993 coordinating the procurement procedures of entities operating in the water, energy, transport and telecommunications sectors (1),</p>
      <p n="9">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The Agreement on telecommunications procurement and the Agreement in the form of a memorandum concerning the procurement of private telecommunications operators between the European Community and the Republic of Korea are hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="12">The texts of the Agreement and of the memorandum are attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the Agreement and the memorandum in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">The Commission is hereby authorized to approve, on behalf of the Community, modifications to Annex I to the Agreement on telecommunications procurement.</p>
      <p n="17">The Commission shall be assisted in this task by a special committee appointed by the Council.</p>
      <p n="18">The authorization referred to in the first subparagraph shall be limited to the modifications that will be necessary were the procedures laid down in Article 8 of Directive 93/38/EEC to be applied.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Luxembourg, 22 April 1997.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Council</p>
      <p n="21">The President</p>
      <p n="22">J. VAN AARTSEN</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ L 199, 9. 8. 1993, p. 84. Directive as amended by the 1994 Act of Accession.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
