<TEI.2 id="jrc31997R2596-en" n="31997R2596" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31997R2596 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 2596/97 of 18 December 1997 extending the period provided for in Article 149 (1) of the Act of Accession of Austria, Finland and Sweden</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>22 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31997R2596:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31997R2596:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1019</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1284</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1565</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2081</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2324</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4320</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31997R2596-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 2596/97 of 18 December 1997 extending the period provided for in Article 149 (1) of the Act of Accession of Austria, Finland and Sweden</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EC) No 2596/97 of 18 December 1997 extending the period provided for in Article 149 (1) of the Act of Accession of Austria, Finland and Sweden</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Act of Accession of Austria, Finland and Sweden, and in particular Article 149 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 149 (1) of the 1994 Act of Accession provides for a period during which transitional measures may be adopted to facilitate the transition from the regime existing in Austria, Finland and Sweden at the time of Accession to those resulting from the application of the common organization of the market under the conditions set out in the said Act and, in particular, to overcome the serious difficulties in applying the new regime from the date laid down; whereas that period expires on 31 December 1997;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, in certain sectors, these difficulties cannot be resolved by the date laid down; whereas the period in question should therefore be extended, as provided for in the Act; whereas the said period should be extended by one year;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas in the milk and milk products sector the requirements relating to the fat content of milk for human consumption continue to cause difficulties for Finland and Sweden; whereas those difficulties cannot be resolved by 31 December 1998; whereas the period in question should therefore be extended, as provided for in the 1994 Act of Accession, by two years in this specific case,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The period referred to in Article 149 (1) of the 1994 Act of Accession is hereby extended until 31 December 1998.</p>
      <p n="13">However, with regard to the requirements relating to the fat content of milk for human consumption produced in Finland and Sweden, the period is hereby extended until 31 December 1999.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 January 1998.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 18 December 1997.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Council</p>
      <p n="19">The President</p>
      <p n="20">F. BODEN</p>
      <p n="21">(1) OJ C 352, 20. 11. 1997, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="22">(2) Opinion delivered on 17 December 1997 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
