<TEI.2 id="jrc22003D0086-en" n="22003D0086" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 22003D0086 English</title>
        <title>Decision of the EEA Joint Committee No 86/2003 of 20 June 2003 amending Protocol 31 to the EEA Agreement, on cooperation in specific fields outside the four freedoms</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>48 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:22003D0086:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:22003D0086:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1474</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">206</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5618</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5864</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">616</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">6894</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc22003D0086-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Decision of the EEA Joint Committee No 86/2003 of 20 June 2003 amending Protocol 31 to the EEA Agreement, on cooperation in specific fields outside the four freedoms</head>
      <p n="2">Decision of the EEA Joint Committee</p>
      <p n="3">No 86/2003</p>
      <p n="4">of 20 June 2003</p>
      <p n="5">amending Protocol 31 to the EEA Agreement, on cooperation in specific fields outside the four freedoms</p>
      <p n="6">THE EEA JOINT COMMITTEE,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Agreement on the European Economic Area, as amended by the Protocol adjusting the Agreement on the European Economic Area, hereinafter referred to as "the Agreement", and in particular Articles 86 and 98 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Protocol 31 to the Agreement was amended by Decision of the EEA Joint Committee No 100/2000 of 10 November 2000(1).</p>
      <p n="10">(2) It is appropriate to extend the cooperation of the Contracting Parties to the Agreement to include Decision No 2045/2002/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 21 October 2002 amending Decision No 1720/1999/EC adopting a series of actions and measures in order to ensure interoperability of and access to trans-European networks for the electronic interchange of data between administrations (IDA)(2).</p>
      <p n="11">(3) It is appropriate to extend the cooperation of the Contracting Parties to the Agreement to include Decision No 2046/2002/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 21 October 2002 amending Decision No 1719/1999/EC on a series of guidelines, including the identification of projects of common interest, for trans-European networks for the electronic interchange of data between administrations (IDA)(3)</p>
      <p n="12">(4) Protocol 31 to the Agreement should therefore be amended in order to allow for this extended cooperation to take place from 1 January 2003,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Article 17(4) of Protocol 31 to the Agreement shall be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. The following shall be added in the second indent (Decision No 1719/1999/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council):</p>
      <p n="17">", as amended by:</p>
      <p n="18">- 32002 D 2046: Decision No 2046/2002/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 21 October 2002 (OJ L 316, 20.11.2002, p. 4)."</p>
      <p n="19">2. The following shall be added in the third indent (Decision No 1720/1999/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council):</p>
      <p n="20">", as amended by:</p>
      <p n="21">- 32002 D 2045: Decision No 2045/2002/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 21 October 2002 (OJ L 316, 20.11.2002, p. 1)."</p>
      <p n="22">Article 2</p>
      <p n="23">Point I (Projects of common interest) in Appendix 3 to Protocol 31 to the Agreement shall be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="24">1. The introductory text shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="25">"The EFTA States shall participate in the following projects of common interest in the sphere of trans-European networks for the interchange of data between administrations, resulting from Article 3(1) of Decision No 1719/1999/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council, as amended."</p>
      <p n="26">2. The following shall be added in section A (In General):</p>
      <p n="27">"- Implementation of networks which facilitate the cooperation between judicial authorities (this applies only for Iceland and Norway)."</p>
      <p n="28">3. Section B (Specific networks supporting EMU and Community policies and activities) shall be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="29">(a) the sixth indent shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="30">"- Telematic networks in the areas of education and culture, information, communication and audiovisual sector, notably for the exchange of information concerning content issues on open networks and to promote the development and free circulation of new audiovisual and information services."</p>
      <p n="31">(b) the eighth indent shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="32">"- Telematic networks in the areas of tourism, environment, consumer protection and public health protection for the support of information exchange between the Contracting Parties to the present Agreement."</p>
      <p n="33">(c) the following shall be added:</p>
      <p n="34">"- Telematic networks contributing to the objectives of the e-Europe initiative and related action plan, in particular the chapter on government online, aimed at benefiting citizens and enterprises.</p>
      <p n="35">- Telematic networks concerning immigration policy, notably through the implementation of improved electronic data exchange with the national administrations in order to facilitate information and consultation procedures (this applies only for Iceland and Norway)."</p>
      <p n="36">Article 3</p>
      <p n="37">This Decision shall enter into force on 21 June 2003, provided that all the notifications under Article 103(1) of the Agreement have been made to the EEA Joint Committee(4).</p>
      <p n="38">It shall apply from 1 January 2003.</p>
      <p n="39">Article 4</p>
      <p n="40">This Decision shall be published in the EEA Section of, and in the EEA Supplement to, the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="41">Done at Brussels, 20 June 2003.</p>
      <p n="42">For the EEA Joint Committee</p>
      <p n="43">The President</p>
      <p n="44">P. Westerlund</p>
      <p n="45">(1) OJ L 7, 11.1.2001, p. 32.</p>
      <p n="46">(2) OJ L 316, 20.11.2002, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="47">(3) OJ L 316, 20.11.2002, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="48">(4) No constitutional requirements indicated.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
