<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R1445-en" n="32003R1445" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R1445 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EC) No 1445/2003 of 21 January 2003 concerning the export of certain steel products from Romania to the Community for the period from the date of entry into force of this Regulation to the date of accession by Romania to the European Union (extension of the double-checking system)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>76 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1445:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1445:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3763</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3824</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4079</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">946</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R1445-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EC) No 1445/2003 of 21 January 2003 concerning the export of certain steel products from Romania to the Community for the period from the date of entry into force of this Regulation to the date of accession by Romania to the European Union (extension of the double-checking system)</head>
      <p n="2">Council Regulation (EC) No 1445/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 21 January 2003</p>
      <p n="4">concerning the export of certain steel products from Romania to the Community for the period from the date of entry into force of this Regulation to the date of accession by Romania to the European Union (extension of the double-checking system)</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 133 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) The Europe Agreement establishing an association between the European Communities and their Member States, of the one part, and Romania, of the other part(1), entered into force on 1 February 1995.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) The Parties have agreed, by Association Council Decision No 1/2003(2), to extend the double-checking system reintroduced by Decision No 3/2002(3) for the period from the date of entry into force of this Regulation to the date of accession by Romania to the European Union.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) It is consequently necessary to extend the Community implementing legislation introduced by Council Regulation (EC) No 1499/2002 of 20 June 2002, concerning the export of certain steel products from Romania to the Community for the period from 1 July to 31 December 2002 (double-checking system)(4),</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Regulation (EC) No 1499/2002 shall continue to apply for the period from the date of entry into force of this Regulation to the date of accession by Romania to the European Union, in accordance with the provisions of Decision No 1/2003 of the Association Council between the European Communities and their Member States, of the one part, and Romania, of the other part.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">Regulation (EC) No 1499/2002 shall in consequence be amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="17">1. In the title, preamble and Article 1(1) of the Regulation, references to the period "1 July to 31 December 2002" shall be replaced by references to "25 August 2003 to the date of accession by Romania to the European Union".</p>
      <p n="18">2. Annex IV to that Regulation shall be replaced by the text contained in the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 3</p>
      <p n="20">Goods shipped to the Community from 1 January 2003 to the date of entry into force of this Regulation shall be excluded from the scope of this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="21">Article 4</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 10th day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="23">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="24">Done at Brussels, 21 January 2003.</p>
      <p n="25">For the Council</p>
      <p n="26">The President</p>
      <p n="27">N. Christodoulakis</p>
      <p n="28">(1) OJ L 357, 31.12.1994, p. 2.</p>
      <p n="29">(2) See page 31 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="30">(3) OJ L 227, 23.8.2002, p. 38.</p>
      <p n="31">(4) OJ L 227, 23.8.2002, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="32">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="33">"ANNEX IV</p>
      <p n="34">LISTA DE LAS AUTORIDADES NACIONALES COMPETENTES/LISTE OVER KOMPETENTE NATIONALE MYNDIGHEDER/LISTE DER ZUSTÄNDIGEN BEHÖRDEN DER MITGLIEDSTAATEN/ΔΙΕΥΘΥΝΣΕΙΣ ΤΩΝ ΑΡΧΩΝ ΕΚΔΟΣΗΣ ΑΔΕΙΩΝ ΤΩΝ ΚΡΑΤΩΝ ΜΕΛΩΝ/LIST OF THE COMPETENT NATIONAL AUTHORITIES/LISTE DES AUTORITÉS NATIONALES COMPÉTENTES/ELENCO DELLE COMPETENTI AUTORITÀ NAZIONALI/LIJST VAN BEVOEGDE NATIONALE INSTANTIES/LISTA DAS AUTORIDADES NACIONAIS COMPETENTES/LUETTELO TOIMIVALTAISISTA KANSALLISISTA VIRANOMAISISTA/FÖRTECKNING ÖVER BEHÖRIGA NATIONELLA MYNDIGHETER</p>
      <p n="35">BELGIQUE/BELGIË</p>
      <p n="36">Ministère des affaires économiques Administration des relations économiques</p>
      <p n="37">Services Licences</p>
      <p n="38">Rue Général Leman 60 B - 1040 Bruxelles Télécopieur (32-2) 230 83 22 Ministerie van Economische Zaken Bestuur van de Economische Betrekkingen</p>
      <p n="39">Dienst Vergunningen</p>
      <p n="40">Generaal Lemanstraat 60 B - 1040 Brussel Fax (32-2) 230 83 22</p>
      <p n="41">DANMARK</p>
      <p n="42">Erhvervsfremme Styrelsen Økonomi- og Erhvervsministeriet Vejlsøvej 29 DK - 8600 Silkeborg Fax (45) 35 46 64 01</p>
      <p n="43">DEUTSCHLAND</p>
      <p n="44">Bundesamt für Wirtschaft und Ausfuhrkontrolle</p>
      <p n="45">(BAFA)</p>
      <p n="46">Frankfurter Straße 29-35 D - 65760 Eschborn 1 Fax: (49-6196) 942 26</p>
      <p n="47">ΕΛΛΑΔΑ</p>
      <p n="48">Υπουργείο Εθνικής Οικονομίας Γενική Γραμματεία Διεθνών Σχέσεων</p>
      <p n="49">Διεύθυνση Διεθνών Οικονομικών Ροών</p>
      <p n="50">Κορνάρου 1 GR - 105 63 Αθήνα Φαξ: (30-10) 328 60 94</p>
      <p n="51">ESPAÑA</p>
      <p n="52">Ministerio de Economía Secretaría General de Comercio Exterior Paseo de la Castellana, 162 E - 28046 Madrid Fax: (34) 915 63 18 23/913 49 38 31</p>
      <p n="53">FRANCE</p>
      <p n="54">Service des industries manufacturières DIGITIP 12, rue Villiot, bâtiment Le Bervil F - 75572 Paris Cedex 12 Télécopieur (33-1) 53 44 91 81</p>
      <p n="55">IRELAND</p>
      <p n="56">Department of Enterprise, Trade and Employment Import/Export Licensing, Block C</p>
      <p n="57">Earlsfort Centre</p>
      <p n="58">Hatch Street Dublin 2 Ireland Fax (353-1) 631 28 26</p>
      <p n="59">ITALIA</p>
      <p n="60">Ministero delle Attività produttive Direzione generale per la politica commerciale e per la gestione del regime degli scambi Viale America, 341 I - 00144 Roma Fax (39) 06 59 93 22 35/59 93 26 36</p>
      <p n="61">LUXEMBOURG</p>
      <p n="62">Ministère des affaires étrangères Office des licences BP 113 L - 2011 Luxembourg Télécopieur (352) 46 61 38</p>
      <p n="63">NEDERLAND</p>
      <p n="64">Belastingdienst/douane Centrale dienst voor in- en uitvoer Postbus 30003 Engelse Kamp 2 9700 RD Groningen Nederland Fax (31-50) 523 23 41</p>
      <p n="65">ÖSTERREICH</p>
      <p n="66">Bundesministerium für Wirtschaft und Arbeit Außenwirtschaftsadministration Landstrasser Hauptstraße 55-57 A - 1030 Wien Fax: (43-1) 711 00/83 86</p>
      <p n="67">PORTUGAL</p>
      <p n="68">Ministério das Finanças Direcção-Geral das Alfândegas e dos Impostos</p>
      <p n="69">Especiais sobre o Consumo</p>
      <p n="70">Rua Terreiro do Trigo, Edifício da Alfândega de Lisboa P - 1140-060 Lisboa Fax: (351-21) 881 42 61</p>
      <p n="71">SUOMI/FINLAND</p>
      <p n="72">Tullihallitus PL 512 FIN - 00101 Helsinki Faksi (358-9) 614 28 52</p>
      <p n="73">SVERIGE</p>
      <p n="74">Kommerskollegium Box 6803 S - 113 86 Stockholm Fax (46-8) 30 67 59</p>
      <p n="75">UNITED KINGDOM</p>
      <p n="76">Department of Trade and Industry Import Licensing Branch Queensway House - West Precinct Billingham, Cleveland TS23 2NF United Kingdom Fax (44-1642) 53 35 57"</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
