<TEI.2 id="jrc32003D0589-en" n="32003D0589" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003D0589 English</title>
        <title>2003/589/EC: Council Decision of 21 July 2003 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement for scientific and technological cooperation between the European Community and the Republic of Chile</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>25 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0589:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0589:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">223</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5383</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5404</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5965</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003D0589-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2003/589/EC: Council Decision of 21 July 2003 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement for scientific and technological cooperation between the European Community and the Republic of Chile</head>
      <p n="2">Council Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 21 July 2003</p>
      <p n="4">concerning the conclusion of the Agreement for scientific and technological cooperation between the European Community and the Republic of Chile</p>
      <p n="5">(2003/589/EC)</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 170(2) thereof, in conjunction with the first sentence of the first subparagraph of Article 300(2) and Article 300(3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission(1),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(2),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">(1) The Commission has negotiated with the Republic of Chile, on behalf of the Community, an Agreement for scientific and technological cooperation.</p>
      <p n="12">(2) This Agreement was signed, on behalf of the Community, on 23 September 2002 in Brussels, subject to a possible conclusion at a later date.</p>
      <p n="13">(3) The Agreement should be approved,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The Agreement for scientific and technological cooperation between the European Community and the Republic of Chile is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="17">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">The President of the Council shall, on behalf of the Community, give the notification provided for in Article 11 of the Agreement.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 21 July 2003.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">F. Frattini</p>
      <p n="24">(1) Proposal of 24 February 2003 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="25">(2) Opinion of 3 June 2003 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
