<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R1201-en" n="32003R1201" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R1201 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1201/2003 of 4 July 2003 deferring the final date for sowing certain arable crops in certain areas of Finland and Sweden in the 2003/04 marketing year</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1201:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1201:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1019</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2723</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4081</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4320</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5096</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R1201-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1201/2003 of 4 July 2003 deferring the final date for sowing certain arable crops in certain areas of Finland and Sweden in the 2003/04 marketing year</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1201/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 4 July 2003</p>
      <p n="4">deferring the final date for sowing certain arable crops in certain areas of Finland and Sweden in the 2003/04 marketing year</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 1251/1999 of 17 May 1999 establishing a support system for producers of certain arable crops(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1038/2001(2), and in particular the third indent of the second paragraph of Article 9 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Article 8(2) of Regulation (EC) No 1251/1999 lays down that, in order to qualify for area payments, producers must have sown the seed no later than 31 May preceding the relevant harvest.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) In Commission Regulation (EC) No 2316/1999 of 22 October 1999 laying down detailed rules for the application of Council Regulation (EC) No 1251/1999 establishing a support system for producers of certain arable crops(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1035/2003(4), the deadline of the sowing date was deferred from the 31 May to the 15 June in view of the weather conditions in Finland and Sweden.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) As a result of the particular weather conditions this year, it will not be possible to comply with the final dates for sowing in certain regions of Finland and Sweden.</p>
      <p n="12">(4) In these circumstances, the deadline for sowing for the 2003/04 marketing year should be deferred.</p>
      <p n="13">(5) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Cereals,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The final dates for sowing for the 2003/04 marketing year are fixed in the Annex for the crops and regions indicated.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="19">It shall apply from 16 June 2003.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 4 July 2003.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ L 160, 16.6.1999, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ L 145, 31.5.2001, p. 16.</p>
      <p n="27">(3) OJ L 280, 30.10.1999, p. 43.</p>
      <p n="28">(4) OJ L 150, 18.6.2003, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="29">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="30">Final dates for sowing for the 2003/04 marketing year</p>
      <p n="31">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
