<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R0047-en" n="32003R0047" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R0047 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 47/2003 of 10 January 2003 amending Annex I to Council Regulation (EC) No 2200/96</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R0047:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R0047:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1115</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1201</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1486</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1602</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2081</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2173</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R0047-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 47/2003 of 10 January 2003 amending Annex I to Council Regulation (EC) No 2200/96</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 47/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 10 January 2003</p>
      <p n="4">amending Annex I to Council Regulation (EC) No 2200/96</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 2200/96 of 28 October 1996 on the common organisation of the market in fruit and vegetables(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 545/2002(2), and in particular Article 2(3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 2200/96 lists the products which are to be supplied fresh to the consumer and are subject to standards.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) Consumer packaging containing different species of fruit and vegetables are becoming more common on the market and enable demand from certain consumers to be met.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) Fair trading requires fresh fruit and vegetables sold in the same package to be of uniform quality. This makes it necessary to extend the list of products subject to marketing standards to include other products when combined in sales packages with products already on that list.</p>
      <p n="12">(4) Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 2200/96 should therefore be amended.</p>
      <p n="13">(5) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Fresh Fruit and Vegetables,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The following is added to Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 2200/96:</p>
      <p n="17">"Other products referred to in Article 1, when combined in a sales package of a net weight of less than three kilograms with at least one of the products in this Annex."</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 20th day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 10 January 2003.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ L 297, 21.11.1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ L 84, 28.3.2002, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
