<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R2000-en" n="32003R2000" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R2000 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2000/2003 of 13 November 2003 fixing, for 2004, the reduction percentages to be applied to applications for an allocation by non-traditional operators under the tariff quotas for imports of bananas</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R2000:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R2000:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1120</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">161</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R2000-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2000/2003 of 13 November 2003 fixing, for 2004, the reduction percentages to be applied to applications for an allocation by non-traditional operators under the tariff quotas for imports of bananas</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2000/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 13 November 2003</p>
      <p n="4">fixing, for 2004, the reduction percentages to be applied to applications for an allocation by non-traditional operators under the tariff quotas for imports of bananas</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 404/93 of 13 February 1993 on the common organisation of the market in bananas(1),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Commission Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 of 7 May 2001 laying down detailed rules for applying Council Regulation (EEC) No 404/93 as regards the arrangements for importing bananas into the Community(2), and in particular Article 9(2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Member States' notifications pursuant to Article 9(1) of Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 indicate that the sum of allocations applied for is 4961407,000 tonnes for all non-traditional operators A/B and 399750,000 tonnes for all non-traditional operators C.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) The percentages to be applied for determining the allocations for non-traditional operators under the tariff quotas A/B and C for 2004 should therefore be fixed.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) It should be pointed out that the provisions of this Regulation are adopted without prejudice to measures that may be taken subsequently in connection with enlargement of the Union.</p>
      <p n="13">(4) So that the operators have sufficient time to lodge licence applications for the first quarter of 2004, this Regulation must enter into force immediately,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">For the tariff quotas A/B and C provided for in Article 18 of Regulation (EEC) No 404/93, the allocation to be granted to each non-traditional operator for 2004 pursuant to Article 9(2) of Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 shall be the following percentage of the allocation applied for:</p>
      <p n="17">(a) for each non-traditional operator A/B: 9,09036 %,</p>
      <p n="18">(b) for each non-traditional operator C: 20,63789 %.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall enter into force on 14 November 2003.</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Brussels, 13 November 2003.</p>
      <p n="23">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">J. M. Silva Rodríguez</p>
      <p n="25">Agriculture Director-General</p>
      <p n="26">(1) OJ L 47, 25.2.1993, p. 1; Regulation as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2587/2001 (OJ L 345, 29.12.2001, p. 13).</p>
      <p n="27">(2) OJ L 126, 8.5.2001, p. 6; Regulation as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1439/2003 (OJ L 204, 13.8.2003, p. 30).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
