<TEI.2 id="jrc32003D0609-en" n="32003D0609" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003D0609 English</title>
        <title>2003/609/EC: Commission Decision of 18 August 2003 laying down special conditions governing imports of fishery products from Saint Pierre et Miquelon (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2003) 2977)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>50 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0609:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0609:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">192</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2718</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2771</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3823</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5369</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003D0609-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2003/609/EC: Commission Decision of 18 August 2003 laying down special conditions governing imports of fishery products from Saint Pierre et Miquelon (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2003) 2977)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 18 August 2003</p>
      <p n="4">laying down special conditions governing imports of fishery products from Saint Pierre et Miquelon</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2003) 2977)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2003/609/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 91/493/EEC of 22 July 1991 laying down the health conditions for the production and the placing on the market of fishery products(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 806/2003(2), and in particular Article 11 thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) An inspection has been carried out on behalf of the Commission in Saint Pierre et Miquelon to verify the conditions under which fishery products are produced, stored and dispatched to the Community.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) The requirements in the legislation of Saint Pierre et Miquelon on health inspection and monitoring of fishery products may be considered equivalent to those laid down in Directive 91/493/EEC.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) In particular, the "Direction des Services de l'Agriculture: Services Vétérinaires (DSA)" belonging to the "Ministère français de l'agriculture et de la pêche", is capable of effectively verifying the implementation of the legislation in force.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) The DSA has provided official assurances regarding compliance with the standards for health controls and monitoring of fishery products as set out in Chapter V of the Annex to Directive 91/493/EEC and regarding the fulfilment of hygienic requirements equivalent to those laid down by that Directive.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) It is appropriate to lay down detailed provisions concerning fishery products imported into the Community from Saint Pierre et Miquelon, in accordance with Directive 91/493/EEC.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) It is also necessary to draw up a list of approved establishments, factory vessels, or cold stores, and a list of freezer vessels equipped in accordance with the requirements of Council Directive 92/48/EEC of 16 June 1992 laying down the minimum hygiene rules applicable to fishery products caught on board of certain vessels in accordance with Article 3(1)(a)(I) of Directive 91/493/EEC(3). These lists should be drawn up on the basis of a communication from the DSA to the Commission.</p>
      <p n="18">(7) It is appropriate for the present Decision to be applied 45 days after its publication providing for the necessary transitional period.</p>
      <p n="19">(8) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="20">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="21">Article 1</p>
      <p n="22">The "Direction des Services de l'Agriculture: Services Vétérinaires (DSA)" of the "Ministère français de l'agriculture et de la pêche", shall be the competent authority in Saint Pierre et Miquelon identified for the purposes of verifying and certifying compliance of fishery products with the requirements of Directive 91/493/EEC.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">Fishery products imported into the Community from Saint Pierre et Miquelon shall meet the requirements set out in Articles 3, 4 and 5.</p>
      <p n="25">Article 3</p>
      <p n="26">1. Each consignment shall be accompanied by a numbered original health certificate in accordance with the model in Annex I and comprising a single sheet, duly completed, signed and dated.</p>
      <p n="27">2. The certificate shall be drawn up in at least one official language of the Member State where the checks are carried out.</p>
      <p n="28">3. The certificate shall bear the name, capacity and signature of the representative of the DSA, and the latter's official stamp in a colour different from that of the endorsements.</p>
      <p n="29">Article 4</p>
      <p n="30">The fishery products shall come from approved establishments, factory vessels, or cold stores, or from registered freezer vessels listed in Annex II.</p>
      <p n="31">Article 5</p>
      <p n="32">All packages shall bear the words "SAINT PIERRE ET MIQUELON" and the approval/registration number of the establishment, factory vessel, cold store or freezer vessel of origin in indelible letters, except in the case of frozen fishery products in bulk and intended for the manufacture of preserved foods.</p>
      <p n="33">Article 6</p>
      <p n="34">This Decision shall apply from 4 October 2003.</p>
      <p n="35">Article 7</p>
      <p n="36">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="37">Done at Brussels, 18 August 2003.</p>
      <p n="38">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="39">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="40">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="41">(1) OJ L 268, 24.9.1991, p. 15.</p>
      <p n="42">(2) OJ L 122, 16.5.2003, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="43">(3) OJ L 187, 7.7.1992, p. 41.</p>
      <p n="44">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="45">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2003210EN.003202.TIF"&gt;</p>
      <p n="46">&gt;PIC FILE= "L_2003210EN.003301.TIF"&gt;</p>
      <p n="47">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="48">LIST OF ESTABLISHMENTS AND VESSELS</p>
      <p n="49">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="50">PP: Processing Plant</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
