<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R1303-en" n="32003R1303" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R1303 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1303/2003 of 23 July 2003 amending Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 laying down detailed rules for applying Council Regulation (EEC) No 404/93 as regards the arrangements for importing bananas into the Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1303:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1303:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1120</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">161</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R1303-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1303/2003 of 23 July 2003 amending Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 laying down detailed rules for applying Council Regulation (EEC) No 404/93 as regards the arrangements for importing bananas into the Community</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1303/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 23 July 2003</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 laying down detailed rules for applying Council Regulation (EEC) No 404/93 as regards the arrangements for importing bananas into the Community</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 404/93 of 13 February 1993 on the common organisation of the market in bananas(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 2587/2001(2), and in particular Article 20 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) Commission Regulation (EC) No 896/2001(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 323/2003(4), lays down detailed rules for the management of the tariff import quotas provided for in Article 18(1) of Regulation (EEC) No 404/93.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) According to Article 8(1) of Regulation (EC) No 896/2001, the request for annual quota allocation of non-traditional operators may not cover a quantity greater than 12,5 % of the total quantity allocated annually to non-traditional operators. The request shall be accompanied by proof that a security of EUR 150 per tonne requested has been lodged.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) Experience of applying the Community banana import regime has shown on the one hand that the total quantity of allocations applied far exceeds the quantity available to non-traditional operators, and on the other hand that the number of non-traditional operators has continuously increased. Therefore, a high percentage reduction is applied to each application for annual allocation of non-traditional operators. Taking these elements into consideration, the maximum percentage of 12,5 % should be decreased. The decrease takes into account the different percentage reductions in Quotas A and B and Quota C and also future developments of the annual allocation to non-traditional operators.</p>
      <p n="12">(4) Regulation (EC) No 896/2001 should be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="13">(5) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Bananas,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">In Article 8(1), second subparagraph, (a), of Regulation (EC) No 896/2001, the percentage "12,5" is replaced by the percentage "5".</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 23 July 2003.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="23">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ L 47, 25.2.1993, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="25">(2) OJ L 345, 29.12.2001, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) OJ L 126, 8.5.2001, p. 6.</p>
      <p n="27">(4) OJ L 47, 21.2.2003, p. 12.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
