<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R1885-en" n="32003R1885" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R1885 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 1885/2003 of 27 October 2003 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>76 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1885:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R1885:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1264</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2709</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3275</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5283</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R1885-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1885/2003 of 27 October 2003 amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1885/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 27 October 2003</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 delimiting the homogenous olive oil production zones</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation No 136/66/EEC of 22 September 1966 on the common organisation of the market in oils and fats(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1513/2001(2),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 of 17 July 1984 laying down general rules on the granting of aid for the production of olive oil and of aid to olive oil producer organisations(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1639/98(4), and in particular Article 19 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="10">(1) Article 18 of Regulation (EEC) No 2261/84 stipulates that olive yields and oil yields are to be fixed by homogenous production zones on the basis of the figures supplied by producer Member States.</p>
      <p n="11">(2) The production zones are delimited in the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 2138/97(5), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1836/2002(6). For administrative and structural reasons the homogeneous production zones in Greece, Spain and Italy should be amended for the marketing year 2002/03.</p>
      <p n="12">(3) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Oils and Fats,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2138/97 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. in point A the parts relating to the provinces of Brindisi, Lecce and Sassari are replaced respectively by the texts in Annex I to this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="17">2. in point C, the heading "Νομός Αχαΐας" is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="18">(a) in zone 3, the names of the municipalities "Aγίας Βαρβάρας, Αγίας Μαρίνας, Αλεποχωρίου, Βελιμαχίου, Δροσιάς, Ερυμανθείας, Καλανίστρας, Καλάνου, Καλεντζίου, Καλουσίου, Κάλφα, Καταρράκτη, Λακκωμάτων, Μανεσίου, Νέου Κομπηγαδίου, Πορτών, Ρουπακίας, Σκιαδά, Σκούρα, Σπαρτιάς, Σταυροδρομίου, Χιόνας, Χρυσοπηγής" are deleted;</p>
      <p n="19">(b) the following zone 4 is added:</p>
      <p n="20">"Ζώνη 4:</p>
      <p n="21">Κοινότητες: Αγίας Βαρβάρας, Αγίας Μαρίνας, Αλεποχωρίου, Βελιμαχίου, Δροσιάς, Ερυμανθείας, Καλανίστρας, Καλάνου, Καλεντζίου, Καλουσίου, Κάλφα, Καταρράκτη, Λακκωμάτων, Μανεσίου, Νέου Κομπηγαδίου, Πορτών, Ρουπακίας, Σκιαδά, Σκούρα, Σπαρτιάς, Σταυροδρομίου, Χιόνας, Χρυσοπηγής.";</p>
      <p n="22">3. point D is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="23">(a) under the heading "Comunidad autónoma: Andalucía", the part relating to the province of "Huelva" is replaced by the text in Annex II to this Regulation;</p>
      <p n="24">(b) the heading "Comunidad autónoma: Aragón" is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="25">(i) the municipality of "Blesa" is added to zone 3 of the province of "Teruel";</p>
      <p n="26">(ii) the municipality of "Pradilla de Ebro" is added to zone 4 of the province of "Zaragoza";</p>
      <p n="27">(iii) the municipality of "Villanueva de Huerva" is added to zone 5 of the province of "Zaragoza";</p>
      <p n="28">(c) the headings "Comunidad autónoma: Castilla y León" and "Comunidad autónoma: Madrid" are replaced respectively by the texts in Annex III to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="29">Article 2</p>
      <p n="30">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="31">It shall apply from 1 November 2002.</p>
      <p n="32">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="33">Done at Brussels, 27 October 2003.</p>
      <p n="34">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="35">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="36">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="37">(1) OJ 172, 30.9.1966 p. 3025/66.</p>
      <p n="38">(2) OJ L 201, 26.7.2001, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="39">(3) OJ L 208, 3.8.1984, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="40">(4) OJ L 210, 28.7.1998, p. 38.</p>
      <p n="41">(5) OJ L 297, 31.10.1997, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="42">(6) OJ L 278, 16.10.2002, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="43">ANEXO I/BILAG I/ANHANG I/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ I/ANNEX I/ANNEXE I/ALLEGATO I/BIJLAGE I/ANEXO I/LIITE I/BILAGA I</p>
      <p n="44">"Brindisi:</p>
      <p n="45">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="46">2. Brindisi, Cellino San Marco, Erchie, Francavilla Fontana, Latiano, Mesagne, Oria, San Donaci, San Pancrazio Salentino, San Pietro Vernotico, Torchiarolo, Torre Santa Susanna."</p>
      <p n="47">"Lecce:</p>
      <p n="48">1. (*)</p>
      <p n="49">2. Aradeo, Bagnolo del Salento, Calimera, Cannole, Caprarica di Lecce, Carpignano Salentino, Castri di Lecce, Castrignano de' Greci, Castro Marino, Copertino, Corigliano d'Otranto, Cursi, Galatina, Galatone, Giuggianello, Giurdignano, Lequile, Leverano, Maglie, Martano, Martignano, Melendugno, Melpignano, Minervino di Lecce, Muro Leccese, Nardò, Neviano, Ortelle, Otranto, Palmariggi, Poggiardo, Porto Cesareo, San Cesario di Lecce, San Donato di Lecce, San Pietro in Lama, Sanarica, Santa Cesarea Terme, Seclì, Sogliano Cavour, Soleto, Sternatia, Surano, Uggiano la Chiesa, Vernole, Zollino.</p>
      <p n="50">3. Acquarica del Capo, Alessano, Alezio, Alliste, Andrano, Botrugno, Casarano, Castrignano del Capo, Collepasso, Corsano, Cutrofiano, Diso, Gagliano del Capo, Gallipoli, Matino, Melissano, Miggiano, Montesano Salentino, Morciano di Leuca, Nociglia, Parabita, Patù, Presicce, Racale, Ruffano, Salve, San Cassiano, Sannicola, Scorrano, Specchia, Spongano, Supersano, Taurisano, Taviano, Tiggiano, Tricase, Tuglie, Ugento."</p>
      <p n="51">"Sassari:</p>
      <p n="52">1. Alghero, Sennori, Sorso, Uri, Usini.</p>
      <p n="53">2. (*)"</p>
      <p n="54">ANEXO II/BILAG II/ANHANG II/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ II/ANNEX II/ANNEXE II/ALLEGATO II/BIJLAGE II/ANEXO II/LIITE II/BILAGA II</p>
      <p n="55">"Huelva:</p>
      <p n="56">1. Alájar, Almonaster la Real, Aracena, Aroche, Arroyomolinos de León, Berrocal, Cabezas Rubias, Cala, Calañas, El Campillo, Campofrío, Cañaveral de León, Castaño del Robledo, El Cerro de Andévalo, Corteconcepción, Cortegana, Cortelazor, Cumbres de Enmedio, Cumbres de San Bartolomé, Cumbres Mayores, Encinasola, Fuenteheridos, Galaroza, La Granada de Río Tinto, Higuera de la Sierra, Hinojales, Jabugo, Linares de la Sierra, Los Marines, Minas de Riotinto, La Nava, Nerva, Puerto Moral, Rosal de la Frontera, Santa Ana la Real, Santa Bárbara de Casa, Santa Olalla del Cala, Valdelarco, Valverde del Camino, Villanueva de las Cruces, Zalamea la Real, Zufre.</p>
      <p n="57">2. Beas, Bollullos Par del Condado, Bonares, Chucena, Escacena del Campo, Manzanilla, Niebla, La Palma del Condado, Paterna del Campo, Rociana del Condado, San Juan del Puerto, Trigueros, Villalba del Alcor, Villarrasa.</p>
      <p n="58">3. Aljaraque, El Almendro, Almonte, Alosno, Ayamonte, Cartaya, Gibraleón, El Granado, Hinojos, Huelva, Isla Cristina, Lepe, Lucena del Puerto, Moguer, Palos de la Frontera, Paymogo, Puebla de Guzmán, Punta Umbría, San Bartolomé de la Torre, San Silvestre de Guzmán, Sanlúcar de Guadiana, Villablanca, Villanueva de los Castillejos."</p>
      <p n="59">ANEXO III/BILAG III/ANHANG III/ΠΑΡΑΡΤΗΜΑ III/ANNEX III/ANNEXE III/ALLEGATO III/BIJLAGE III/ANEXO III/LIITE III/BILAGA III</p>
      <p n="60">"Comunidad autónoma: Castilla y León</p>
      <p n="61">Ávila:</p>
      <p n="62">1. Arenas de San Pedro, Candeleda, Poyales del Hoyo, Proindiviso Arenas-Candeleda.</p>
      <p n="63">2. Mombeltrán, Guisando, El Hornillo, El Arenal, Cuevas del Valle, Villarejo del Valle, San Esteban del Valle, Santa Cruz del Valle.</p>
      <p n="64">3. Lanzahita, Pedro Bernardo, Gavilanes, Mijares, Casavieja, Piedralaves, La Adrada, Sotillo de la Adrada, Navahondilla, Santa María del Tiétar, Higuera de las Dueñas, Fresnedilla.</p>
      <p n="65">4. Cebreros, El Barraco, El Tiemblo, El Hoyo de Pinares, San Juan de la Nava.</p>
      <p n="66">Salamanca:</p>
      <p n="67">1. Ahigal de los Aceiteros, Aldeadávila de la Ribera, La Fregeneda, Hinojosa de Duero, Lumbrales, Masueco de la Ribera, Mieza, Pereña de la Ribera, San Felices de los Gallegos, Saucelle, Sobradillo, Villarino de los Aires, Vilvestre.</p>
      <p n="68">2. Casas del Conde, Cepeda, Cerro (El), Colmenar de Montemayor, Garcibuey, Herguijuela de la Sierra, Lagunilla, Miranda del Castañar, Mogarraz, Molinillo, Pinedas, San Esteban de la Sierra, Santibáñez de la Sierra, Madroñal, San Miguel de Valero, San Martín del Castañar, Sequeros, Sotoserrano, Valero de la Sierra, Valdelageve, Villanueva del Conde.</p>
      <p n="69">Valladolid:</p>
      <p n="70">1. Fuensaldaña, Medina del Campo, Pozaldez, Rueda.</p>
      <p n="71">Zamora:</p>
      <p n="72">1. Fariza, Fermoselle, Manganeses de la Lampreana, Moralina, Trabazos, Villabrázaro, Villar del Buey."</p>
      <p n="73">"Comunidad autónoma: Madrid</p>
      <p n="74">Madrid:</p>
      <p n="75">1. Aranjuez, Arganda del Rey, Belmonte de Tajo, Campo Real, Carabaña, Ciempozuelos, Colmenar de Oreja, Chinchón, Fuenlabrada, Getafe, Humanes de Madrid, Loeches, Mejorada del Campo, Morata de Tajuña, Parla, Perales de Tajuña, Pinto, San Martín de la Vega, Santos Humosa (Los), Tielmes, Titulcia, Torrejón de Velasco, Torres de la Alameda, Valdaracete, Valdilecha, Valdelaguna, Valdemoro, Velilla de San Antonio, Villaconejos, Villalbilla, Villarejo de Salvanés.</p>
      <p n="76">2. (*)"</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
