<TEI.2 id="jrc32003L0004-en" n="32003L0004" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003L0004 English</title>
        <title>Directive 2003/4/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2003 on public access to environmental information and repealing Council Directive 90/313/EEC</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>170 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003L0004:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003L0004:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2470</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">441</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">448</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">453</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">513</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">6621</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003L0004-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Directive 2003/4/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2003 on public access to environmental information and repealing Council Directive 90/313/EEC</head>
      <p n="2">Directive 2003/4/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council</p>
      <p n="3">of 28 January 2003</p>
      <p n="4">on public access to environmental information and repealing Council Directive 90/313/EEC</p>
      <p n="5">THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 175(1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission(1),</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the opinion of the European Economic and Social Committee(2),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the Committee of the Regions(3),</p>
      <p n="10">Acting in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 251 of the Treaty(4) in the light of the joint text approved by the Conciliation Committee on 8 November 2002,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) Increased public access to environmental information and the dissemination of such information contribute to a greater awareness of environmental matters, a free exchange of views, more effective participation by the public in environmental decision-making and, eventually, to a better environment.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) Council Directive 90/313/EEC of 7 June 1990 on the freedom of access to information on the environment(5) initiated a process of change in the manner in which public authorities approach the issue of openness and transparency, establishing measures for the exercise of the right of public access to environmental information which should be developed and continued. This Directive expands the existing access granted under Directive 90/313/EEC.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) Article 8 of that Directive requires Member States to report to the Commission on the experience gained, in the light of which the Commission is required to make a report to the European Parliament and to the Council together with any proposal for revision of the Directive which it may consider appropriate.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) The report produced under Article 8 of that Directive identifies concrete problems encountered in the practical application of the Directive.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) On 25 June 1998 the European Community signed the UN/ECE Convention on Access to Information, Public Participation in Decision-Making and Access to Justice in Environmental Matters ("the Aarhus Convention"). Provisions of Community law must be consistent with that Convention with a view to its conclusion by the European Community.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) It is appropriate in the interest of increased transparency to replace Directive 90/313/EEC rather than to amend it, so as to provide interested parties with a single, clear and coherent legislative text.</p>
      <p n="18">(7) Disparities between the laws in force in the Member States concerning access to environmental information held by public authorities can create inequality within the Community as regards access to such information or as regards conditions of competition.</p>
      <p n="19">(8) It is necessary to ensure that any natural and legal person has a right of access to environmental information held by or for public authorities without his having to state an interest.</p>
      <p n="20">(9) It is also necessary that public authorities make available and disseminate environmental information to the general public to the widest extent possible, in particular by using information and communication technologies. The future development of these technologies should be taken into account in the reporting on, and reviewing of, this Directive.</p>
      <p n="21">(10) The definition of environmental information should be clarified so as to encompass information in any form on the state of the environment, on factors, measures or activities affecting or likely to affect the environment or designed to protect it, on cost-benefit and economic analyses used within the framework of such measures or activities and also information on the state of human health and safety, including the contamination of the food chain, conditions of human life, cultural sites and built structures in as much as they are, or may be, affected by any of those matters.</p>
      <p n="22">(11) To take account of the principle in Article 6 of the Treaty, that environmental protection requirements should be integrated into the definition and implementation of Community policies and activities, the definition of public authorities should be expanded so as to encompass government or other public administration at national, regional or local level whether or not they have specific responsibilities for the environment. The definition should likewise be expanded to include other persons or bodies performing public administrative functions in relation to the environment under national law, as well as other persons or bodies acting under their control and having public responsibilities or functions in relation to the environment.</p>
      <p n="23">(12) Environmental information which is physically held by other bodies on behalf of public authorities should also fall within the scope of this Directive.</p>
      <p n="24">(13) Environmental information should be made available to applicants as soon as possible and within a reasonable time and having regard to any timescale specified by the applicant.</p>
      <p n="25">(14) Public authorities should make environmental information available in the form or format requested by an applicant unless it is already publicly available in another form or format or it is reasonable to make it available in another form or format. In addition, public authorities should be required to make all reasonable efforts to maintain the environmental information held by or for them in forms or formats that are readily reproducible and accessible by electronic means.</p>
      <p n="26">(15) Member States should determine the practical arrangements under which such information is effectively made available. These arrangements shall guarantee that the information is effectively and easily accessible and progressively becomes available to the public through public telecommunications networks, including publicly accessible lists of public authorities and registers or lists of environmental information held by or for public authorities.</p>
      <p n="27">(16) The right to information means that the disclosure of information should be the general rule and that public authorities should be permitted to refuse a request for environmental information in specific and clearly defined cases. Grounds for refusal should be interpreted in a restrictive way, whereby the public interest served by disclosure should be weighed against the interest served by the refusal. The reasons for a refusal should be provided to the applicant within the time limit laid down in this Directive.</p>
      <p n="28">(17) Public authorities should make environmental information available in part where it is possible to separate out any information falling within the scope of the exceptions from the rest of the information requested.</p>
      <p n="29">(18) Public authorities should be able to make a charge for supplying environmental information but such a charge should be reasonable. This implies that, as a general rule, charges may not exceed actual costs of producing the material in question. Instances where advance payment will be required should be limited. In particular cases, where public authorities make available environmental information on a commercial basis, and where this is necessary in order to guarantee the continuation of collecting and publishing such information, a market-based charge is considered to be reasonable; an advance payment may be required. A schedule of charges should be published and made available to applicants together with information on the circumstances in which a charge may be levied or waived.</p>
      <p n="30">(19) Applicants should be able to seek an administrative or judicial review of the acts or omissions of a public authority in relation to a request.</p>
      <p n="31">(20) Public authorities should seek to guarantee that when environmental information is compiled by them or on their behalf, the information is comprehensible, accurate and comparable. As this is an important factor in assessing the quality of the information supplied the method used in compiling the information should also be disclosed upon request.</p>
      <p n="32">(21) In order to increase public awareness in environmental matters and to improve environmental protection, public authorities should, as appropriate, make available and disseminate information on the environment which is relevant to their functions, in particular by means of computer telecommunication and/or electronic technology, where available.</p>
      <p n="33">(22) This Directive should be evaluated every four years, after its entry into force, in the light of experience and after submission of the relevant reports by the Member States, and be subject to revision on that basis. The Commission should submit an evaluation report to the European Parliament and the Council.</p>
      <p n="34">(23) Since the objectives of the proposed Directive cannot be sufficiently achieved by the Member States and can therefore be better achieved at Community level, the Community may adopt measures, in accordance with the principle of subsidiarity as set out in Article 5 of the Treaty. In accordance with the principle of proportionality, as set out in that Article, this Directive does not go beyond what is necessary in order to achieve those objectives.</p>
      <p n="35">(24) The provisions of this Directive shall not affect the right of a Member State to maintain or introduce measures providing for broader access to information than required by this Directive,</p>
      <p n="36">HAVE ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="37">Article 1</p>
      <p n="38">Objectives</p>
      <p n="39">The objectives of this Directive are:</p>
      <p n="40">(a) to guarantee the right of access to environmental information held by or for public authorities and to set out the basic terms and conditions of, and practical arrangements for, its exercise; and</p>
      <p n="41">(b) to ensure that, as a matter of course, environmental information is progressively made available and disseminated to the public in order to achieve the widest possible systematic availability and dissemination to the public of environmental information. To this end the use, in particular, of computer telecommunication and/or electronic technology, where available, shall be promoted.</p>
      <p n="42">Article 2</p>
      <p n="43">Definitions</p>
      <p n="44">For the purposes of this Directive:</p>
      <p n="45">1. "Environmental information" shall mean any information in written, visual, aural, electronic or any other material form on:</p>
      <p n="46">(a) the state of the elements of the environment, such as air and atmosphere, water, soil, land, landscape and natural sites including wetlands, coastal and marine areas, biological diversity and its components, including genetically modified organisms, and the interaction among these elements;</p>
      <p n="47">(b) factors, such as substances, energy, noise, radiation or waste, including radioactive waste, emissions, discharges and other releases into the environment, affecting or likely to affect the elements of the environment referred to in (a);</p>
      <p n="48">(c) measures (including administrative measures), such as policies, legislation, plans, programmes, environmental agreements, and activities affecting or likely to affect the elements and factors referred to in (a) and (b) as well as measures or activities designed to protect those elements;</p>
      <p n="49">(d) reports on the implementation of environmental legislation;</p>
      <p n="50">(e) cost-benefit and other economic analyses and assumptions used within the framework of the measures and activities referred to in (c); and</p>
      <p n="51">(f) the state of human health and safety, including the contamination of the food chain, where relevant, conditions of human life, cultural sites and built structures inasmuch as they are or may be affected by the state of the elements of the environment referred to in (a) or, through those elements, by any of the matters referred to in (b) and (c).</p>
      <p n="52">2. "Public authority" shall mean:</p>
      <p n="53">(a) government or other public administration, including public advisory bodies, at national, regional or local level;</p>
      <p n="54">(b) any natural or legal person performing public administrative functions under national law, including specific duties, activities or services in relation to the environment; and</p>
      <p n="55">(c) any natural or legal person having public responsibilities or functions, or providing public services, relating to the environment under the control of a body or person falling within (a) or (b).</p>
      <p n="56">Member States may provide that this definition shall not include bodies or institutions when acting in a judicial or legislative capacity. If their constitutional provisions at the date of adoption of this Directive make no provision for a review procedure within the meaning of Article 6, Member States may exclude those bodies or institutions from that definition.</p>
      <p n="57">3. "Information held by a public authority" shall mean environmental information in its possession which has been produced or received by that authority.</p>
      <p n="58">4. "Information held for a public authority" shall mean environmental information which is physically held by a natural or legal person on behalf of a public authority.</p>
      <p n="59">5. "Applicant" shall mean any natural or legal person requesting environmental information.</p>
      <p n="60">6. "Public" shall mean one or more natural or legal persons, and, in accordance with national legislation or practice, their associations, organisations or groups.</p>
      <p n="61">Article 3</p>
      <p n="62">Access to environmental information upon request</p>
      <p n="63">1. Member States shall ensure that public authorities are required, in accordance with the provisions of this Directive, to make available environmental information held by or for them to any applicant at his request and without his having to state an interest.</p>
      <p n="64">2. Subject to Article 4 and having regard to any timescale specified by the applicant, environmental information shall be made available to an applicant:</p>
      <p n="65">(a) as soon as possible or, at the latest, within one month after the receipt by the public authority referred to in paragraph 1 of the applicant's request; or</p>
      <p n="66">(b) within two months after the receipt of the request by the public authority if the volume and the complexity of the information is such that the one-month period referred to in (a) cannot be complied with. In such cases, the applicant shall be informed as soon as possible, and in any case before the end of that one-month period, of any such extension and of the reasons for it.</p>
      <p n="67">3. If a request is formulated in too general a manner, the public authority shall as soon as possible, and at the latest within the timeframe laid down in paragraph 2(a), ask the applicant to specify the request and shall assist the applicant in doing so, e.g. by providing information on the use of the public registers referred to in paragraph 5(c). The public authorities may, where they deem it appropriate, refuse the request under Article 4(1)(c).</p>
      <p n="68">4. Where an applicant requests a public authority to make environmental information available in a specific form or format (including in the form of copies), the public authority shall make it so available unless:</p>
      <p n="69">(a) it is already publicly available in another form or format, in particular under Article 7, which is easily accessible by applicants; or</p>
      <p n="70">(b) it is reasonable for the public authority to make it available in another form or format, in which case reasons shall be given for making it available in that form or format.</p>
      <p n="71">For the purposes of this paragraph, public authorities shall make all reasonable efforts to maintain environmental information held by or for them in forms or formats that are readily reproducible and accessible by computer telecommunications or by other electronic means.</p>
      <p n="72">The reasons for a refusal to make information available, in full or in part, in the form or format requested shall be provided to the applicant within the time limit referred to in paragraph 2(a).</p>
      <p n="73">5. For the purposes of this Article, Member States shall ensure that:</p>
      <p n="74">(a) officials are required to support the public in seeking access to information;</p>
      <p n="75">(b) lists of public authorities are publicly accessible; and</p>
      <p n="76">(c) the practical arrangements are defined for ensuring that the right of access to environmental information can be effectively exercised, such as:</p>
      <p n="77">- the designation of information officers;</p>
      <p n="78">- the establishment and maintenance of facilities for the examination of the information required,</p>
      <p n="79">- registers or lists of the environmental information held by public authorities or information points, with clear indications of where such information can be found.</p>
      <p n="80">Member States shall ensure that public authorities inform the public adequately of the rights they enjoy as a result of this Directive and to an appropriate extent provide information, guidance and advice to this end.</p>
      <p n="81">Article 4</p>
      <p n="82">Exceptions</p>
      <p n="83">1. Member States may provide for a request for environmental information to be refused if:</p>
      <p n="84">(a) the information requested is not held by or for the public authority to which the request is addressed. In such a case, where that public authority is aware that the information is held by or for another public authority, it shall, as soon as possible, transfer the request to that other authority and inform the applicant accordingly or inform the applicant of the public authority to which it believes it is possible to apply for the information requested;</p>
      <p n="85">(b) the request is manifestly unreasonable;</p>
      <p n="86">(c) the request is formulated in too general a manner, taking into account Article 3(3);</p>
      <p n="87">(d) the request concerns material in the course of completion or unfinished documents or data;</p>
      <p n="88">(e) the request concerns internal communications, taking into account the public interest served by disclosure.</p>
      <p n="89">Where a request is refused on the basis that it concerns material in the course of completion, the public authority shall state the name of the authority preparing the material and the estimated time needed for completion.</p>
      <p n="90">2. Member States may provide for a request for environmental information to be refused if disclosure of the information would adversely affect:</p>
      <p n="91">(a) the confidentiality of the proceedings of public authorities, where such confidentiality is provided for by law;</p>
      <p n="92">(b) international relations, public security or national defence;</p>
      <p n="93">(c) the course of justice, the ability of any person to receive a fair trial or the ability of a public authority to conduct an enquiry of a criminal or disciplinary nature;</p>
      <p n="94">(d) the confidentiality of commercial or industrial information where such confidentiality is provided for by national or Community law to protect a legitimate economic interest, including the public interest in maintaining statistical confidentiality and tax secrecy;</p>
      <p n="95">(e) intellectual property rights;</p>
      <p n="96">(f) the confidentiality of personal data and/or files relating to a natural person where that person has not consented to the disclosure of the information to the public, where such confidentiality is provided for by national or Community law;</p>
      <p n="97">(g) the interests or protection of any person who supplied the information requested on a voluntary basis without being under, or capable of being put under, a legal obligation to do so, unless that person has consented to the release of the information concerned;</p>
      <p n="98">(h) the protection of the environment to which such information relates, such as the location of rare species.</p>
      <p n="99">The grounds for refusal mentioned in paragraphs 1 and 2 shall be interpreted in a restrictive way, taking into account for the particular case the public interest served by disclosure. In every particular case, the public interest served by disclosure shall be weighed against the interest served by the refusal. Member States may not, by virtue of paragraph 2(a), (d), (f), (g) and (h), provide for a request to be refused where the request relates to information on emissions into the environment.</p>
      <p n="100">Within this framework, and for the purposes of the application of subparagraph (f), Member States shall ensure that the requirements of Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data are complied with(6).</p>
      <p n="101">3. Where a Member State provides for exceptions, it may draw up a publicly accessible list of criteria on the basis of which the authority concerned may decide how to handle requests.</p>
      <p n="102">4. Environmental information held by or for public authorities which has been requested by an applicant shall be made available in part where it is possible to separate out any information falling within the scope of paragraphs 1(d) and (e) or 2 from the rest of the information requested.</p>
      <p n="103">5. A refusal to make available all or part of the information requested shall be notified to the applicant in writing or electronically, if the request was in writing or if the applicant so requests, within the time limits referred to in Article 3(2)(a) or, as the case may be, (b). The notification shall state the reasons for the refusal and include information on the review procedure provided for in accordance with Article 6.</p>
      <p n="104">Article 5</p>
      <p n="105">Charges</p>
      <p n="106">1. Access to any public registers or lists established and maintained as mentioned in Article 3(5) and examination in situ of the information requested shall be free of charge.</p>
      <p n="107">2. Public authorities may make a charge for supplying any environmental information but such charge shall not exceed a reasonable amount.</p>
      <p n="108">3. Where charges are made, public authorities shall publish and make available to applicants a schedule of such charges as well as information on the circumstances in which a charge may be levied or waived.</p>
      <p n="109">Article 6</p>
      <p n="110">Access to justice</p>
      <p n="111">1. Member States shall ensure that any applicant who considers that his request for information has been ignored, wrongfully refused (whether in full or in part), inadequately answered or otherwise not dealt with in accordance with the provisions of Articles 3, 4 or 5, has access to a procedure in which the acts or omissions of the public authority concerned can be reconsidered by that or another public authority or reviewed administratively by an independent and impartial body established by law. Any such procedure shall be expeditious and either free of charge or inexpensive.</p>
      <p n="112">2. In addition to the review procedure referred to in paragraph 1, Member States shall ensure that an applicant has access to a review procedure before a court of law or another independent and impartial body established by law, in which the acts or omissions of the public authority concerned can be reviewed and whose decisions may become final. Member States may furthermore provide that third parties incriminated by the disclosure of information may also have access to legal recourse.</p>
      <p n="113">3. Final decisions under paragraph 2 shall be binding on the public authority holding the information. Reasons shall be stated in writing, at least where access to information is refused under this Article.</p>
      <p n="114">Article 7</p>
      <p n="115">Dissemination of environmental information</p>
      <p n="116">1. Member States shall take the necessary measures to ensure that public authorities organise the environmental information which is relevant to their functions and which is held by or for them, with a view to its active and systematic dissemination to the public, in particular by means of computer telecommunication and/or electronic technology, where available.</p>
      <p n="117">The information made available by means of computer telecommunication and/or electronic technology need not include information collected before the entry into force of this Directive unless it is already available in electronic form.</p>
      <p n="118">Member States shall ensure that environmental information progressively becomes available in electronic databases which are easily accessible to the public through public telecommunication networks.</p>
      <p n="119">2. The information to be made available and disseminated shall be updated as appropriate and shall include at least:</p>
      <p n="120">(a) texts of international treaties, conventions or agreements, and of Community, national, regional or local legislation, on the environment or relating to it;</p>
      <p n="121">(b) policies, plans and programmes relating to the environment;</p>
      <p n="122">(c) progress reports on the implementation of the items referred to in (a) and (b) when prepared or held in electronic form by public authorities;</p>
      <p n="123">(d) the reports on the state of the environment referred to in paragraph 3;</p>
      <p n="124">(e) data or summaries of data derived from the monitoring of activities affecting, or likely to affect, the environment;</p>
      <p n="125">(f) authorisations with a significant impact on the environment and environmental agreements or a reference to the place where such information can be requested or found in the framework of Article 3;</p>
      <p n="126">(g) environmental impact studies and risk assessments concerning the environmental elements referred to in Article 2(1)(a) or a reference to the place where the information can be requested or found in the framework of Article 3.</p>
      <p n="127">3. Without prejudice to any specific reporting obligations laid down by Community legislation, Member States shall take the necessary measures to ensure that national, and, where appropriate, regional or local reports on the state of the environment are published at regular intervals not exceeding four years; such reports shall include information on the quality of, and pressures on, the environment.</p>
      <p n="128">4. Without prejudice to any specific obligation laid down by Community legislation, Member States shall take the necessary measures to ensure that, in the event of an imminent threat to human health or the environment, whether caused by human activities or due to natural causes, all information held by or for public authorities which could enable the public likely to be affected to take measures to prevent or mitigate harm arising from the threat is disseminated, immediately and without delay.</p>
      <p n="129">5. The exceptions in Article 4(1) and (2) may apply in relation to the duties imposed by this Article.</p>
      <p n="130">6. Member States may satisfy the requirements of this Article by creating links to Internet sites where the information can be found.</p>
      <p n="131">Article 8</p>
      <p n="132">Quality of environmental information</p>
      <p n="133">1. Member States shall, so far as is within their power, ensure that any information that is compiled by them or on their behalf is up to date, accurate and comparable.</p>
      <p n="134">2. Upon request, public authorities shall reply to requests for information pursuant to Article 2(1)b, reporting to the applicant on the place where information, if available, can be found on the measurement procedures, including methods of analysis, sampling, and pre-treatment of samples, used in compiling the information, or referring to a standardised procedure used.</p>
      <p n="135">Article 9</p>
      <p n="136">Review procedure</p>
      <p n="137">1. Not later than 14 February 2009, Member States shall report on the experience gained in the application of this Directive.</p>
      <p n="138">They shall communicate the report to the Commission not later than 14 August 2009.</p>
      <p n="139">No later than 14 February 2004, the Commission shall forward to the Member States a guidance document setting out clearly the manner in which it wishes the Member States to report.</p>
      <p n="140">2. In the light of experience and taking into account developments in computer telecommunication and/or electronic technology, the Commission shall make a report to the European Parliament and to the Council together with any proposal for revision, which it may consider appropriate.</p>
      <p n="141">Article 10</p>
      <p n="142">Implementation</p>
      <p n="143">Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with this Directive by 14 February 2005. They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="144">When Member States adopt these measures, they shall contain a reference to this Directive or shall be accompanied by such reference on the occasion of their official publication. The methods of making such reference shall be laid down by Member States.</p>
      <p n="145">Article 11</p>
      <p n="146">Repeal</p>
      <p n="147">Directive 90/313/EEC is hereby repealed with effect from 14 February 2005.</p>
      <p n="148">References to the repealed Directive shall be construed as referring to this Directive and shall be read in accordance with the correlation table in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="149">Article 12</p>
      <p n="150">Entry into force</p>
      <p n="151">This Directive shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="152">Article 13</p>
      <p n="153">Addressees</p>
      <p n="154">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="155">Done at Brussels, 28 January 2003.</p>
      <p n="156">For the European Parliament</p>
      <p n="157">The President</p>
      <p n="158">P. Cox</p>
      <p n="159">For the Council</p>
      <p n="160">The President</p>
      <p n="161">G. Papandreou</p>
      <p n="162">(1) OJ C 337 E, 28.11.2000, p. 156 and OJ C 240 E, 28.8.2001, p. 289.</p>
      <p n="163">(2) OJ C 116, 20.4.2001, p. 43.</p>
      <p n="164">(3) OJ C 148, 18.5.2001, p. 9.</p>
      <p n="165">(4) Opinion of the European Parliament of 14 March 2001 (OJ C 343, 5.12.2001, p. 165), Council Common Position of 28 January 2002 (OJ C 113 E, 14.5.2002, p. 1) and Decision of the European Parliament of 30 May 2002 (not yet published in the Official Journal). Decision of the Council of 16 December 2002 and decision the European Parliament of 18 December 2002.</p>
      <p n="166">(5) OJ L 158, 23.6.1990, p. 56.</p>
      <p n="167">(6) OJ L 281, 23.11.1995, p. 31.</p>
      <p n="168">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="169">CORRELATION TABLE</p>
      <p n="170">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
