<TEI.2 id="jrc32003D0015-en" n="32003D0015" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003D0015 English</title>
        <title>2003/15/EC: Commission Decision of 10 January 2003 amending Decision 2002/613/EC as regards the approved semen collection centres of Slovenia (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2002) 5564)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>34 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0015:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0015:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">192</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2560</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3408</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5898</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003D0015-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2003/15/EC: Commission Decision of 10 January 2003 amending Decision 2002/613/EC as regards the approved semen collection centres of Slovenia (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2002) 5564)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 10 January 2003</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 2002/613/EC as regards the approved semen collection centres of Slovenia</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2002) 5564)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2003/15/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 90/429/EEC of 26 June 1990 laying down the animal health requirements applicable to intra-Community trade in and imports of semen of domestic animals of the porcine species(1), as last amended by Commission Decision 2000/39/EC(2), and in particular Article 7(1) and Article 8(1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) Commission Decision 2002/613/EC(3) establishes a list of third countries from which Member States may authorise the importation of semen of domestic animals of the porcine species and a list of semen collection centres from those third countries approved for the export to the Community.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) Slovenia should be added to the list of third countries from which imports are authorised by Decision 2002/613/EC, following Commission missions and in the light of the situation achieved with regard to animal health in this country.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) The competent veterinary services of Slovenia have sent a list of semen collection centres officially approved for the export of pig semen to the Community.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) Guarantees regarding compliance with the requirements specified in Article 8 of Directive 90/429/EEC have been provided to the Commission by the competent veterinary services of Slovenia, and they have officially approved the collection centres concerned for exports to the Community.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="17">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="18">Article 1</p>
      <p n="19">Decision 2002/613/EC is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="20">(a) Slovenia is added to Annex II;</p>
      <p n="21">(b) Slovenia is added to the title of Annex IV;</p>
      <p n="22">(c) in Annex V, the following rows are added for Slovenia:</p>
      <p n="23">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Decision shall apply as from 31 January 2003.</p>
      <p n="26">Article 3</p>
      <p n="27">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 10 January 2003.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="31">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ L 224, 18.8.1990, p. 62.</p>
      <p n="33">(2) OJ L 13, 19.1.2000, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="34">(3) OJ L 196, 25.7.2002, p. 45.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
