<TEI.2 id="jrc32003D0376-en" n="32003D0376" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003D0376 English</title>
        <title>2003/376/EC: Commission Decision of 22 May 2003 amending Annexes I and II to Decision 2002/304/EC as regards programmes applied with a view to obtaining the status of approved zones or farms for viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN) (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2003) 1627)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>91 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0376:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0376:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1085</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1318</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1519</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">192</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2320</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2435</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">336</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">6124</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">863</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003D0376-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2003/376/EC: Commission Decision of 22 May 2003 amending Annexes I and II to Decision 2002/304/EC as regards programmes applied with a view to obtaining the status of approved zones or farms for viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN) (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2003) 1627)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 22 May 2003</p>
      <p n="4">amending Annexes I and II to Decision 2002/304/EC as regards programmes applied with a view to obtaining the status of approved zones or farms for viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN)</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2003) 1627)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2003/376/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 91/67/EEC of 28 January 1991 concerning the animal health conditions governing the placing on the market of aquaculture animals and products(1), as last amended by Directive 98/45/EC(2), and in particular Article 10(3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) By means of Decision 2002/304/EC(3), as amended by Decision 2002/879/EC(4), the Commission approved programmes with a view to obtaining the status of approved zones or approved farms in non-approved zones with regard to one or more of the fish diseases viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS) and infectious haematopoietic necrosis (IHN).</p>
      <p n="13">(2) Italy has submitted to the Commission additional programmes concerning IHN and VHS, with a view to obtaining approved zone status for water catchment areas. These programmes specify geographical delimitation of the zones concerned, the measures to be taken by the official services, the procedures to be followed by the approved laboratories, the prevalence of the diseases concerned and the measures to combat these diseases where detected.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) The programmes submitted by Italy have been found to comply with Article 10 of Directive 91/67/EEC.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) Some programmes approved by Decision 2002/304/EC have been finalised, and should be deleted from Decision 2002/304/EC.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) Decision 2002/304/EC should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">Decision 2002/304/EC is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="21">1. Annex I is replaced by the text in Annex I to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="22">2. Annex II is replaced by the text in Annex II to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="25">Done at Brussels, 22 May 2003.</p>
      <p n="26">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="27">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="28">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="29">(1) OJ L 46, 19.2.1991, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="30">(2) OJ L 189, 3.7.1998, p. 12.</p>
      <p n="31">(3) OJ L 104, 20.4.2002, p. 37.</p>
      <p n="32">(4) OJ L 305, 7.11.2002, p. 59.</p>
      <p n="33">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="34">ZONES IN WHICH APPROVED PROGRAMMES ARE APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO ONE OR MORE OF THE FISH DISEASES VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="35">1. ZONES IN DENMARK IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS</p>
      <p n="36">- The catchment area of FISKEBÆK Å</p>
      <p n="37">- All PARTS OF JUTLAND south and west of the catchment areas of Storåen, Karup å, Gudenåen and Grejs å</p>
      <p n="38">- The area of all THE DANISH ISLES</p>
      <p n="39">2. ZONES IN GERMANY IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="40">- A zone in the water catchment area of WOLFEGGER AACH and ROHRSEE</p>
      <p n="41">- A zone in the water catchment area OBERN NAGOLD</p>
      <p n="42">3. ZONES IN SPAIN IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="43">- THE AUTONOMOUS COMMUNITY OF LA RIOJA</p>
      <p n="44">4. ZONES IN FRANCE IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="45">- LES FORGES</p>
      <p n="46">- LA NIVE and LES NIVELLES</p>
      <p n="47">- L'ÉLORN</p>
      <p n="48">5. ZONES IN ITALY IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="49">5.1. The Autonomous Province of Bolzano</p>
      <p n="50">ZONA PROVINCE OF BOLZANO</p>
      <p n="51">- The zone comprises all water catchment areas within the Province of Bolzano.</p>
      <p n="52">The zone includes the upper part of the zone ZONA VAL DELL'ADIGE - i.e. the water catchment areas of Adige river from its sources in the Province of Bolzano to the border with the Province of Trento.</p>
      <p n="53">(NB:</p>
      <p n="54">The remaining, lower part of the zone ZONA VAL DELL'ADIGE is under the approved programme of the Autonomous Province of Trento. The upper and lower parts of this zone have to be viewed as one epidemiological unit.)</p>
      <p n="55">5.2. The Autonomous Province of Trento</p>
      <p n="56">ZONA VAL DI SOLE E DI NON</p>
      <p n="57">- The water catchment area from the source of the stream Noce to the dam of S. Giustina.</p>
      <p n="58">ZONA VAL DELL'ADIGE - lower part</p>
      <p n="59">- The water catchment areas of the Adige river and its sources located within the territory of the Autonomous Province of Trento, from the border with the Province of Bolzano to the dam of Ala (hydroelectric generating station).</p>
      <p n="60">(NB:</p>
      <p n="61">The upstream part of the zone ZONA VAL DELL'ADIGE is under the approved programme of the Province of Bolzano. The upper and lower parts of this zone have to be viewed as one epidemiological unit.)</p>
      <p n="62">ZONA TORRENTE ARNÒ</p>
      <p n="63">- The water catchment area from the source of Arnò torrent to the down-stream barriers, situated before the Arnò torrent flows into the Sarca river.</p>
      <p n="64">ZONA VAL BANALE</p>
      <p n="65">- The water catchment area of the Ambies stream basin to the dam of a hydroelectric generating station.</p>
      <p n="66">ZONA VARONE</p>
      <p n="67">- The water catchment area from the source of the Magnone stream to the waterfall.</p>
      <p n="68">ZONA ALTO E BASSO CHIESE</p>
      <p n="69">- The water catchment area of the Chiese river from the source to the dam of Condino, except the Adanà and Palvico torrents basins.</p>
      <p n="70">ZONA TORRENTE PALVICO</p>
      <p n="71">- The water catchment area of the Palvico torrent basin to a barrier made of concrete and stones.</p>
      <p n="72">5.3. The Region of Veneto</p>
      <p n="73">ZONA TORRENTE ASTICO</p>
      <p n="74">- The water catchment area of Astico river, from its sources (in the Autonomous Province of Trento and in the Province of Vicenza, the Region of Veneto) to the dam located close to the Pedescala bridge in the Province of Vicenza.</p>
      <p n="75">The downstream part of Astico river, between the dam close to the Pedescala bridge and the Pria Maglio dam, is considered as a buffer zone.</p>
      <p n="76">5.4. The Region of Umbria</p>
      <p n="77">ZONA FOSSO DE MONTERIVOSO: The water catchment area of Monterivoso river, from its sources to the impassible barriers near Ferentillo.</p>
      <p n="78">5.5. The Region of Lombardia</p>
      <p n="79">ZONA VAL BREMBANA: The water catchment area of Brembo river, from its sources to the impassible barrier in the commune de Ponte S. Pietro.</p>
      <p n="80">6.A. ZONES IN FINLAND IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="81">- All continental and coastal areas of FINLAND except the Province of Åland and the restriction area in Pyhtää.</p>
      <p n="82">6.B. ZONES IN FINLAND IN WHICH AN APPROVED PROGRAMME - INCLUDING SPECIFIC ERADICATION MEASURES FOR VHS - IS APPLIED WITH THE FINAL VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED ZONE WITH REGARD TO VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="83">- The whole PROVINCE OF ÅLAND and the restriction area in PYHTÄÄ.</p>
      <p n="84">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="85">FARMS IN ITALY IN WHICH A PROGRAMME IS APPLIED WITH A VIEW TO OBTAINING THE STATUS OF APPROVED FARM SITUATED IN A NON-APPROVED ZONE AS REGARDS VHS AND IHN</p>
      <p n="86">1. REGION: FRIULI VENEZIA GIULIA, PROVINCE OF UDINE</p>
      <p n="87">Farms in the drainage basin of the Tagliamento river:</p>
      <p n="88">- Azienda Vidotti Giulio snc, Sutrio</p>
      <p n="89">2. REGION: THE REGION OF VENETO</p>
      <p n="90">Farms in the drainage basin of the Sile river:</p>
      <p n="91">- Azienda Troticoltura S. Cristina, Via Chiesa Vecchia 14 - Loc. S. Cristina di Quinto</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
