<TEI.2 id="jrc32003D0732-en" n="32003D0732" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003D0732 English</title>
        <title>2003/732/EC: Commission Decision of 10 October 2003 amending Decision 93/52/EEC as regards the recognition of certain Italian provinces as officially free of brucellosis (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2003) 3562)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>42 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0732:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0732:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1445</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1519</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2211</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5047</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5252</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003D0732-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2003/732/EC: Commission Decision of 10 October 2003 amending Decision 93/52/EEC as regards the recognition of certain Italian provinces as officially free of brucellosis (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2003) 3562)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 10 October 2003</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 93/52/EEC as regards the recognition of certain Italian provinces as officially free of brucellosis</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2003) 3562)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2003/732/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Commission Directive 91/68/EEC of 28 January 1991 on animal health conditions governing intra-Community trade in ovine and caprine animals(1), as last amended by Council Directive 2003/50/EC(2), and in particular Annex A(1)(II) thereto,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) In Italy, in the region of Lombardia (provinces of Bergamo, Brescia, Como, Cremona, Lecco, Lodi, Mantua, Milan, Pavia, Sondrio and Varese) and in the province of Trento, brucellosis (Brucella melitensis) has been a notifiable disease for at least five years.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) In the provinces of Bergamo, Brescia, Como, Cremona, Lecco, Lodi, Mantua, Milan, Pavia, Sondrio, Varese and Trento, at least 99,8 % of the ovine or caprine holdings are officially brucellosis-free holdings. These provinces undertake, furthermore, to comply with Annex A(1)(II)(2) to Directive 91/68/EEC.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) The provinces of Bergamo, Brescia, Como, Cremona, Lecco, Lodi, Mantua, Milan, Pavia, Sondrio, Varese and Trento should consequently be recognised as officially free of brucellosis (Brucella melitensis).</p>
      <p n="15">(4) Commission Decision 93/52/EEC(3), as last amended by Decision 2003/237/EC(4), should therefore be amended accordingly.</p>
      <p n="16">(5) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="17">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="18">Article 1</p>
      <p n="19">Annex II to Decision 93/52/EEC is replaced by the text in the Annex to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Brussels, 10 October 2003.</p>
      <p n="23">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="25">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">(1) OJ L 46, 19.2.1991, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="27">(2) OJ L 169, 8.7.2003, p. 51.</p>
      <p n="28">(3) OJ L 13, 21.1.1993, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="29">(4) OJ L 87, 4.4.2003, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="30">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="31">"ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="32">In France:</p>
      <p n="33">Ain, Aisne, Allier, Ardèche, Ardennes, Aube, Aveyron, Cantal, Charente, Charente-Maritime, Cher, Corrèze, Côte-d'Or, Côtes-d'Armor, Creuse, Deux-Sèvres, Dordogne, Doubs, Essonne, Eure, Eure-et-Loir, Finistère, Gers, Gironde, Hauts-de-Seine, Haute-Loire, Haute-Vienne, Ille-et-Vilaine, Indre, Indre-et-Loire, Jura, Loir-et-Cher, Loire, Loire-Atlantique, Loiret, Lot-et-Garonne, Lot, Lozère, Maine-et-Loire, Manche, Marne, Mayenne, Morbihan, Nièvre, Nord, Oise, Orne, Pas-de-Calais, Puy-de-Dôme, Rhône, Haute-Saône, Saône-et-Loire, Sarthe, Seine-Maritime, Seine-Saint-Denis, Territoire de Belfort, Val-de-Marne, Val-d'Oise, Vendée, Vienne, Yonne, Yvelines, Ville de Paris, Vosges.</p>
      <p n="34">In Italy:</p>
      <p n="35">- Lombardy region: provinces of Bergamo, Brescia, Como, Cremona, Lecco, Lodi, Mantua, Milan, Pavia, Sondrio, Varese.</p>
      <p n="36">- Sardinia region: Cagliari, Nuoro, Oristano and Sassari.</p>
      <p n="37">- Trentino-Alto Aldige region: provinces of Bolzano and Trento.</p>
      <p n="38">- Tuscany region: province of Arezzo.</p>
      <p n="39">In Portugal:</p>
      <p n="40">Autonomous Region of the Azores.</p>
      <p n="41">In Spain:</p>
      <p n="42">Santa Cruz de Tenerife, Las Palmas."</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
