<TEI.2 id="jrc32003D0560-en" n="32003D0560" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003D0560 English</title>
        <title>2003/560/EC: Commission Decision of 22 July 2003 revoking the exemption from the payment of the anti-dumping duty extended to certain bicycle parts originating in the People's Republic of China granted to certain parties pursuant to Regulation (EC) No 88/97 (notified under document number C(2003) 1961)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>53 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0560:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003D0560:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2771</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4653</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">519</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5969</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">932</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003D0560-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2003/560/EC: Commission Decision of 22 July 2003 revoking the exemption from the payment of the anti-dumping duty extended to certain bicycle parts originating in the People's Republic of China granted to certain parties pursuant to Regulation (EC) No 88/97 (notified under document number C(2003) 1961)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 22 July 2003</p>
      <p n="4">revoking the exemption from the payment of the anti-dumping duty extended to certain bicycle parts originating in the People's Republic of China granted to certain parties pursuant to Regulation (EC) No 88/97</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2003) 1961)</p>
      <p n="6">(2003/560/EC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 384/96 of 22 December 1995 on protection against dumped imports from countries not members of the European Community(1), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1972/2002(2),</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Regulation (EC) No 71/97 of 10 January 1997 extending the definitive anti-dumping duty imposed by Regulation (EEC) No 2474/93 on bicycles originating in the People's Republic of China to imports of certain bicycle parts from the People's Republic of China and levying the extended duty on such imports registered under Commission Regulation (EC) No 703/96(3), and maintained by Regulation (EC) No 1524/2000(4),</p>
      <p n="11">Having regard to Commission Regulation (EC) No 88/97 of 20 January 1997 on the authorisation of the exemption of imports of certain bicycle parts originating in the People's Republic of China from the extension by Council Regulation (EC) No 71/97 of the anti-dumping duty imposed by Council Regulation (EEC) No 2474/93(5), and maintained by Regulation (EC) No 1524/2000,</p>
      <p n="12">After consulting the Advisory Committee,</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="14">(1) After the entry into force of Regulation (EC) No 88/97, which exempted a certain number of bicycle assemblers from the payment of the anti-dumping duty as extended to imports of certain bicycle parts originating in the People's Republic of China by Council Regulation (EC) No 71/97 (the "extended anti-dumping duty"), the Commission by successive Decisions published in the Official Journal of the European Communities(6) has exempted additional parties from the payment of the extended anti-dumping duty pursuant to Article 7 of Regulation (EC) No 88/97.</p>
      <p n="15">(2) The Commission was informed from various sources that a number of exempted parties have ceased to exist or have stopped assembling bicycles.</p>
      <p n="16">(3) The Commission informed the parties concerned in writing that it intended to revoke their exemption and gave them the opportunity to comment. The Commission received confirmation from most of these parties that they have ceased the production or the assembling of bicycles. For the remaining parties, the Commission did not receive any comments within the given deadline.</p>
      <p n="17">(4) Consequently, in accordance with the principle of good administration, the exemptions for these parties, which are listed in Article 1 of this Decision, should be revoked,</p>
      <p n="18">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="19">Article 1</p>
      <p n="20">The exemptions from the extension by Regulation (EC) No 71/97 of the definitive anti-dumping duty imposed by Regulation (EEC) No 2474/93, and maintained by Regulation (EC) No 1524/2000, on bicycles originating in the People's Republic of China to imports of certain bicycle parts from the People's Republic of China are hereby revoked for the parties listed below from the date following that of the publication of this Decision in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="21">Parties for which the exemption is revoked</p>
      <p n="22">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">This Decision is addressed to the Member States and to the parties listed hereunder:</p>
      <p n="25">Aurelia Dino SpA, Via Cuneo 11, I-12011 Borgo San Dalmazzo (CN)</p>
      <p n="26">Baronia-Fahrrad GmbH, Weher Str. 81-83, D-32369 Rahden</p>
      <p n="27">Brennabor Fahrräder Bernard Fischer GmbH, Schnatweg 3, D-32105 Bad Salzuflen</p>
      <p n="28">Cicli Casadei snc, Via dei Mestieri, I-44020 San Giuseppe di Comacchio</p>
      <p n="29">Cycles Eddie Koepler, ZI No. 2 de Rouvignies - Rue Louis Dacquin - Batterie 900, F-59309 Valenciennes Cedex</p>
      <p n="30">Dangre Cycles, Rue Paul Vaillant Couturier 23, F-59583 Marly</p>
      <p n="31">Dawes Cycles, Wharfdale Road, Tyseley, Birmingham, B11 2DG, United Kingdom</p>
      <p n="32">Fonlupt SA, Rue Joseph Mouterde, F-71600 Paray-Le-Monial</p>
      <p n="33">Girardengo SRL, Via N. Sauro 5, I-15065 Frugarolo</p>
      <p n="34">José Ferreira &amp; Almeida, Lda, Estrada Nacional 235, P-3770 Oliveira do Barro</p>
      <p n="35">Kynast AG, Artlandstr. 55, D-49692 Quakenbrück</p>
      <p n="36">Lombardo Gaspare, Via Roma, 233, I-91012 Buseto Palizzolo</p>
      <p n="37">Magna Technology, Unit 5 Riverside Trading Estate, Fiddlers Ferry, WA5 2UL, Warrington, United Kingdom</p>
      <p n="38">MGI (nv Marcel Geurts Industry), Oude Bunders 2030, B-3630 Maasmechelen</p>
      <p n="39">Portosa Srl, Via Industria 6, I-35030 Rubano</p>
      <p n="40">PRO-FIT Sportartikel, Weinsberger Str. 81, D-74076 Heilbronn</p>
      <p n="41">Reparto Corse Bianchi SRL, Via delle Battaglie 5, I-24047 Treviglio</p>
      <p n="42">Sprint SpA, Via Padana Superiore 91/93 -SS11, I-75045 Castegnato</p>
      <p n="43">Vicini Mario e Figli SNC, Via dell'Artigianato 284, I-47023 Cesena</p>
      <p n="44">Done at Brussels, 22 July 2003.</p>
      <p n="45">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="46">Pascal Lamy</p>
      <p n="47">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="48">(1) OJ L 56, 6.3.1996, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="49">(2) OJ L 305, 7.11.2002, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="50">(3) OJ L 16, 18.1.1997, p. 55.</p>
      <p n="51">(4) OJ L 175, 14.7.2000, p. 39.</p>
      <p n="52">(5) OJ L 17, 21.1.1997, p. 17.</p>
      <p n="53">(6) OJ L 193, 22.7.1997, p. 32, OJ L 31, 6.2.1998, p. 25, OJ L 164, 9.6.1998, p. 49, OJ L 320, 28.11.1998, p. 60, OJ L 41, 10.2.2001, p. 30, OJ L 47, 19.2.2002, p. 43, OJ L 195, 24.7.2002, p. 81.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
