<TEI.2 id="jrc32003R0546-en" n="32003R0546" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32003R0546 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 546/2003 of 27 March 2003 on certain notifications regarding the application of Council Regulations (EEC) No 2771/75, (EEC) No 2777/75 and (EEC) No 2783/75 in the eggs and poultrymeat sectors</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>38 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R0546:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32003R0546:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1857</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2121</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2653</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2664</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2687</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4687</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5334</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">720</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32003R0546-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 546/2003 of 27 March 2003 on certain notifications regarding the application of Council Regulations (EEC) No 2771/75, (EEC) No 2777/75 and (EEC) No 2783/75 in the eggs and poultrymeat sectors</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 546/2003</p>
      <p n="3">of 27 March 2003</p>
      <p n="4">on certain notifications regarding the application of Council Regulations (EEC) No 2771/75, (EEC) No 2777/75 and (EEC) No 2783/75 in the eggs and poultrymeat sectors</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2771/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common organisation of the market in eggs(1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 493/2002(2), and in particular Article 15 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2777/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common organisation of the market in poultrymeat(3), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 493/2002, and in particular Article 15 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2783/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common system of trade for ovalbumin and lactalbumin(4), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 2916/95(5), and in particular Article 10 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">(1) Commission Regulation (EC) No 572/1999 of 16 March 1999 concerning certain reciprocal communications between the Member States and the Commission relating to eggs and poultrymeat and repealing Regulation (EEC) No 1527/73(6) introduced a system whereby the Member States and the Commission notify each other of the prices on the eggs and poultrymeat markets, with a view to their sound management.</p>
      <p n="12">(2) Experience indicates a need to make some improvements to the system. Regulation (EC) No 572/1999 must therefore be replaced.</p>
      <p n="13">(3) The weekly prices should be notified to the Commission by an electronic data transmission system acceptable to it and the prices should be available for consultation by electronic means.</p>
      <p n="14">(4) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Eggs and Poultrymeat,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">1. No later than 12.00 each Thursday, each Member State shall electronically notify the Commission of:</p>
      <p n="18">(a) the selling price in packing stations for eggs in class A from caged hens, being the average of categories L and M;</p>
      <p n="19">(b) the selling price in slaughter plants or the wholesale prices recorded on the representative markets for whole class A chickens known as "65 % chickens", or for another whole chicken presentation if it is more representative.</p>
      <p n="20">2. The prices referred to in paragraph 1 shall be the average prices in the week preceding the week of notification. They shall exclude VAT and be expressed in national currency per 100 kg.</p>
      <p n="21">3. Member States shall adopt no later than 1 May 2003 an electronic data transmission system acceptable to the Commission.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 2</p>
      <p n="23">At least once a month at Management Committee meetings, the Commission shall provide a summary of the prices notified under Article 1 and shall make them available to the Member States on its website.</p>
      <p n="24">Article 3</p>
      <p n="25">Regulation (EC) No 572/1999 is hereby repealed.</p>
      <p n="26">Article 4</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall enter into force on the seventh day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</p>
      <p n="28">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="29">Done at Brussels, 27 March 2003.</p>
      <p n="30">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="31">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="32">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="33">(1) OJ L 282, 1.11.1975, p. 49.</p>
      <p n="34">(2) OJ L 77, 20.3.2002, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="35">(3) OJ L 282, 1.11.1975, p. 77.</p>
      <p n="36">(4) OJ L 282, 1.11.1975, p. 104.</p>
      <p n="37">(5) OJ L 305, 19.12.1995, p. 49.</p>
      <p n="38">(6) OJ L 70, 17.3.1999, p. 16.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
