<TEI.2 id="jrc31984D0309-en" n="31984D0309" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31984D0309 English</title>
        <title>84/309/EEC: Council Decision of 8 May 1984 relating to point 2 of the Voluntary Restraint Agreements on mutton, lamb and goatmeat between the European Economic Community and Austria, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Iceland, Poland, Uruguay and Yugoslavia</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984D0309:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984D0309:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31984D0309-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">84/309/EEC: Council Decision of 8 May 1984 relating to point 2 of the Voluntary Restraint Agreements on mutton, lamb and goatmeat between the European Economic Community and Austria, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Iceland, Poland, Uruguay and Yugoslavia</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 8 May 1984</p>
      <p n="5">relating to point 2 of the Voluntary Restraint Agreements on mutton, lamb and goatmeat between the European Economic Community and Austria, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Iceland, Poland, Uruguay and Yugoslavia</p>
      <p n="6">(84/309/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas under the Voluntary Restraint Agreements concluded with the European Economic Community on mutton, lamb and goatmeat or live sheep and goats, the non-member countries in question undertook, in exchanges of letters, to limit the amount of their exports to certain Community markets considered to be sensitive areas; whereas those undertakings, however, expire on 31 March 1984;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas there has been no change in the circumstances which led to these areas to be recognized as sensitive; whereas provision should therefore be made for extending the arrangements concerning restrictions on exports to those areas;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the Commission has conducted negotiations to that end in Austria, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Iceland, Poland, Uruguay and Yugoslavia; whereas these negotiations resulted in the initialling of an Agreement with each of those countries,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">1. The exchanges of letters concerning point 2 of the Voluntary Restraint Agreements on trade in mutton, lamb and goatmeat are hereby approved on behalf of the European Economic Community with the following countries:</p>
      <p n="17">- Austria,</p>
      <p n="18">- Bulgaria,</p>
      <p n="19">- Czechoslovakia,</p>
      <p n="20">- Hungary,</p>
      <p n="21">- Iceland,</p>
      <p n="22">- Poland,</p>
      <p n="23">- Uruguay,</p>
      <p n="24">- Yugoslavia.</p>
      <p n="25">2. The texts of the exchanges of letters are attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="26">Article 2</p>
      <p n="27">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the exchanges of letters referred to in Article 1, in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 8 May 1984.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Council</p>
      <p n="30">The President</p>
      <p n="31">M. ROCARD</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
