<TEI.2 id="jrc31984R0269-en" n="31984R0269" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31984R0269 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 269/84 of 1 February 1984 correcting Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 3439/83 laying down special conditions for the export of certain cheeses to Australia</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R0269:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R0269:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31984R0269-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 269/84 of 1 February 1984 correcting Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 3439/83 laying down special conditions for the export of certain cheeses to Australia</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 269/84</p>
      <p n="4">of 1 February 1984</p>
      <p n="5">correcting Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 3439/83 laying down special conditions for the export of certain cheeses to Australia</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1600/83 (2), and in particular the first subparagraph of Article 17 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3439/83 of 5 December 1983 laying down special conditions for the export of certain cheeses to Australia (3) introduced a system of accompanying certificates for the said cheeses; whereas the water content by weight of the non-fatty matter is not included in box 7 of section B of the sample certificate shown in Annex II to the said Regulation; whereas Annex II should therefore be republished in full;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Annex II to Regulation (EEC) No 3439/83 is hereby replaced by the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 1 February 1984.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">Poul DALSAGER</p>
      <p n="21">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="22">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="23">(2) OJ No L 163, 22. 6. 1983, p. 56.</p>
      <p n="24">(3) OJ No L 340, 6. 12. 1983, p. 7.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
