<TEI.2 id="jrc31984R1555-en" n="31984R1555" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31984R1555 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 1555/84 of 4 June 1984 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3671/81 on imports into the Community of certain agricultural products originating in Turkey</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>28 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R1555:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R1555:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31984R1555-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 1555/84 of 4 June 1984 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3671/81 on imports into the Community of certain agricultural products originating in Turkey</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 1555/84</p>
      <p n="4">of 4 June 1984</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 3671/81 on imports into the Community of certain agricultural products originating in Turkey</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Regulation (EEC) No 3671/81 (1) lays down that where, pursuant to Articles 25 and 25a of Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72 (2), the Commission introduces a countervailing charge on imports of certain fruit and vegetables originating in Turkey, it shall at the same time reintroduce for these products a customs duty at the level which applied before 1 January 1981;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the application of the abovementioned provision may, in the case of certain products, result in a customs duty being imposed on Turkey which is higher than that which, since 1 January 1981, has been agreed for all non-member supplier countries which do not enjoy special arrangements as regards imports into the Community;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas Article 1 of Regulation (EEC) No 3671/81 should be modified accordingly; whereas, moreover, account should be taken of the arrangements applicable to imports originating in Turkey under the Association Agreement as at 31 December 1980,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1 of Regulation (EEC) No 3671/81 is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="16">'Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">Where, pursuant to Articles 25 and 25a of Regulation (EEC) No 1035/72, the Commission introduces a countervailing charge on imports of certain fruit and vegetables originating in Turkey, it shall at the same time reintroduce:</p>
      <p n="18">- for those products originating in Turkey which as at 31 December 1980 did not enjoy tariff preference under the arrangements arising from the Association Agreement, the duty applicable to non-member countries covered by the most-favoured nation clause,</p>
      <p n="19">- for those products originating in Turkey which enjoy a special arrangement under the Association Agreement, the duty under the Common Customs Tariff currently applicable to countries covered by the most-favoured nation clause, reduced in accordance with the provisions of the preferential scheme in force as at 31 December 1980.'</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="22">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Luxembourg, 4 June 1984.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Council</p>
      <p n="25">The President</p>
      <p n="26">J. DELORS</p>
      <p n="27">(1) OJ No L 367, 23. 12. 1981, p. 3.</p>
      <p n="28">(2) OJ No L 118, 20. 5. 1972, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
