<TEI.2 id="jrc31984R3516-en" n="31984R3516" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31984R3516 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3516/84 of 13 December 1984 on the classification of goods falling within subheading 08.12 C of the Common Customs Tariff</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R3516:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R3516:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31984R3516-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3516/84 of 13 December 1984 on the classification of goods falling within subheading 08.12 C of the Common Customs Tariff</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 3516/84</p>
      <p n="4">of 13 December 1984</p>
      <p n="5">on the classification of goods falling within subheading 08.12 C of the Common Customs Tariff</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 97/69 of 16 January 1969 on measures to be taken for the uniform application of the nomenclature of the Common Customs Tariff (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2055/84 (2), and in particular Article 3 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, in order to ensure that the Common Customs Tariff Nomenclature is applied uniformly, measures must be taken concerning the classification of pitted prunes, ready to eat, having a moisture content not exceeding 35 % to which sorbic acid has been added;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas heading No 08.12 of the Common Customs Tariff annexed to Council Regulation (EEC) No 950/68 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3400/84 (4), relates in particular to dried fruits other than those falling within heading No 08.01 to 08.05 inclusive;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the products in question have the characteristics of goods falling within heading No 08.12 and must therefore be classified in this heading; whereas, within the latter, subheading 08.12 C is the most appropriate;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Committee on Common Customs Tariff Nomenclature,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">Pitted prunes, ready to eat, having a moisture content not exceeding 35 % to which sorbic acid has been added, shall be classified in the Common Customs Tariff within subheading:</p>
      <p n="17">08.12 Fruit, dried, other than that falling within heading Nos 08.01, 08.02, 08.03, 08.04 or 08.05:</p>
      <p n="18">C. Prunes</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 21st day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Brussels, 13 December 1984.</p>
      <p n="23">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="24">Karl-Heinz Narjes</p>
      <p n="25">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="26">(1) OJ No L 14, 21. 1. 1969, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="27">(2) OJ No L 191, 19. 7. 1984, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="28">(3) OJ No L 172, 22. 7. 1968, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="29">(4) OJ No L 320, 10. 12. 1984, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
