<TEI.2 id="jrc31984R3626-en" n="31984R3626" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31984R3626 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 3626/84 of 19 December 1984 amending Regulation No 11 concerning the abolition of discrimination in transport rates and conditions, in implementation of Article 79 (3) of the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R3626:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31984R3626:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31984R3626-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 3626/84 of 19 December 1984 amending Regulation No 11 concerning the abolition of discrimination in transport rates and conditions, in implementation of Article 79 (3) of the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 3626/84</p>
      <p n="4">of 19 December 1984</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation No 11 concerning the abolition of discrimination in transport rates and conditions, in implementation of Article 79 (3) of the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 75 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="11">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (2),</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas, Council Directive 84/647/EEC (3) makes provision for carriers for hire or reward and carriers for own account to use hired vehicles;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the definition of own-account carriage of goods by road contained in Article 9 of Regulation No 11 (4) excludes the use of hired vehicles; whereas it is therefore necessary to amend the said Regulation,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">First indent of Article 9 of Regulation No 11 is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="17">'- the goods must be carried by vehicles owned or obtained on deferred terms or hired by the undertaking, provided that in the latter case they meet the conditions of Article 2 of Directive 84/647/EEC (1).</p>
      <p n="18">(1) OJ No L 335, 22. 12. 1984, p. 72.'</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 July 1986.</p>
      <p n="21">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Brussels, 19 December 1984.</p>
      <p n="23">For the Council</p>
      <p n="24">The President</p>
      <p n="25">J. BRUTON</p>
      <p n="26">(1) OJ No C 10, 16. 1. 1984, p. 91.</p>
      <p n="27">(2) OJ No C 35, 9. 2. 1984, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="28">(3) See p. 72 of this Official Journal.</p>
      <p n="29">(4) OJ No 52, 16. 8. 1960, p. 1121/60.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
