<TEI.2 id="jrc31986D0277-en" n="31986D0277" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986D0277 English</title>
        <title>86/277/EEC: Council Decision of 12 June 1986 on the conclusion of the Protocol to the 1979 Convention on long-range transboundary air pollution on long-term financing of the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0277:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0277:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986D0277-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">86/277/EEC: Council Decision of 12 June 1986 on the conclusion of the Protocol to the 1979 Convention on long-range transboundary air pollution on long-term financing of the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP)</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 12 June 1986 on the conclusion of the Protocol to the 1979 Convention on long-range transboundary air pollution on long-term financing of the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP) (86/277/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission(1),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(2),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, by Decision 81/462/EEC(1), the Community approved the Convention on long-range transboundary air pollution;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP), which is to be implemented under the Convention, is the principal means of obtaining information about the quantities emitted and possibly transmitted across national frontiers;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, on 24 May 1984, the Commission was authorized to take part, on behalf of the Community, in the negotiations on the Protocol to the Convention on long-term financing of the EMEP;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the negotiations culminated in the adoption of the final text of the Protocol and in the fixing of the cost-sharing formula for the EMEP;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, as authorized by the Council on 25 September 1984, the Protocol was signed by the Community on 28 September 1984 at the second meeting of the Executive Body of the Convention,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The Protocol to the 1979 Convention on long-range transboundary air pollution on long-term financing of the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP) is hereby approved on behalf of the European Economic Community.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Protocol is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The President of the Council shall deposit the act of approval provided for in Article 9 of the Protocol.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Luxembourg, 12 June 1986.</p>
      <p n="19">For the CouncilThe PresidentP. WINSEMIUS</p>
      <p n="20">(1)OJ N째 C 321, 13. 12. 1985, p. 5.</p>
      <p n="21">(2)OJ N째 C 88, 14. 4. 1986, p. 109.</p>
      <p n="22">(3)OJ N째 L 171, 27. 6. 1981, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="23">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="24">referred to in Article 4 of the Protocol to the 1979 Convention on long-range transboundary air pollution on long-term financing of the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP) Mandatory contributions for sharing of costs for financing the cooperative programme for monitoring and evaluation of the long-range transmission of air pollutants in Europe (EMEP), shall be calculated according to the following scale:</p>
      <p n="25">% Austria1,59 Bulgaria0,35 Belorussian SSR0,71 Czechoslovakia1,54 Finland1,07 German Democratic Republic2,74 Holy See0,02 Hungary0,45 Iceland0,06 Liechtenstein0,02 N째rway1,13 Poland1,42 Portugal0,30 Romania0,37 San Marino0,02 Spain3,54 Sweden2,66 Switzerland2,26 Turkey0,60 Ukrainian SSR2,60 USSR20,78 Yugoslavia0,60 Member States the European Economic Community:</p>
      <p n="26">Belgium2,36 Denmark1,38 France11,99 Germany, Federal Republic of15,73 Greece1,00 Ireland0,50 Italy6,89 Luxembourg0,10 Netherlands3,28 United Kingdom8,61 European Economic Community3,33 Total 100,00 The order in which the Contracting Parties are listed in this Annex is specifically made in relation to the cost-sharing system agreed upon by the Executive Body for the Convention. Accordingly, the listing is a feature which is specific to the Protocol on the financing of EMEP.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
