<TEI.2 id="jrc31986D0391-en" n="31986D0391" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986D0391 English</title>
        <title>86/391/EEC: Commission Decision of 23 July 1986 amending Decision 81/713/EEC as regards the list of establishments in Brazil approved for the purpose of importing fresh meat into the Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>37 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0391:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0391:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986D0391-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">86/391/EEC: Commission Decision of 23 July 1986 amending Decision 81/713/EEC as regards the list of establishments in Brazil approved for the purpose of importing fresh meat into the Community</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 23 July 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending Decision 81/713/EEC as regards the list of establishments in Brazil approved for the purpose of importing fresh meat into the Community</p>
      <p n="6">(86/391/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Directive 72/462/EEC of 12 December 1972 on health and veterinary inspection problems upon importation of bovine animals and swine and fresh meat from third countries (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3768/85 (2), and in particular Articles 4 (1) and 18 (1) thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas a list of establishments in Brazil, approved for the purpose of importing fresh meat into the Community, was drawn up initially by Commission Decision 81/713/EEC (3), as last amended by Decision 86/53/EEC (4);</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas a routine inspection under Article 5 of Directive 72/462/EEC and Article 3 (1) of Commission Decision 83/196/EEC of 8 April 1983 concerning on-the-spot inspections to be carried out in respect of the importation of bovine animals and swine and fresh meat from non-member countries (5) has revealed that the level of hygiene of certain establishments has altered since the last inspection;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the list of establishments should therefore be amended;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are inaccordance with the opinion of the Standing Veterinary Committee,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The Annex to Decision 81/713/EEC is hereby replaced by the Annex to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="19">Done at Brussels, 23 July 1986.</p>
      <p n="20">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="22">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 302, 31. 12. 1972, p. 28.</p>
      <p n="24">(2) OJ No L 362, 31. 12. 1985, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="25">(3) OJ No L 257, 10. 9. 1981, p. 28.</p>
      <p n="26">(4) OJ No L 68, 11. 3. 1986, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="27">(5) OJ No L 108, 26. 4. 1983, p. 18.</p>
      <p n="28">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="29">LIST OF ESTABLISHMENTS FROM WHICH IMPORTS OF FRESH MEAT MAY BE AUTHORIZED WITHOUT TIME LIMIT</p>
      <p n="30">1.2 // // // Approval No // Establishment/Address // 1,2 // // I. BOVINE MEAT // A. Slaughterhouses and cutting premises // 1.2 // // // SIF 7 // Swift Armour SA Indústria e Comércio, Santana do Livramento, Rio Grande do Sul // 168 // Frigoríficos Minas Gerais SA, Santa Luzia, Minas Gerais // 196 // Frigorífico Bordon SA, Presidente Prudente, São Paulo // 226 // Frigorífico Bordon SA, Bagé, Rio Grande do Sul // 232 // Cooperativa Industrial Regional de Carnes e Derivados Ltda, Bagé, Rio Grande do Sul // 337 // Frigorífico Bertin Ltda, Lins, São Paulo // 385 // Frigorífico Mouran SA, Andradina, São Paulo // 451 // Frigorífico Vale de Tietê SA, José Bonifácio, São Paulo // 458 // Frigorífico Bordon SA, Presidente Epitácio, São Paulo // 504 // Frigorífico Ituiutaba Ltda, Ituiutaba, Minas Gerais // 506 // Frisa - Frigorífico Rio Doce SA, Colatina, Espírito Santo // 716 // Frigobras - Companhia Brasileira de Frigoríficos, Toledo, Paraná // 760 // Cooperativa Regional Castilhense de Carnes e Derivados Ltda, Júlio de Castilhos, Rio Grande do Sul // 761 // Frigorífico Vacariense SA, Indústria e Comércio, Vacaria, Rio Grande do Sul // 834 // Frigorífico Kaiowa SA, Presidente Venceslau, São Paulo // 862 // Frigorífico Anglo, Goiania, Goiás // 876 // Cia Peteffi de Alimentos, Caxias do Sul, Rio Grande do Sul // 954 // Cossisa Frigorífico SA, Sete Lagoas, Minas Gerais // 1602 // Bon Beef Indústria e Comércio de Carnes SA, Vinhedo, São Paulo // 1651 // Frigorífico Extremo Sul SA, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul // 1676 // Swift Armour SA Indústria e Comércio, Uberlândia Minas Gerais // 2007 // Cooperativa Rural Alegretense Ltda, Alegrete, Rio Grande do Sul // 2023 // Frigorífico Quatro Rios SA, Votuporanga, São Paulo // 2051 // Frinasa - Frigorífico Nanuque SA, Nanuque, Minas Gerais // 2161 // Frigorífico Dias SA - Frigobras SA, Janauba, Minas Gerais // 2543 // Frigorífico Gejota Ltda, Promissão, São Paulo // 1,2 // B. Cutting premises // 1.2 // // // SIF 1 // Comabra - Cia de Alimentos do Brasil SA, Osasco, São Paulo // 30 // SA Frigorífico Anglo, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul // 736 // Sola SA, Indústrias Alimentícias, Três Rios, Rio de Janeiro // 1,2 // II. HORSEMEAT Slaughterhouses and cutting premises // 1.2 // // // SIF 3 // Frigorífico Yukijirushi do Paraná SA, Curitiba, Paraná // 55 // Martini Meat SA - Comércio, Importação e Exportação de Carnes, Apucarana, Paraná // 733 // Indústria et Comércio Sonva SA, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul // 924 // Mafisa-Matadouro e Frigorífico Industrial SA, Belo Jardim, Pernambuco // 1803 // Fava - Industrial de Alimentos Ltda, Araguari, Minas Gerais // 2168 // Matadouro Itaobim SA - Maisa, Itaobim, Minas Gerais // //</p>
      <p n="31">III. COLD STORES</p>
      <p n="32">1.2 // // // Approval No // Establishment/Address // // // 4 // Swift Armour SA - Indústria e Comércio, Rosário do Sul, Rio Grande do Sul // 63 // Friozen - Armazéns Frigoríficos Ltda, Jandira, São Paulo // 71 // Frigorífico Rio Doce SA, Niterói, Rio de Janeiro // 72 // Cefri - Centrais de Estocagem Frigorificada Ltd, Mairinque, São Paulo // 78 // Interfrio SA Comercial e Industrial, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul // 216 // Arfrio SA - Armazéns Gerais Frigoríficos, Barueri, São Paulo // 250 // Cetrim, Uberlândia, Minas Gerais // 251 // Refrio Armazéns Gerais Frigoríficos Ltda, Itap. da Serra, São Paulo // 324 // Entreposto Frigorífico João Mascarenhas, Rio Grande, Rio Grande do Sul // 535 // Matadouro e Frigorífico Industrial SA - Mafisa, Recife, Pernambuco // 785 // Frigobras, Paranaguá, Paraná // 933 // Companhia Brasileira de Armazenamento - Cibrazem, Rio de Janeiro // 966 // C. Sola, Comércio e Exportação SA, Três Rios, Rio de Janeiro // 1075 // CGA - Companhia Geral de Armazenagem, Santos, São Paulo // 1127 // Companhia Brasileira de Armazenamento - Cibrazem, Curitiba, Paraná // 1148 // Indústria e Comércio Sonva SA, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul // 1597 // Companhia Estadual de Silos e Armazéns - Cesa, Caxias do Sul, Rio Grande do Sul // 1599 // Martini Meat SA - Comércio, Importação e Exportação de Carnes, Paranaguá, Paraná // 1632 // Junção Armazenagem Comércio e Exportação Ltda, Rio Grande, Rio Grande do Sul // 1660 // Frigorífico Mouran Araçatuba SA, Santos, São Paulo // 1958 // Avante SA Productos Alimentícios, Santos, São Paulo // 2248 // Armazém Frigorífico Coronel Augusto A. Leitão - Cibrazem, Canoas, Rio Grande do Sul // 2427 // Cesca, Itajai, Santa Catarina // 2608 // Companhia Estadual de Silos e Armazéns - Cesa, Capão do Leão, Rio Grande do Sul // //</p>
      <p n="33">LIST OF ESTABLISHMENTS FROM WHICH FRESH MEAT MAY BE INTRODUCED INTO THE TERRITORY OF THE COMMUNITY ONLY UNTIL THE STATED DATE</p>
      <p n="34">1.2 // // // Approval No // Establishment/Address // 1,2 // BOVINE MEAT Slaughterhouses and cutting premises // 1.2 // // // SIF 6 (1) // Frigorífico Mouran Araçatuba SA, Araçatuba, São Paulo // 76 (2) // SA Frigorífico Anglo, Barretos, São Paulo // 592 (3) // Frigorífico Central Ltda, Paranavai, Paraná // //</p>
      <p n="35">(1) Until 29 August 1986.</p>
      <p n="36">(2) Until 30 January 1987.</p>
      <p n="37">(3) Until 31 July 1986.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
