<TEI.2 id="jrc31986R1174-en" n="31986R1174" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986R1174 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 1174/86 of 21 April 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 706/73 concerning the Community arrangements applicable to the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man for trade in agricultural products</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>34 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R1174:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R1174:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986R1174-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 1174/86 of 21 April 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 706/73 concerning the Community arrangements applicable to the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man for trade in agricultural products</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 1174/86</p>
      <p n="4">of 21 April 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 706/73 concerning the Community arrangements applicable to the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man for trade in agricultural products</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the 1972 Act of Accession, and in particular the third subparagraph of Article 1 (2) of Protocol No 3 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas certain veterinary provisions in respect of Northern Ireland and relating to foot-and-mouth disease and trade in live animals, fresh meat and meat-based products have been liberalized;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas Regulation (EEC) No 706/73 (1) linked the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man to Northern Ireland for purposes of the veterinary sector;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas, in order to minimize the risk of disease, it is necessary to permit these islands to maintain their veterinary rules in relation to foot-and-mouth disease which have been in force hitherto,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3 of Regulation (EEC) No 706/73 is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="16">'Article 3</p>
      <p n="17">From 1 September 1973, the Community provisions in the following fields:</p>
      <p n="18">- veterinary legislation,</p>
      <p n="19">- animal health legislation,</p>
      <p n="20">- plant health legislation,</p>
      <p n="21">- marketing of seeds and seedlings,</p>
      <p n="22">- food legislation,</p>
      <p n="23">- feedingstuffs legislation,</p>
      <p n="24">- quality and marketing standards,</p>
      <p n="25">shall apply under the same conditions as in the United Kingdom to the products referred to in Article 1 imported into the islands or exported from the islands to the Community.</p>
      <p n="26">However, the Channel Islands and the Isle of Man may retain, concerning trade in live animals, fresh meat and meat-based products, the specific provisions in relation to foot-and-mouth disease which they apply to imports. Such provisions shall be no more restrictive than those in force on 30 September 1985'.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 2</p>
      <p n="28">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="29">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="30">Done at Luxembourg, 21 April 1986.</p>
      <p n="31">For the Council</p>
      <p n="32">The President</p>
      <p n="33">G. BRAKS</p>
      <p n="34">(1) OJ No L 68, 15. 3. 1973, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
