<TEI.2 id="jrc31986R1325-en" n="31986R1325" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986R1325 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1325/86 of 5 May 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>38 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R1325:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R1325:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986R1325-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1325/86 of 5 May 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1325/86</p>
      <p n="4">of 5 May 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3768/85 (2), and in particular Article 6 (7) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Commission Regulation No 3143/85 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 715/86 (4), made provision for the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Article 2 (4) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 lays down, in particular, that the contract of sale of the reduced-price butter should name the establishment where the concentrated butter will be packaged for marketing; whereas experience has shown that operators are having difficulties in fulfilling this contractual obligation; whereas this provision introduces a degree of inflexibility that is not essential for the purposes of the controls provided for; whereas it should therefore be relaxed;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas Article 4 (4) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 sets the time limit for the processing of the butter into concentrated butter and for the packaging of the concentrated butter; whereas the recent unfavourable trend in sales of concentrated butter means that operators are no longer able to meet the time limit laid down without running a considerable commercial risk related to the latest permitted date of use indicated on the packaging of the concentrated butter under national rules; whereas this economic situation is likely to compromise the future of the system; whereas the time limit as fixed should be waived temporarily;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas Article 5 (5) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 lays down that the packs should have a maximum net content of three kilograms; whereas, in the light of the experience gained and, in particular, of demand by restaurants and community establishments, the maximum net content should be increased to 10 kilograms;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas Article 5 (3) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 lays down that nitrogen gas may be added to concentrated butter within certain limits; whereas experience has shown that the permitted increase in volume that results from the treatment referred to in the said Article should be increased for concentrated butter with a minimum butterfat content of 99,8 % whereas, moreover, it seems desirable to relax the provision referred to in the second subparagraph of Article 5 (4) concerning the sealing of the packs;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas the provisions of this Regulation are to the benefit of operators and should, therefore, be applicable to current contracts;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="16">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="17">Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="19">1. The following is added to the second subparagraph of Article 2 (4):</p>
      <p n="20">'However following agreement by the responsible agency, all of the concentrated butter may be packaged for marketing in an establishment other than stated in the contract of sale.'</p>
      <p n="21">2. The following is added to Article 4 (4):</p>
      <p n="22">'However, for contracts signed before 1 May 1986, the abovementioned period shall expire on 1 September 1986.'</p>
      <p n="23">3. Article 5 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="24">(a) The following subparagraph is added to paragraph 3:</p>
      <p n="25">'However, in the case of concentrated butter with a maximum butterfat content of 99,8 %, the increase in volume from this treatment may not exceed 20 % of the concentrated butter before treatment.'</p>
      <p n="26">(b) The words 'hermetically sealed packs' in the second subparagraph of paragraph 4 are replaced by the words 'sealed packs'.</p>
      <p n="27">(c) The words 'three kilograms' in paragraph 5 are replaced by the words '10 kilograms'.</p>
      <p n="28">Article 2</p>
      <p n="29">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="30">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="31">Done at Brussels, 5 May 1986</p>
      <p n="32">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="33">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="34">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="35">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="36">(2) OJ No L 362, 31. 12. 1985, p. 8.</p>
      <p n="37">(3) OJ No L 298, 12. 11. 1985, p. 9.</p>
      <p n="38">(4) OJ No L 65, 7. 3. 1986, p. 18.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
