<TEI.2 id="jrc31986R3574-en" n="31986R3574" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986R3574 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3574/86 of 24 November 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2806/79 concerning the exchange between the Member States and the Commission of certain information concerning pigmeat</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R3574:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R3574:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986R3574-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3574/86 of 24 November 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2806/79 concerning the exchange between the Member States and the Commission of certain information concerning pigmeat</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 3574/86</p>
      <p n="4">of 24 November 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 2806/79 concerning the exchange between the Member States and the Commission of certain information concerning pigmeat</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2759/75 of 29 October 1975 on the common organization of the market in pigmeat (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1475/86 (2), and in particular Article 22 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas quotations for pig carcases are to be determined in the Community as from 1 August 1986 in accordance with the Community scale for grading pig carcases as laid down by Council Regulation (EEC) No 3220/84 (3); whereas, however, Member States may instead continue until 31 December 1988 to apply the scale determined by Council Regulation (EEC) No 2760/75 (4);</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2806/79 (5) provides for the exchange between the Member States and the Commission of certain information concerning prices in the pigmeat sector; whereas it should be amended in the light of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2342/86 of 25 July 1986 on the marketing stage to which the average prices for pig carcases refers and laying down transitional rules for the application of Regulation (EEC) No 3220/84 (6), which redefines the basis for determining the average market price for pig carcases;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Pigmeat,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">Regulation (EEC) No 2806/79 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="15">1. Article 1 (1) (a) is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="16">'(a) the quotations as determined in accordance with Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2342/86 (1).</p>
      <p n="17">(1) OJ No L 203, 26. 7. 1986, p. 18.'</p>
      <p n="18">2. Article 2 is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="19">'Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">The Member States shall communicate to the Commission once a month for the preceding month:</p>
      <p n="21">- where Council Regulation (EEC) No 3220/84 (1) is applied, the average of the quotations for pig carcases for commercial grades E to P as specified in Article 3 (2) thereof;</p>
      <p n="22">- where Regulation (EEC) No 2760/75 is applied, the average of the quotations for pig carcases for commercial grades E to IV as specified in Annex I thereto.</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 301, 20. 11. 1984, p. 1.'</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="26">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="27">Done at Brussels, 24 November 1986.</p>
      <p n="28">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="29">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="30">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="31">(1) OJ No L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="32">(2) OJ No L 133, 21. 5. 1986, p. 39.</p>
      <p n="33">(3) OJ No L 301, 20. 11. 1984, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="34">(4) OJ No L 282, 1. 11. 1975, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="35">(5) OJ No L 319, 14. 12. 1979, p. 17.</p>
      <p n="36">(6) OJ No L 203, 26. 7. 1986, p. 18.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
