<TEI.2 id="jrc31986D0028-en" n="31986D0028" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986D0028 English</title>
        <title>86/28/Euratom: Council Decision of 20 January 1986 approving the conclusion by the Commission of a Memorandum of Understanding between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada concerning cooperation in the field of fusion research and development</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0028:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0028:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986D0028-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">86/28/Euratom: Council Decision of 20 January 1986 approving the conclusion by the Commission of a Memorandum of Understanding between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada concerning cooperation in the field of fusion research and development</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 20 January 1986</p>
      <p n="5">approving the conclusion by the Commission of a Memorandum of Understanding between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada concerning cooperation in the field of fusion research and development</p>
      <p n="6">(86/28/Euratom)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular the second paragraph of Article 101 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas the Commission has carried out negotiations in accordance with Council directives and proposes concluding a Memorandum of Understanding between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada concerning cooperation in the field of fusion research and development;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the conclusion by the Commission of that Memorandum of Understanding should be approved,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Sole Article</p>
      <p n="14">The conclusion by the Commission of the Memorandum of Understanding between the European Atomic Energy Community and the Government of Canada concerning cooperation in the field of fusion research and development is hereby approved.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Memorandum of Understanding is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Brussels, 20 January 1986.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">G. BRAKS</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
