<TEI.2 id="jrc31986D0006-en" n="31986D0006" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986D0006 English</title>
        <title>86/6/EEC: Council Decision of 20 January 1986 accepting on behalf of the Community, the Customs Cooperation Council recommendation of 16 June 1982 concerning the production of goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>29 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0006:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986D0006:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986D0006-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">86/6/EEC: Council Decision of 20 January 1986 accepting on behalf of the Community, the Customs Cooperation Council recommendation of 16 June 1982 concerning the production of goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 20 January 1986</p>
      <p n="5">accepting</p>
      <p n="6">on behalf of the Community, the Customs Cooperation Council recommendation of 16 June 1982 concerning the production of goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers</p>
      <p n="7">(86/6/EEC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the Customs Cooperation Council recommendation of 16 June 1982 concerning the production of goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers can be accepted by the Community with immediate effect,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The Customs Cooperation Council recommendation of 16 June 1982 concerning the production of goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers is hereby accepted on behalf of the Community with immediate effect.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the recommendation is annexed to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to notify the Customs Cooperation Council's Secretary-General of the Community's acceptance with immediate effect of the recommendation referred to in Article 1.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 20 January 1986.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Council</p>
      <p n="20">The President</p>
      <p n="21">G. BRAKS</p>
      <p n="22">RECOMMENDATION OF THE CUSTOMS COOPERATION COUNCIL</p>
      <p n="23">of 16 June 1982</p>
      <p n="24">concerning the production of goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers</p>
      <p n="25">THE CUSTOMS COOPERATION COUNCIL,</p>
      <p n="26">Desirous of facilitating the accomplishment of formalities in international trade by enabling declarants to make the greatest possible use of modern methods for the production of international trade documents,</p>
      <p n="27">Considering that automatic data processing techniques make it possible for declarants to produce Goods declarations, by means of computer or other automatic printers on pre-printed forms or on plain paper, which substantially conform to the official model specified by the Customs or other competent authorities,</p>
      <p n="28">Recommends that States, whether or not Members of the Council, and Customs or Economic unions should authorize declarants, under conditions to be laid down by the Customs or other competent authorities, to produce their Goods declarations by means of computer or other automatic printers, on pre-printed forms or on plain paper. Such authorization may be made subject, in particular, to the condition that declarations produced in this manner substantially conform to the official model specified by the Customs or other competent authorities,</p>
      <p n="29">Requests States, whether or not Members of the Council, and Customs or Economic unions which accept this recommendation to notify the Secretary-General of their acceptance, of the date from which they will apply the recommendation, and of the conditions of its application. The Secretary-General will transmit this information to the Customs administrations of all Members. He will also transmit it to any Customs administrations of non-members or any Customs or Economic unions which have accepted this recommendation.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
