<TEI.2 id="jrc31986L0320-en" n="31986L0320" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986L0320 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 86/320/EEC of 20 June 1986 amending Council Directive 66/402/EEC on the marketing of cereal seed</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>34 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986L0320:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986L0320:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986L0320-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 86/320/EEC of 20 June 1986 amending Council Directive 66/402/EEC on the marketing of cereal seed</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE</p>
      <p n="4">of 20 June 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending Council Directive 66/402/EEC on the marketing of cereal seed</p>
      <p n="6">(86/320/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Directive 66/402/EEC of 14 June 1966 on the marketing of cereal seed (1), as last amended by Directive 86/155/EEC (2), and in particular Articles 2 (1a) and 21a thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, in the light of the development of scientific and technical knowledge concerning the hybrids resulting from the crossing of species covered by Directive 66/402/EEC, the hybrids resulting from the crossing of Sorghum bicolor and Sorghum sudanense should, owing to their increased importance in the Community, be included in the scope of the Directive;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas, in the light of the development of scientific and technical knowledge, Annex I to the said Directive should be amended in order to adapt the conditions to be satisfied by crops of Sorghum species;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Seeds and Propagating Material for Agriculture, Horticulture and Forestry,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">Directive 66/402/EEC is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">1. In Article 2 (1) (A) the following is added:</p>
      <p n="17">'This definition shall also cover the following hybrids resulting from the crossing of species referred to above.</p>
      <p n="18">1.2 // Sorghum bicolor (L.) Moench × Sorghum sudanense (Piper) Stapf. // Hybrids resulting from the crossing of Sorghum and Sudan grass.</p>
      <p n="19">Unless otherwise specified, seed of the aforementioned hybrids shall be subject to the standards or other conditions applicable to seed of each of the species from which they are derived.'</p>
      <p n="20">2. In Annex I (3) (C) (b) the words 'of hybrid varieties' are inserted after the words 'certified seed'.</p>
      <p n="21">3. In Annex I (3) (C) the following is added:</p>
      <p n="22">'(c) crops of open pollinated varieties or synthetic varieties of Sorghum spp. shall conform to the following standards: the number of plants of the crop which are recognizable as obviously not being true to the variety shall not exceed:</p>
      <p n="23">- one per 30 m2 for the producton of basic seed,</p>
      <p n="24">- one per 10 m2 for the production of certified seed'.</p>
      <p n="25">Article 2</p>
      <p n="26">Member States shall take the measures necessary to comply with this Directive not later than 1 July 1987. They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 3</p>
      <p n="28">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="29">Done at Brussels, 20 June 1986.</p>
      <p n="30">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="31">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="32">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="33">(1) OJ No 125, 11. 7. 1966, p. 2308/66.</p>
      <p n="34">(2) OJ No L 118, 7. 5. 1986, p. 23.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
