<TEI.2 id="jrc31986R2889-en" n="31986R2889" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986R2889 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2889/86 of 18 September 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R2889:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986R2889:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986R2889-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2889/86 of 18 September 1986 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 2889/86</p>
      <p n="4">of 18 September 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 on the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter intended for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1335/86 (2), and in particular Article 6 (7) thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1741/86 (4), introduced a scheme for the sale at reduced prices of intervention butter for direct consumption in the form of concentrated butter;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Article 4 (4) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85 set time limits for the processing of butter into concentrated butter and the packaging thereof; whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1325/86 (5) introduced a derogation from the time limit for contracts concluded before 1 May 1986, since the unfavourable trend in sales of concentrated butter meant that operators could not meet the time limit without running a considerable commercial risk, given their obligation under national provisions to display on packs a final date for use; whereas the advertising campaign just launched to promote the use of concentrated butter will not produce results for some time; whereas the time limit for contracts concluded before 1 May 1986 should therefore be further extended so that operators can benefit from the campaign;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk products,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">In the second subparagraph of Article 4 (4) of Regulation (EEC) No 3143/85, '1 September 1986' is replaced by '1 November 1986'.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 18 September 1986.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="21">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="22">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="23">(2) OJ No L 119, 8. 5. 1986, p. 19.</p>
      <p n="24">(3) OJ No L 298, 12. 11. 1985, p. 9.</p>
      <p n="25">(4) OJ No L 151, 5. 6. 1986, p. 20.</p>
      <p n="26">(5) OJ No L 117, 6. 5. 1986, p. 14.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
