<TEI.2 id="jrc31986L0094-en" n="31986L0094" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31986L0094 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 86/94/EEC of 10 March 1986 amending for the second time Directive 73/404/EEC on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to detergents</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>35 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986L0094:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31986L0094:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31986L0094-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 86/94/EEC of 10 March 1986 amending for the second time Directive 73/404/EEC on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to detergents</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DIRECTIVE</p>
      <p n="4">of 10 March 1986</p>
      <p n="5">amending for the second time Directive 73/404/EEC on the approximation of the laws of the Member States relating to detergents</p>
      <p n="6">(86/94/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particularr Article 100 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the proposal from the Comission (1),</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="11">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (3),</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas Article 2a of Council Directive 73/404/EEC (4), as amended by Directive 82/242/EEC (5), provides for certain exemptions until 31 March 1986 from the requirement of a minimum biodegradability level for the non-ionic surfactants contained in detergents;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the substances in question are non-ionic surfactants which do not comply with the biodegradability limits laid down in Directive 73/404/EEC; whereas they are used for some purposes because of technical problems and in order to avoid other undesirable effects on health and the environment;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas research on biodegradability of these substances has progressed since the adoption of Directive 82/242/EEC; whereas, however, the results of that research have not made it possible to dispense with all the exemption rules; whereas this derives from very wide disparities that exist between Member States as regards, inter alia, water properties, eating habits and machine design;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas, although substitutes are already being used in dish-washing machine products in certain regions of the Community, no suitable substitution products have yet been found for the metal-working industry, despite intensive efforts;</p>
      <p n="16">Whereas, a relatively small quantity of surfactants is involved, which, however, are of considerable economic significance; whereas it is desirable to give Member States the possibility of allowing exemptions until 31 December 1989, insofar as their national situations so require,</p>
      <p n="17">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="18">Article 1</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2a (1) of Directive 73/404/EEC is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="20">'1. Until 31 December 1989, Member States may, exempt the following products from the requirements of the first paragraph of Article 2:</p>
      <p n="21">(a) low-foaming alkene oxide additives on such substances as alcohols, alkylphenols, glycols, polyols, fatty acids, amides or amines, used in dish-washing products;</p>
      <p n="22">(b) alkali-resistant terminally blocked alkyl and alkyl-aryl polyglycol ethers and substances of the type referred to in subparagraph (a), used in cleaning agents for the food, beverage and metal-working industries.'.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 1</p>
      <p n="24">Member States shall forthwith inform the Commission of any measures they take in order to implement this Directive.</p>
      <p n="25">Article 3</p>
      <p n="26">This Directive is addressed to Member States.</p>
      <p n="27">Done at Brussels, 10 March 1986.</p>
      <p n="28">For the Council</p>
      <p n="29">The President</p>
      <p n="30">H. van den BROEK</p>
      <p n="31">(1) OJ No C 139, 7. 6. 1985, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="32">(2) OJ No C 68, 24. 3. 1986.</p>
      <p n="33">(3) OJ No C 303, 25. 11. 1985, p. 26.</p>
      <p n="34">(4) OJ No L 347, 17. 12. 1973, p. 51.</p>
      <p n="35">(5) OJ No L 109, 22. 4. 1982, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
