<TEI.2 id="jrc32002D0527-en" n="32002D0527" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32002D0527 English</title>
        <title>2002/527/EC: Commission Decision of 27 June 2002 amending Decision 97/252/EC drawing up provisional lists of third country establishments from which the Member States authorise imports of milk and milk products for human consumption, with respect to the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2002) 2301)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>61 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32002D0527:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32002D0527:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1284</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1309</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1565</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">192</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2763</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5713</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32002D0527-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">2002/527/EC: Commission Decision of 27 June 2002 amending Decision 97/252/EC drawing up provisional lists of third country establishments from which the Member States authorise imports of milk and milk products for human consumption, with respect to the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (Text with EEA relevance) (notified under document number C(2002) 2301)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Decision</p>
      <p n="3">of 27 June 2002</p>
      <p n="4">amending Decision 97/252/EC drawing up provisional lists of third country establishments from which the Member States authorise imports of milk and milk products for human consumption, with respect to the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia</p>
      <p n="5">(notified under document number C(2002) 2301)</p>
      <p n="6">(Text with EEA relevance)</p>
      <p n="7">(2002/527/EC)</p>
      <p n="8">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Decision 95/408/EC of 22 June 1995 on the conditions for drawing up, for an interim period, provisional lists of third country establishments from which Member States are authorised to import certain products of animal origin, fishery products or live bivalve molluscs(1), as last amended by Decision 2001/4/EC(2), and in particular Article 2(4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="12">(1) Commission Decision 95/343/EC of 27 July 1995 providing for the specimens of the health certificate for the importation from third countries of heat-treated milk, milk-based products and raw milk for human consumption intended to be accepted at a collection centre, standardisation centre, treatment establishment or processing establishment(3), as last amended by Decision 97/115/EC(4), lays down the health and veterinary certification requirements for imports of milk and milk products for human consumption.</p>
      <p n="13">(2) The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia is listed in the Annex to Commission Decision 95/340/EC(5), as last amended by Decision 2001/743/EC(6), drawing up a provisional list of third countries from which Member States authorise imports of milk and milk products.</p>
      <p n="14">(3) The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia has provided to the Commission the name of an establishment producing milk and milk products with the guarantees that this establishment fully meets the Community health requirements.</p>
      <p n="15">(4) The Commission has received from the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia the relevant residue monitoring plan and program for milk and milk products intended for human consumption, as required in Directive 96/23/EC(7).</p>
      <p n="16">(5) Commission Decision 97/252/EC(8) as last amended by Decision 2001/177/EC(9) has drawn up provisional lists of third country establishments from which the Member States authorise imports of milk and milk-based products for human consumption. These lists should therefore be amended to include the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia list of approved establishments.</p>
      <p n="17">(6) Following Article 2(4) of Decision 95/408/EC, those non-member countries' establishments where on-the-spot checks have not yet been carried out by the Commission but which met all the other conditions of Article 2(1) may appear on the lists. However, imports from such establishments will not be eligible for reduced physical checks.</p>
      <p n="18">(7) The measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health,</p>
      <p n="19">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="20">Article 1</p>
      <p n="21">In the Annex to Decision 97/252/EC, the following row is added for the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia: "MK (a) País: Antigua República Yugoslava de Macedonia/Land: Den Tidligere Jugoslaviske Republik Makedonien/Land: die Ehemalige Jugoslawische Republik Mazedonien/Χώρα: Πρώην Γιουγκοσλαβική Δημοκρατία της Μακεδονίας/Country: Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia/Pays: Ancienne République yougoslave de Macédoine/Paese: ex Repubblica iugoslava di Macedonia/Land: Voormalige Joegoslavische Republiek Macedonië/País: antiga República jugoslava da Macedónia/Maa: Entinen Jugoslavian tasavalta Makedonia/Land: f.d. jugoslaviska republiken Makedonien.</p>
      <p n="22">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="23">Nota:</p>
      <p n="24">Código provisional que no afecta en absoluto a la denominación definitiva del país, que se acordará tras la conclusión de las negociaciones actualmente en curso sobre este tema en las Naciones Unidas.</p>
      <p n="25">/Note:</p>
      <p n="26">Denne foreløbige kode foregriber på ingen måde landets endelige benævnelse, som vil blive fastlagt efter afslutningen af de forhandlinger, der for tiden føres herom inden for rammerne af FN.</p>
      <p n="27">/Note:</p>
      <p n="28">Provisorischer Code, der die endgültige Benennung des Landes nicht berührt, die nach Abschluss der laufenden Verhandlungen innerhalb der Vereinten Nationen festgelegt wird.</p>
      <p n="29">/Σημείωση:</p>
      <p n="30">Αυτός ο κωδικός δεν προδικάζει καθόλου την οριστική ονομασία της χώρας η ονομασία θα συμφωνηθεί όταν ολοκληρωθούν οι σχετικές διαπραγματεύσεις στο πλαίσιο των Ηνωμένων Εθνών.</p>
      <p n="31">/Note:</p>
      <p n="32">Provisional code, which does not prejudge in any way the definitive nomenclature for this country, which will be agreed following the conclusion of negotiations currently taking place on this subject at the United Nations.</p>
      <p n="33">/Note:</p>
      <p n="34">Code provisoire qui ne préjuge en rien de la dénomination définitive du pays, qui sera agréée dès conclusion des négociations actuellement en cours à ce sujet dans le cadre des Nations unies.</p>
      <p n="35">/Nota:</p>
      <p n="36">Questo codice provvisorio non pregiudica assolutamente la denominazione definitiva del paese che sarà approvata non appena conclusi i negoziati attualmente in corso al riguardo nel quadro delle Nazioni Unite.</p>
      <p n="37">/Noot:</p>
      <p n="38">Voorlopige code die geen invloed op de definitieve naam van het land heeft, die aan het einde van de lopende onderhandelingen in het kader van de Verenigde Naties zal worden vastgesteld.</p>
      <p n="39">/Nota:</p>
      <p n="40">Código provisório que não interfere em nada com a denominação definitiva do país, que será aprovada após conclusão das negociações actualmente em curso sobre este assunto no quadro das Nações Unidas.</p>
      <p n="41">/Huomautus:</p>
      <p n="42">Tämä väliaikainen koodi ei estä ottamasta käyttöön maan lopullista nimeä, joka hyväksytään, kun Yhdistyneissä Kansakunnissa asiasta käytävät neuvottelut saadaan päätökseen.</p>
      <p n="43">/Anmärkning:</p>
      <p n="44">Koden föregriper inte den definitiva beteckningen av detta land, vilken kommer att bestämmas under de förhandlingar som för närvarande pågår i Förenta nationerna."</p>
      <p n="45">Article 2</p>
      <p n="46">This Decision shall apply as from the 20th day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="47">Article 3</p>
      <p n="48">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="49">Done at Brussels, 27 June 2002.</p>
      <p n="50">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="51">David Byrne</p>
      <p n="52">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="53">(1) OJ L 243, 11.10.1995, p. 17.</p>
      <p n="54">(2) OJ L 2, 5.1.2001, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="55">(3) OJ L 200, 24.8.1995, p. 52.</p>
      <p n="56">(4) OJ L 42, 13.2.1997, p. 16.</p>
      <p n="57">(5) OJ L 200, 24.8.1995, p. 38.</p>
      <p n="58">(6) OJ L 278, 23.10.2001, p. 32.</p>
      <p n="59">(7) OJ L 125, 23.5.1996, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="60">(8) OJ L 101, 18.4.1997, p. 46.</p>
      <p n="61">(9) OJ L 68, 9.3.2001, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
