<TEI.2 id="jrc32002R2066-en" n="32002R2066" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32002R2066 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EC) No 2066/2002 of 21 November 2002 supplementing the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2400/96 on the entry of certain names in the Register of protected designations of origin and protected geographical indications provided for in Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 on the protection of geographical indications and designations of origin for agricultural products and foodstuffs (Carne de Bovino Cruzado dos Lameiros do Barroso, Pruneaux d'Agen — Pruneaux d'Agen mi-cuits, Carciofo romanesco del Lazio, Aktinidio Pierias, Milo Kastorias, Welsh Beef)</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>50 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32002R2066:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32002R2066:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1118</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1120</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1686</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2962</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">3173</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4682</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4689</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5231</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5573</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32002R2066-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2066/2002 of 21 November 2002 supplementing the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2400/96 on the entry of certain names in the Register of protected designations of origin and protected geographical indications provided for in Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 on the protection of geographical indications and designations of origin for agricultural products and foodstuffs (Carne de Bovino Cruzado dos Lameiros do Barroso, Pruneaux d'Agen — Pruneaux d'Agen mi-cuits, Carciofo romanesco del Lazio, Aktinidio Pierias, Milo Kastorias, Welsh Beef)</head>
      <p n="2">Commission Regulation (EC) No 2066/2002</p>
      <p n="3">of 21 November 2002</p>
      <p n="4">supplementing the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2400/96 on the entry of certain names in the Register of protected designations of origin and protected geographical indications provided for in Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 on the protection of geographical indications and designations of origin for agricultural products and foodstuffs (Carne de Bovino Cruzado dos Lameiros do Barroso, Pruneaux d'Agen - Pruneaux d'Agen mi-cuits, Carciofo romanesco del Lazio, Aktinidio Pierias, Milo Kastorias, Welsh Beef)</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 of 14 July 1992 on the protection of geographical indications and designations of origin for agricultural products and foodstuffs(1), as last amended by Commission Regulation (EC) No 2796/2000(2), and in particular Article 6(3) and (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="9">(1) In accordance with Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92, Portugal has sent the Commission an application for registration of the name "Carne de Bovino Cruzado dos Lameiros do Barroso" as a geographical indication, France has sent the Commission an application for registration of the name "Pruneaux d'Agen - Pruneaux d'Agen mi-cuits" as a geographical indication, Italy has sent the Commission an application for registration of the name "Carciofo Romanesco del Lazio" as a geographical indication, Greece has sent the Commission two applications for registration of the names "Aktinidio Pierias" and "Milo Kastorias" as geographical indications and the United Kingdom has sent the Commission an application for registration of the name "Welsh Beef" as a geographical indication.</p>
      <p n="10">(2) In accordance with Article 6(1) of that Regulation, the applications have been found to meet all the requirements laid down therein and in particular to contain all the information required in accordance with Article 4 thereof.</p>
      <p n="11">(3) No statement of objection under Article 7 of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92 has been received by the Commission in respect of the names given in the Annex hereto following their publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities(3).</p>
      <p n="12">(4) The applicant group formerly known as "Welsh Beef Promotions" has since changed its title to "Welsh Lamb and Beef Promotions Ltd".</p>
      <p n="13">(5) The names should therefore be entered in the Register of protected designations of origin and protected geographical indications and hence be protected throughout the Community as protected designations of origin or protected geographical indications.</p>
      <p n="14">(6) The Annex to this Regulation supplements the Annex to Commission Regulation (EC) No 2400/96(4), as last amended by Regulation (EC) No 1495/2002(5),</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">The names in the Annex hereto are added to the Annex to Regulation (EC) No 2400/96 and entered as protected geographical indications (PGI) in the Register of protected designations of origin and protected geographical indications provided for in Article 6(3) of Regulation (EEC) No 2081/92.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the 20th day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 21 November 2002.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Franz Fischler</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ L 208, 24.7.1992, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ L 324, 21.12.2000, p. 26.</p>
      <p n="27">(3) OJ C 21, 25.1.2000, p. 18 (Welsh Beef)</p>
      <p n="28">OJ C 21, 24.1.2002, p. 27 (Carne de Bovino Cruzado dos Lameiros do Barroso)</p>
      <p n="29">OJ C 46, 20.2.2002, p. 5 (Pruneaux d'Agen - Pruneaux d'Agen mi-cuits)</p>
      <p n="30">OJ C 51, 26.2.2002, p. 26 (Carciofo Romanesco del Lazio)</p>
      <p n="31">OJ C 76, 27.3.2002, p. 7 (Aktinidio Pierias)</p>
      <p n="32">OJ C 67, 16.3.2002, p. 29 (Milo Kastorias)</p>
      <p n="33">(4) OJ L 327, 18.12.1996, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="34">(5) OJ L 225, 22.8.2002, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="35">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="36">PRODUCTS LISTED IN ANNEX I TO THE EC TREATY, INTENDED FOR HUMAN CONSUMPTION</p>
      <p n="37">Fresh beef</p>
      <p n="38">PORTUGAL</p>
      <p n="39">Carne de Bovino Cruzado dos Lameiros do Barroso (PGI)</p>
      <p n="40">UNITED KINGDOM</p>
      <p n="41">Welsh Beef (PGI)</p>
      <p n="42">Fruits - Dried fruit</p>
      <p n="43">FRANCE</p>
      <p n="44">Pruneaux d'Agen - Pruneaux d'Agen mi-cuits (PGI)</p>
      <p n="45">Fruit and vegetables</p>
      <p n="46">ITALY</p>
      <p n="47">Carciofo Romanesco del Lazio (PGI)</p>
      <p n="48">GREECE</p>
      <p n="49">Ακτινίδιο Πιερίας (Aktinidio Pierias) (PGI)</p>
      <p n="50">Μήλο Καστοριάς (Milo Kastorias) (PGI)</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
