<TEI.2 id="jrc32002L0093-en" n="32002L0093" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 32002L0093 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 2002/93/EC of 3 December 2002 amending Directive 77/388/EEC to extend the facility allowing Member States to apply reduced rates of VAT to certain labour-intensive services</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>30 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32002L0093:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32002L0093:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">1234</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2602</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">2897</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4392</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">4585</classCode>
        <classCode scheme="eurovoc">5283</classCode>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc32002L0093-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 2002/93/EC of 3 December 2002 amending Directive 77/388/EEC to extend the facility allowing Member States to apply reduced rates of VAT to certain labour-intensive services</head>
      <p n="2">Council Directive 2002/92/EC</p>
      <p n="3">of 3 December 2002</p>
      <p n="4">amending Directive 77/388/EEC to extend the facility allowing Member States to apply reduced rates of VAT to certain labour-intensive services</p>
      <p n="5">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN UNION,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Community, and in particular Article 93 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament(1),</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee(2),</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas:</p>
      <p n="11">(1) Article 28(6) of Council Directive 77/388/EC of 17 May 1977 on the harmonisation of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes - common system of value added tax: uniform basis of assessment(3), allows the reduced rates provided for in the third subparagraph of Article 12(3)(a) also to be applied to the labour-intensive services listed in the categories set out in Annex K to that Directive for a maximum period of three years from 1 January 2000 to 31 December 2002.</p>
      <p n="12">(2) Council Decision 2000/185/EC of 28 February 2000 authorising Member States to apply a reduced rate of VAT to certain labour-intensive services in accordance with the procedure provided for in Article 28(6) of Directive 77/388/EEC(4) authorised certain Member States to apply, up to 31 December 2002, a reduced rate of VAT to those labour-intensive services for which they had submitted an application.</p>
      <p n="13">(3) Based on the reports to be drawn up by 1 October 2002 by the Member States that have applied such reduced rates, the Commission is required to submit a global evaluation report to the Council and the European Parliament by 31 December 2002, accompanied if necessary by a proposal for a final decision on the rate to be applied to labour-intensive services.</p>
      <p n="14">(4) In view of the time needed to produce a thorough global evaluation of such reports to extend the maximum period of application set for this measure in Directive 77/388/EEC.</p>
      <p n="15">(5) Directive 77/388/EEC should therefore be amended accordingly,</p>
      <p n="16">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="17">Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">In the first subparagraph of Article 28(6) of Directive 77/388/EEC the words "three years between 1 January 2000 and 31 December 2002" shall be replaced by the words "four years between 1 January 2000 and 31 December 2003".</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">This Directive shall enter into force on the day of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="21">Article 3</p>
      <p n="22">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="23">Done at Brussels, 3 December 2002.</p>
      <p n="24">For the Council</p>
      <p n="25">The President</p>
      <p n="26">T. Pedersen</p>
      <p n="27">(1) Opinion delivered on 20 November 2002 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="28">(2) Opinion delivered on 24 October 2002 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
      <p n="29">(3) OJ L 145, 13.6.1977, p. 1. Directive as last amended by Directive 2002/38/EC (OJ L 128, 15.5.2002, p. 41).</p>
      <p n="30">(4) OJ L 59, 4.3.2000, p. 10.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
