<TEI.2 id="jrc31980D0764-en" n="31980D0764" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31980D0764 English</title>
        <title>80/764/EEC: Commission Decision of 8 July 1980 establishing the schedule of tables and definitions relating to intermediate statistical surveys of areas under vines</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>51 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980D0764:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980D0764:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31980D0764-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">80/764/EEC: Commission Decision of 8 July 1980 establishing the schedule of tables and definitions relating to intermediate statistical surveys of areas under vines</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 8 July 1980 establishing the schedule of tables and definitions relating to intermediate statistical surveys of areas under vines (80/764/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 of 5 February 1979 on statistical surveys of areas under vines (1), and in particular to Article 5 (5) and Article 6 (7) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, pursuant to Article 5 (5) of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79, the Member States must submit the results of the intermediate surveys in the form of a schedule of tables to be adopted in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 8 of that Regulation;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, in order to ensure comparability of the data given in these tables, certain definitions relating to the intermediate surveys should be laid down;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, pursuant to Article 6 (7) of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79, the information referred to in Article 6 must be forwarded to the Commission in the form of a schedule of tables to be adopted in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 8 of that Regulation;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The form of the schedule of tables for the intermediate surveys on areas under vines and for the data referred to in Article 6 of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 shall be as laid down in Annex I.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">The definitions relating to the intermediate surveys shall be as laid down in Annex II.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 3</p>
      <p n="16">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 8 July 1980.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">François-Xavier ORTOLI</p>
      <p n="20">Vice-President (1)OJ No L 54, 5.3.1979, p. 124.</p>
      <p n="21">ANNEX I</p>
      <p n="22">TABLE 5 AREA UNDER WINE-GRAPE VARIETIES BROKEN DOWN BY TYPE OF PRODUCTION AND BY YIELD CLASS IN ha</p>
      <p n="23">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0013517"&gt; TABLE 6 CHANGES IN AREAS UNDER WINE-GRAPE VINES BROKEN DOWN BY TYPE OF PRODUCTION AND BY YIELD CLASS DURING THE WINE-GROWING YEAR 19.. / ..., IN ha</p>
      <p n="24">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0013518"&gt; TABLE 7 PRODUCTION IN hl FROM THE AREA UNDER WINE-GRAPE VINES BROKEN DOWN BY YIELD CLASSES AND MEAN NATURAL ALCOHOLIC STRENGTH ESTIMATED IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TYPE OF PRODUCTION FOR THE WINE-GROWING YEAR 19.. / ...</p>
      <p n="25">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0013519"&gt; TABLE 8 ESTIMATED TREND IN PRODUCTION FROM THE AREA UNDER WINE-GRAPE VINES BY TYPE OF PRODUCTION AND YIELD CLASS OVER THE WINE-GROWING YEARS 19.. / ... TO 19.. / ...</p>
      <p n="26">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0013520"&gt;</p>
      <p n="27">ANNEX II</p>
      <p n="28">Within the meaning of this Decision, the following definitions apply: (a) holding:</p>
      <p n="29">a technico-economic unit under a single management and producing agricultural products;</p>
      <p n="30">(b) area cultivated:</p>
      <p n="31">the total area of land under vines, in production or not yet in production, intended for the production of grapes and/or vegetative propagation material for vines and subjected to regular cultivation to obtain a marketable product;</p>
      <p n="32">(c) area under wine-grape varieties for quality wines psr:</p>
      <p n="33">area under wine-grape varieties suitable for the production of quality wines produced in specified regions (psr) conforming to the provisions of Council Regulation (EEC) No 338/79 of 5 February 1979 (1) and to the provisions laid down to implement this Regulation, as well as to the national provisions taken in application of Article 19 of this same Regulation;</p>
      <p n="34">(d) area under wine-grape varieties for other wines:</p>
      <p n="35">area under wine-grape varieties cultivated for the production of wines other than quality wines psr;</p>
      <p n="36">(e) wine-growing year:</p>
      <p n="37">the wine-growing year begins on 1 September and ends on 31 August;</p>
      <p n="38">(f) wine-grape varieties:</p>
      <p n="39">as defined in Council Regulation (EEC) No 347/79 of 5 February 1979 on general rules for the classification of vine varieties (2);</p>
      <p n="40">(g) grubbing:</p>
      <p n="41">complete removal of all roots on an area planted with vines;</p>
      <p n="42">(h) discontinuation:</p>
      <p n="43">cessation of regular cultivation operations on the areas planted with vines to obtain a marketable product;</p>
      <p n="44">(i) planting:</p>
      <p n="45">definitive establishment of vine plants or parts of plants, grafted or not, with a view to production of grapes or the establishment of a parent vine for root-stock;</p>
      <p n="46">(l) replanting right:</p>
      <p n="47">the right to replant vines as a single crop on an area equivalent to that grubbed, under the circumstances laid down by Regulation (EEC) No 337/79 over the period of the eight wine-growing years following the year during which the grubbing, duly declared, took place;</p>
      <p n="48">(m) replanting:</p>
      <p n="49">planting of vines in accordance with a right of replanting;</p>
      <p n="50">(n) new planting:</p>
      <p n="51">vine planting which does not correspond to the definition of replanting given in (m). (1)OJ No L 54, 5.3.1979, p. 48. (2)OJ No L 54, 5.3.1979, p. 75.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
