<TEI.2 id="jrc31980L1274-en" n="31980L1274" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31980L1274 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 80/1274/EEC of 22 December 1980 amending, consequent on the accession of Greece, Directive 64/432/EEC on animal health problems affecting intra-Community trade in bovine animals and swine and Directive 80/217/EEC introducing Community measures for the control of classical swine fever</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980L1274:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980L1274:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31980L1274-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 80/1274/EEC of 22 December 1980 amending, consequent on the accession of Greece, Directive 64/432/EEC on animal health problems affecting intra-Community trade in bovine animals and swine and Directive 80/217/EEC introducing Community measures for the control of classical swine fever</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DIRECTIVE of 22 December 1980 amending, consequent on the accession of Greece, Directive 64/432/EEC on animal health problems affecting intra-Community trade in bovine animals and swine and Directive 80/217/EEC introducing Community measures for the control of classical swine fever (80/1274/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the 1979 Act of Accession, and in particular Article 146 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the proposal of the Commission,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, pursuant to Article 22 of the 1979 Act of Accession, the adaptations to the acts listed in Annex II to be drawn up in conformity with the guidelines set out in that Annex ; whereas Directive 64/432/EEC (1), as last amended by Directive 80/219/EEC (2), should be adapted accordingly;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas, moreover, Directive 80/217/EEC (3), which was adopted after signature of the Treaty of Accession and is valid beyond 1 January 1981, must be adapted to ensure compliance with the provisions of the Act of Accession,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Directive 64/432/EEC is hereby amended as follows: 1. At Annex B, point 12, the following letter shall be added: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0013976"&gt;</p>
      <p n="12">2. At Annex C, point 9, the following letter shall be added: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0013977"&gt;</p>
      <p n="13">3. In Annex F, footnote 4 of model certificate I and footnote 5 of model certificates II, III, and IV shall be completed by the following: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0013978"&gt;</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">The following shall be added to the list of national laboratories for swine fever in Annex II of Directive 80/217/EEC: &gt;PIC FILE= "T0013979"&gt;</p>
      <p n="16">Article 3</p>
      <p n="17">The Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with this Directive, in respect of Article 1, no later than 1 January 1981, and in respect of Article 2, no later than 1 July 1981. They shall inform the Commission immediately.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 4</p>
      <p n="19">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 22 December 1980.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">J. SANTER (1)OJ No 121, 29.7.1964, p. 1977/64. (2)OJ No L 47, 21.2.1980, p. 25. (3)OJ No L 47, 21.2.1980, p. 11.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
