<TEI.2 id="jrc31980D0763-en" n="31980D0763" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31980D0763 English</title>
        <title>80/763/EEC: Commission Decision of 8 July 1980 laying down additional provisions concerning statistical surveys of areas under vines</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980D0763:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980D0763:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31980D0763-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">80/763/EEC: Commission Decision of 8 July 1980 laying down additional provisions concerning statistical surveys of areas under vines</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 8 July 1980 laying down additional provisions concerning statistical surveys of areas under vines (80/763/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 357/79 of 5 February 1979 on statistical surveys of areas under vines (1), and in particular Article 6 (2) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas, because of the existence within the Community of growing areas with very varied yields, the areas under vines cultivated with wine-grape varieties should, in order to monitor developments in wine-growing potential effectively, be subdivided into yield classes based upon the mean yield per hectare;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, pursuant to Article 6 (2) of Regulation (EEC) No 357/79, such yield classes shall be established in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 8 of that Regulation;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for by this Decision are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Agricultural Statistics,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">The yield classes referred to in Article 6 (2) of Regulation (EEC) 357/79 shall be those indicated in the Annex.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="14">Done at Brussels, 8 July 1980.</p>
      <p n="15">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="16">François-Xavier ORTOLI</p>
      <p n="17">Vice-President (1)OJ No L 54, 5.3.1979, p. 124.</p>
      <p n="18">ANNEX YIELD CLASSES (in hl/ha of grape must or wine)</p>
      <p n="19">&gt;PIC FILE= "T0013514"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
