<TEI.2 id="jrc31980R2214-en" n="31980R2214" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31980R2214 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 2214/80 of 27 June 1980 on the conclusion of the Agreement on fisheries between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980R2214:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980R2214:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31980R2214-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 2214/80 of 27 June 1980 on the conclusion of the Agreement on fisheries between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 2214/80 of 27 June 1980 on the conclusion of the Agreement on fisheries between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament [1],</p>
      <p n="7">[1]OJ No C 182, 31.7.1978, p. 56.</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas by its resolution of 3 November 1976 on certain external aspects of the creation of a 200-mile fisheries zone in the Community with effect from 1 January 1977, the Council agreed that fishing rights for Community fishermen in the waters of third countries must be obtained and preserved by appropriate Community Agreements;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Agreement on fisheries between the Community and Norway should be approved,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">The Agreement on fisheries between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Norway is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="13">The text of the Agreement is annexed to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">The President of the Council shall give the notification provided for in Article 12 of the Agreement [2].</p>
      <p n="16">[2]The date of the entry into force of the Agreement will be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities by the General Secretariat of the Council.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 3</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 27 June 1980.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">A. SARTI</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
