<TEI.2 id="jrc31980D0461-en" n="31980D0461" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31980D0461 English</title>
        <title>80/461/EEC: Council Decision of 22 April 1980 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement negotiated between the European Economic Community and Canada under Article XXVIII of GATT concerning certain products in the fruit and vegetables sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>19 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980D0461:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980D0461:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31980D0461-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">80/461/EEC: Council Decision of 22 April 1980 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement negotiated between the European Economic Community and Canada under Article XXVIII of GATT concerning certain products in the fruit and vegetables sector</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 22 April 1980 concerning the conclusion of the Agreement negotiated between the European Economic Community and Canada under Article XXVIII of GATT concerning certain products in the fruit and vegetables sector (80/461/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Canada, on the basis of Article XXVIII of the General Agreement on tariffs and trade (GATT), indicated its intention of modifying tariff concessions on certain products of which the European Economic Community is its principal supplier;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the Commission opened negotiations with Canada under Article XXVIII of GATT and has reached a satisfactory agreement with that country,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The Agreement negotiated between the European Economic Community and Canada under Article XXVIII of GATT concerning certain products in the fruit and vegetables sector is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="11">The text of the Agreement is annexed to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the Agreement in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="14">Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">The outcome of the negotiations shall be notified to the Contracting Parties to GATT.</p>
      <p n="16">Done at Luxembourg, 22 April 1980.</p>
      <p n="17">For the Council</p>
      <p n="18">The President</p>
      <p n="19">G. ZAMBERLETTI</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
