<TEI.2 id="jrc31980R0914-en" n="31980R0914" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31980R0914 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 914/80 of 15 April 1980 amending for the second time Regulation (EEC) No 2960/77 on detailed rules for the sale of olive oil held by intervention agencies</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>20 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980R0914:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31980R0914:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31980R0914-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 914/80 of 15 April 1980 amending for the second time Regulation (EEC) No 2960/77 on detailed rules for the sale of olive oil held by intervention agencies</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 914/80 of 15 April 1980 amending for the second time Regulation (EEC) No 2960/77 on detailed rules for the sale of olive oil held by intervention agencies</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation No 136/66/EEC of 22 September 1966 on the establishment of a common organization of the market in oils and fats (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 590/79 (2), and in particular Article 12 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Article 5 (3) of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2960/77 (3), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 883/79 (4), specifies the stage at which the minimum selling price for olive oil fixed under an invitation to tender shall apply;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the application of Article 5 (3) of Regulation (EEC) No 2960/77 was limited in time ; whereas experience has shown that the stage therein specified is the most appropriate as regards the olive oil sector ; whereas application of the provision in question should therefore no longer be limited;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Oils and Fats,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Paragraph 3 of Article 5 of Regulation (EEC) No 2960/77 is amended to read as follows:</p>
      <p n="12">"3. The minimum price shall be net of tax and shall relate to 100 kilograms of olive oil delivered in the purchaser's own drums, loaded on a vehicle provided by the purchaser ex-storage depot, or in the purchaser's tanker ex-storage depot."</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="15">It shall apply with effect from 1 January 1980.</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="17">Done at Brussels, 15 April 1980.</p>
      <p n="18">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">Finn GUNDELACH</p>
      <p n="20">Vice-President (1)OJ No 172, 30.9.1966, p. 3025/66. (2)OJ No L 78, 30.3.1979, p. 1. (3)OJ No L 348, 30.12.1977, p. 46. (4)OJ No L 111, 4.5.1979, p. 16.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
