<TEI.2 id="jrc31992D0583-en" n="31992D0583" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992D0583 English</title>
        <title>92/583/EEC: Council Decision of 14 December 1992 on the conclusion of the Protocol of amendment to the European Convention for the Protection of Animals kept for Farming Purposes</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992D0583:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992D0583:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992D0583-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">92/583/EEC: Council Decision of 14 December 1992 on the conclusion of the Protocol of amendment to the European Convention for the Protection of Animals kept for Farming Purposes</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 14 December 1992 on the conclusion of the Protocol of amendment to the European Convention for the Protection of Animals kept for Farming Purposes (92/583/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (2),</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas by Decision 78/923/EEC (3) the Community approved the European Convention for the Protection of Animals kept for Farming Purposes, hereinafter referred to as 'the Convention`; whereas the Community has deposited its instrument of approval;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe adopted, on 15 November 1991, a Protocol of amendment to the Convention in order to take account of technical and scientific developments in livestock farming;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas disparities in national laws on the protection of animals kept for farming purposes may give rise to unequal conditions of competition and may consequently have an indirect effect on the proper functioning of the common market;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the Convention covers matters which fall within the scope of the common agricultural policy;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the Community's participation thus contributes to the achievement of its objectives,</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the Protocol of amendment should therefore be approved,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The Protocol of amendment to the European Convention for the Protection of Animals kept for Farming Purposes is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="17">The text of the Protocol is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">The President of the Council shall deposit the instrument of approval in accordance with Article 6 (4) of the Protocol of amendment.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 14 December 1992.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">J. GUMMER</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ N° C 337, 21. 12. 1992.</p>
      <p n="25">(2) OJ N° C 332, 16. 12. 1992, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) OJ N° L 323, 17. 11. 1978, p. 12.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
