<TEI.2 id="jrc31992L0089-en" n="31992L0089" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992L0089 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 92/89/EEC of 3 November 1992 amending Annex I to Fourth Directive 73/46/EEC establishing Community methods of analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992L0089:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992L0089:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992L0089-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 92/89/EEC of 3 November 1992 amending Annex I to Fourth Directive 73/46/EEC establishing Community methods of analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE 92/89/EEC of 3 November 1992 amending Annex I to Fourth Directive 73/46/EEC establishing Community methods of analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 70/373/EEC of 20 July 1970 on the introduction of Community methods of sampling and analysis for the official control of feedingstuffs (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3768/85 (2), and in particular Article 2 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Fourth Commission Directive 73/46/EEC (3), as amended by Directive 81/680/EEC (4), prescribes the method to be used for the determination of crude fibre;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas there are grounds to adapt this method in the light of advances in scientific and technical knowledge; whereas it is advisable, in particular, to take account of the provisions of Council Directive 80/1107/EEC of 27 November 1980 on the protection of workers from the risks related to exposure to chemical, physical and biological agents at work (5), as amended by Directive 88/642/EEC (6), and, in particular, the measures taken to prevent exposure to asbestos;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas it is from now on necessary to replace asbestos by glass containers in order to carry out the filtration procedures;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee for Feedingstuffs,</p>
      <p n="10">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="11">Article 1</p>
      <p n="12">Annex I to Directive 73/46/EEC is amended in accordance with this Directive.</p>
      <p n="13">Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">Member States shall bring into force not later than 1 October 1993 the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with the provisions of this Directive. They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="15">When Member States adopt these provisions, these shall contain a reference to this Directive or shall be accompanied by such reference at the time of their official publication. The procedure for such reference shall be adopted by the Member States.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 3</p>
      <p n="17">This Directive is addressed to the Member States. Done at Brussels, 3 November 1992. For the Commission</p>
      <p n="18">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="19">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="20">(1) OJ No L 170, 3. 8. 1970, p. 2. (2) OJ No L 362, 31. 12. 1985, p. 8. (3) OJ No L 83, 30. 3. 1973, p. 21. (4) OJ No L 246, 29. 8. 1981, p. 32. (5) OJ No L 327, 3. 12. 1980, p. 8. (6) OJ No L 356, 24. 12. 1988, p. 74.</p>
      <p n="21">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="22">Annex I, point 3, 'Determination of crude fibre' is replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="23">/* Tables: see OJ */</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
