<TEI.2 id="jrc31992D0605-en" n="31992D0605" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992D0605 English</title>
        <title>92/605/EEC: Council Decision of 14 December 1992 concerning the conclusion of a trade and cooperation agreement between the European Economic Community and Macao</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992D0605:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992D0605:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992D0605-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">92/605/EEC: Council Decision of 14 December 1992 concerning the conclusion of a trade and cooperation agreement between the European Economic Community and Macao</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 14 December 1992 concerning the conclusion of a trade and cooperation agreement between the European Economic Community and Macao (92/605/ EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 113 and 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas the Agreement for trade and cooperation between the European Economic Community and Macao should be approved,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The Agreement for trade and cooperation between the European Economic Community and Macao is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="11">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">The President of the Council shall give the notification provided for in Article 19 of the Agreement (2).</p>
      <p n="14">Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">The Commission, assisted by representatives of the Member States, shall represent the Community in the Joint Committee set up by Article 16 of the Agreement.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 4</p>
      <p n="17">This Decision shall be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Luxembourg, 14 December 1992.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Council</p>
      <p n="20">The President</p>
      <p n="21">N. LAMONT</p>
      <p n="22">(1) OJ No C 337, 21. 12. 1992.</p>
      <p n="23">(2) See page 32 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
