<TEI.2 id="jrc31992R1939-en" n="31992R1939" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992R1939 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1939/92 of 14 July 1992 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2921/90 on aid for the production of casein and caseinates from skimmed milk</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>23 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992R1939:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992R1939:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992R1939-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1939/92 of 14 July 1992 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2921/90 on aid for the production of casein and caseinates from skimmed milk</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1939/92 of 14 July 1992 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2921/90 on aid for the production of casein and caseinates from skimmed milk</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 816/92 (2), and in particular Article 11 (3) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 756/70 of 24 April 1970 on granting aid for skimmed milk processed into casein and caseinates (3) was repealed by Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2921/90 (4), as amended by Regulation (EEC) No 1768/91 (5); whereas specific provisions were adopted in order to facilitate release of securities lodged from 1 March 1989 under Article 4 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 756/70; whereas these provisions have not so far, for no reason attributable to the producers in question, enabled all cases to be settled; whereas the time limits set by Article 28 of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2220/85 of 22 July 1985 laying down common detailed rules for the application of the system of securities for agricultural products (6), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3745/89 (7), should therefore be extended in order to prevent unjustified loss of the securities in question;</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas Article 2 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 2921/90 sets the aid for skimmed milk processed into casein or caseinates; whereas given the market trend for these products and that for skimmed milk powder the aid should be reduced;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">Regulation (EEC) No 2921/90 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="12">1. in Article 2 (1) the amount of 'ECU 7,94' is replaced by 'ECU 7,00';</p>
      <p n="13">2. the following sixth paragraph is added to Article 6:</p>
      <p n="14">'At the request of the parties concerned the time limits of 12 months and three years specified in Article 28 of Regulation (EEC) No 2220/85 may be raised to 18 months and 42 months respectively.'</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="17">However,</p>
      <p n="18">- point 1 in Article 1 shall apply from 20 July 1992,</p>
      <p n="19">- point 2 in Article 1 shall apply from 1 October 1991. This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 14 July 1992. For the Commission</p>
      <p n="21">Ray MAC SHARRY</p>
      <p n="22">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13. (2) OJ No L 86, 1. 4. 1992, p. 83. (3) OJ No L 91, 25. 4. 1970, p. 28. (4) OJ No L 279, 11. 10. 1990, p. 22. (5) OJ No L 158, 22. 6. 1991, p. 49. (6) OJ No L 205, 3. 8. 1985, p. 5. (7) OJ No L 364, 14. 12. 1989, p. 54.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
