<TEI.2 id="jrc31992D0205-en" n="31992D0205" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992D0205 English</title>
        <title>92/205/EEC:Council Decision of 16 March 1992 concerning the conclusion of the Framework Agreement for cooperation between the European Economic Community and the Eastern Republic of Uruguay</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>18 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992D0205:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992D0205:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992D0205-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">92/205/EEC:Council Decision of 16 March 1992 concerning the conclusion of the Framework Agreement for cooperation between the European Economic Community and the Eastern Republic of Uruguay</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DECISION of 16 March 1992 concerning the conclusion of the Framework Agreement for cooperation between the European Economic Community and the Eastern Republic of Uruguay (92/205/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 113 and 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas, in order to attain its objectives regarding external economic relations, the Community should approve the Framework Agreement for cooperation with the Eastern Republic of Uruguay,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The Framework Agreement for cooperation between the European Economic Community and the Eastern Republic of Uruguay is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="11">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="12">Article 2</p>
      <p n="13">The President of the Council shall give the notification provided for in Article 25 of the Agreement (3).</p>
      <p n="14">Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">The Commission, assisted by representatives of the Member States, shall represent the Community in the Joint Committee set up by Article 21 of the Agreement.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 4</p>
      <p n="17">This Decision shall be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities and shall enter into force on the day of publication.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 16 March 1992. For the Council The President Jorge BRAGA DE MACEDO</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
