<TEI.2 id="jrc31992R1084-en" n="31992R1084" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992R1084 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 1084/92 of 28 April 1992 amending Regulation No 422/67/EEC, No 5/67/Euratom determining the emoluments of the President and Members of the Commission, of the President, Judges, Advocates-General and Registrar of the Court of Justice and of the President, Members and Registrar of the Court of First Instance, and Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 2290/77 determining the emoluments of the Members of the Court of Auditors</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>25 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992R1084:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992R1084:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992R1084-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 1084/92 of 28 April 1992 amending Regulation No 422/67/EEC, No 5/67/Euratom determining the emoluments of the President and Members of the Commission, of the President, Judges, Advocates-General and Registrar of the Court of Justice and of the President, Members and Registrar of the Court of First Instance, and Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 2290/77 determining the emoluments of the Members of the Court of Auditors</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC, EURATOM, ECSC) No 1084/92 of 28 April 1992 amending Regulation No 422/67/EEC, No 5/67/Euratom determining the emoluments of the President and Members of the Commission, of the President, Judges, Advocates-General and Registrar of the Court of Justice and of the President, Members and Registrar of the Court of First Instance, and Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 2290/77 determining the emoluments of the Members of the Court of Auditors</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing a Single Council and a Single Commission of the European Communities, and in particular Article 6 thereof,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Coal and Steel Community, and in particular Article 78e thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 206 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community, and in particular Article 180 thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Protocol on the Privileges and Immunities of the European Communities, and in particular Articles 20 and 21 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas Council Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 3831/91 of 19 December 1991 amending the Staff Regulations of Officials and the Conditions of Employment of Other Servants of the European Communities with a view to introducing a temporary contribution (1) incorporated in the Staff Regulations of Officials of the European Communities an Article 66a introducing such a temporary contribution;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas that temporary contribution should be applied mutatis mutandis to the President and Members of the Commission, the President, Judges, Advocates-General and Registrar of the Court of Justice, the President, Members and Registrar of the Court of First Instance and the Members of the Court of Auditors,</p>
      <p n="11">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="12">Article 1</p>
      <p n="13">1. Article 19a of Regulation No 422/67/EEC, No 5/67/Euratom (2) is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="14">'Article 19a</p>
      <p n="15">Article 66a of the Staff Regulations of Officials shall apply mutatis mutandis to the President and Members of the Commission, the President, Judges, Advocates-General and Registrar of the Court of Justice and the President, Members and Registrar of the Court of First Instance.'</p>
      <p n="16">2. Article 19a of Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 2290/77 (3) is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="17">'Article 19a</p>
      <p n="18">Article 66a of the Staff Regulations of Officials shall apply mutatis mutandis to the Members of the Court of Auditors.'</p>
      <p n="19">Article 2</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="21">It shall apply as from 1 January 1992. This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="22">Done at Luxembourg, 28 April 1992. For the Council</p>
      <p n="23">The President</p>
      <p n="24">Arlindo MARQUES CUNHA</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ No L 361, 31. 12. 1991, p. 7. (2) OJ No L 187, 8. 8. 1967, p. 1. Regulation as last amended by Regulation (ECSC, EEC, Euratom) No 3835/91 (OJ No L 361, 31. 12. 1991, p. 16). (3) OJ No L 268, 20. 10. 1977, p. 1. Regulation as last amended by Regulation (EEC, Euratom, ECSC) No 2426/91 (OJ No L 222, 10. 8. 1991, p. 1).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
