<TEI.2 id="jrc31992R3899-en" n="31992R3899" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31992R3899 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3899/92 of 23 December 1992 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3510/82 fixing the conversion factors applicable to tuna</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992R3899:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31992R3899:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31992R3899-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3899/92 of 23 December 1992 amending Regulation (EEC) No 3510/82 fixing the conversion factors applicable to tuna</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 3899/92</p>
      <p n="3">of 23 December 1992</p>
      <p n="4">amending Regulation (EEC) No 3510/82 fixing the conversion factors applicable to tuna</p>
      <p n="5">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 3759/92 of 17 December 1992 on the common organization of the market in fishery and aquaculture products (1), and in particular Article 17 (6) thereof,</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3510/82 (2), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3971/89 (3), fixes the conversion factors applicable to the different species, sizes and presentations of tuna;</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas the developments on the tuna market since the fixing of the conversion factors have brought about a change in the commercial value ratio between the products concerned and the pilot product; whereas this state of affairs calls for the conversion factors in question and the products for which they are specifically intended to be reviewed;</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas, therefore, the Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 3510/92 should be amended;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Fishery Products,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 3510/82 is replaced by the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="15">Article 2</p>
      <p n="16">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 January 1993.</p>
      <p n="17">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 23 December 1992. For the Commission</p>
      <p n="19">Manuel MARÍN</p>
      <p n="20">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="21">ANNEX</p>
      <p n="22">&lt;(BLK0)BLK2 ID="I"&gt;</p>
      <p n="23">I. Conversion factors applicable to the different species of tuna</p>
      <p n="24">&gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="25">II. Conversion factors applicable to each of the species referred to in section I depending on the presentation &gt;TABLE&gt;</p>
      <p n="26">&lt;/(BLK0)BLK2&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
