<TEI.2 id="jrc41992X1223-en" n="41992X1223" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 41992X1223 English</title>
        <title>Decision taken by common agreement between the Representatives of the Governments of the Member States on the location of the seats of the institutions and of certain bodies and departments of the European Communities</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>56 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41992X1223:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:41992X1223:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc41992X1223-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Decision taken by common agreement between the Representatives of the Governments of the Member States on the location of the seats of the institutions and of certain bodies and departments of the European Communities</head>
      <p n="2">DECISION TAKEN BY COMMON AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE REPRESENTATIVES OF THE GOVERNMENTS OF THE MEMBER STATES ON THE LOCATION OF THE SEATS OF THE INSTITUTIONS AND OF CERTAIN BODIES AND DEPARTMENTS OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES (92/C 341/01)</p>
      <p n="3">THE REPRESENTATIVES OF THE GOVERNMENTS OF THE MEMBER STATES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to Article 216 of the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, Article 77 of the Treaty establishing the European Coal and Steel Community and Article 189 of the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Recalling the Decision of 8 April 1965, and without prejudice to the provisions contained therein concerning the seat of future institutions, bodies and departments,</p>
      <p n="6">HEREBY DECIDE: Article 1</p>
      <p n="7">(a) The European Parliament shall have its seat in Strasbourg where the twelve periods of monthly plenary sessions, including the budget session, shall be held. The periods of additional plenary sessions shall be held in Brussels. The Committees of the European Parliament shall meet in Brussels. The General Secretariat of the European Parliament and its departments shall remain in Luxembourg.</p>
      <p n="8">(b) The Council shall have its seat in Brussels. During the months of April, June and October, the Council shall hold its meetings in Luxembourg.</p>
      <p n="9">(c) The Commission shall have its seat in Brussels. The departments listed in Articles 7, 8 and 9 of the Decision of 8 April 1965 shall be established in Luxembourg.</p>
      <p n="10">(d) The Court of Justice and the Court of First Instance shall have their seats in Luxembourg.</p>
      <p n="11">(e) The Economic and Social Committee shall have its seat in Brussels.</p>
      <p n="12">(f) The Court of Auditors shall have its seat in Luxembourg.</p>
      <p n="13">(g) The European Investment Bank shall have its seat in Luxembourg. Article 2</p>
      <p n="14">The seat of other bodies and departments set up or to be set up will be decided by common agreement between the Representatives of the Governments of the Member States at a forthcoming European Council, taking account of the advantages of the above provisions to the Member States concerned, and giving appropriate priority to Member States who do not at present provide the sites for Community institutions. Article 3</p>
      <p n="15">This Decison shall enter into force as of today.</p>
      <p n="16">Hecho en Edimburgo, el doce de diciembre de mil novecientos noventa y dos.</p>
      <p n="17">Udfaerdiget i Edinburgh, den tolvte december nitten hundrede og tooghalvfems.</p>
      <p n="18">Geschehen zu Edinburgh am zwoelften Dezember neunzehnhundertzweiundneunzig.</p>
      <p n="19">¸ãéíaa óôï AAaeéìâïýñãï, óôéò aeþaeaaêá AEaaêaaìâñssïõ ÷ssëéá aaííéáêueóéá aaíaaíÞíôá aeýï.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Edinburgh on the twelfth day of December in the year one thousand nine hundred and ninety-two.</p>
      <p n="21">Fait à Édimbourg, le douze décembre mil neuf cent quatre-vingt-douze.</p>
      <p n="22">Fatto a Edimburgo, addì dodici dicembre millenovecentonovantadue.</p>
      <p n="23">Gedaan te Edinburgh, de twaalfde december negentienhonderd tweeënnegentig.</p>
      <p n="24">Feito em Edimburgo, em doze de Dezembro de mil novecentos e noventa e dois.</p>
      <p n="25">Pour le gouvernement du royaume de Belgique</p>
      <p n="26">Voor de Regering van het Koninkrijk België</p>
      <p n="27">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="28">For regeringen for Kongeriget Danmark</p>
      <p n="29">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="30">Fuer die Regierung der Bundesrepublik Deutschland</p>
      <p n="31">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="32">Ãéá ôçí êõâÝñíçóç ôçò AAëëçíéêÞò AEçìïêñáôssáò</p>
      <p n="33">&gt; REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="34">Por el Gobierno del Reino de España</p>
      <p n="35">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="36">Pour le gouvernement de la République française</p>
      <p n="37">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="38">For the Government of Ireland</p>
      <p n="39">Thar ceann Rialtas na hÉireann</p>
      <p n="40">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="41">Per il governo della Repubblica italiana</p>
      <p n="42">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="43">Pour le gouvernement du grand-duché de Luxembourg</p>
      <p n="44">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="45">Voor de Regering van het Koninkrijk der Nederlanden</p>
      <p n="46">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="47">Pelo Governo da República Portuguesa</p>
      <p n="48">&gt; REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="49">For the Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</p>
      <p n="50">&gt;REFERENCE TO A FILM&gt;</p>
      <p n="51">Statement</p>
      <p n="52">The Representatives of the Governments of the Member States declare that, taking into account the Protocol on the Economic and Social Committee and the Committee of the Regions annexed to the Treaty establishing the European Community, the Committee of the Regions, having an organizational structure in common with the Economic and Social Committee, shall also have its seat in Brussels.</p>
      <p n="53">Unilateral Declaration of Luxembourg</p>
      <p n="54">Luxembourg accepts this formula in a spirit of compromise. It is however understood that its acceptance may not be interpreted as constituting a waiver of the provisions and the potentialities of the Decision of 8 April 1965.</p>
      <p n="55">Unilateral Declaration of the Netherlands</p>
      <p n="56">The Netherlands Government takes it as self-evident that the Decision of 1965, in view of the enlargement of the Community and of its institutions and bodies in the meantime, may never stand in the way of a balanced and equitable distribution of the seats of the institutions and bodies throughout the Member States.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
