<TEI.2 id="jrc21977A0312_01-en" n="21977A0312(01)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21977A0312(01) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>38 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21977A0312(01):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21977A0312(01):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21977A0312_01-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">AGREEMENT in the form of an exchange of letters between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Morocco concerning certain wine originating in Morocco and entitled to a designation of origin</p>
      <p n="3">Your Excellency,</p>
      <p n="4">I have the honour to inform you that the necessary conditions have been fulfilled for the application of the concession provided for, subject to observance of the reference price, in Article 21 (2) of the Cooperation Agreement signed on 27 April 1976 between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Morocco and in Article 14 (2) of the Interim Agreement, as regards imports into the Community of wine which is entitled, under Moroccan law, to one of the designations of origin listed below and in respect of which you have requested application of the above provisions: - BERKANE,</p>
      <p n="5">- SAIS,</p>
      <p n="6">- BENI M'TIR,</p>
      <p n="7">- GUERROUANE,</p>
      <p n="8">- ZEMMOUR,</p>
      <p n="9">- ZENNATA.</p>
      <p n="10">In addition, I am taking this opportunity to inform you that, for the purposes of application of the Community declaration on the provisions of the above Articles, wine in bulk must, in order to qualify for the arrangements in question, be put up in accordance with the following requirements: (a) the containers must be suitable for transporting wine and be used solely for that purpose;</p>
      <p n="11">(b) the containers must be completely filled;</p>
      <p n="12">(c) the means of closing the containers must be such that they cannot be tampered with and must ensure that they cannot be the subject of operations during transportation or storage other than those carried out under the supervision of the authorities of either Morocco or the Member States of the Community;</p>
      <p n="13">(d) each container must be labelled in such a way as to permit identification of the quality wine it contains;</p>
      <p n="14">(e) the wine in question may be transported only in containers of a capacity not exceeding 25 hectolitres.</p>
      <p n="15">This Agreement in the form of an exchange of letters shall form an integral part of the Cooperation Agreement and of the Interim Agreement.</p>
      <p n="16">The Community will take all necessary steps to ensure that the above arrangements apply with effect from 1 April 1977.</p>
      <p n="17">I should be grateful if you would confirm the agreement of your Government to the foregoing.</p>
      <p n="18">Please accept, Your Excellency, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Council of the European Communities</p>
      <p n="20">Sir,</p>
      <p n="21">I have the honour to acknowledge receipt of your letter of today's date, in which you inform me as follows:</p>
      <p n="22">"I have the honour to inform you that the necessary conditions have been fulfilled for the application of the concession provided for, subject to observance of the reference price, in Article 21 (2) of the Cooperation Agreement signed on 27 April 1976 between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Morocco and in Article 14 (2) of the Interim Agreement, as regards imports into the Community of wine which is entitled, under Moroccan law, to one of the designations of origin listed below and in respect of which you have requested application of the above provisions: - BERKANE,</p>
      <p n="23">- SAIS,</p>
      <p n="24">- BENI M'TIR,</p>
      <p n="25">- GUERROUANE,</p>
      <p n="26">- ZEMMOUR,</p>
      <p n="27">- ZENNATA.</p>
      <p n="28">In addition, I am taking this opportunity to inform you that, for the purposes of application of the Community declaration on the provisions of the above Articles, wine in bulk must, in order to qualify for the arrangements in question, be put up in accordance with the following requirements: (a) the containers must be suitable for transporting wine and be used solely for that purpose;</p>
      <p n="29">(b) the containers must be completely filled;</p>
      <p n="30">(c) the means of closing the containers must be such that they cannot be tampered with and must ensure that they cannot be the subject of operations during transportation or storage other than those carried out under the supervision of the authorities of either Morocco or the Member States of the Community;</p>
      <p n="31">(d) each container must be labelled in such a way as to permit identification of the quality wine it contains;</p>
      <p n="32">(e) the wine in question may be transported only in containers of a capacity not exceeding 25 hectolitres.</p>
      <p n="33">This Agreement in the form of an exchange of letters shall form an integral part of the Cooperation Agreement and of the Interim Agreement.</p>
      <p n="34">The Community will take all necessary steps to ensure that the above arrangements apply with effect from 1 April 1977.</p>
      <p n="35">I should be grateful if you would confirm the agreement of your Government to the foregoing."</p>
      <p n="36">I can confirm the agreement of my Government to the foregoing.</p>
      <p n="37">Please accept, Sir, the assurance of my highest consideration.</p>
      <p n="38">For the Government of the Kingdom of Morocco</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
