<TEI.2 id="jrc31977R1496-en" n="31977R1496" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31977R1496 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1496/77 of 4 July 1977 on communications between Member States and the Commission in the silkworm sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31977R1496:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31977R1496:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31977R1496-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 1496/77 of 4 July 1977 on communications between Member States and the Commission in the silkworm sector</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 1496/77 of 4 July 1977 on communications between Member States and the Commission in the silkworm sector</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 845/72 of 24 April 1972 laying down special measures to encourage silkworm rearing (1), and in particular Article 4 thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 867/77 of 26 April 1977 on the granting of supplementary aid in the silkworm sector for the 1977/78 marketing year (2), and in particular Article 5 thereof,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas to ensure the proper functioning of the aid system referred to in Regulations (EEC) No 845/72 and (EEC) No 867/77 certain information on production and the payment of these aids should be communicated regularly by the producer Member States to the Commission;</p>
      <p n="8">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Flax and Hemp,</p>
      <p n="9">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="10">Article 1</p>
      <p n="11">In respect of both the aid referred to in paragraph 2 (1) of Regulation (EEC) No 845/72 and the supplementary aid referred to in Article 1 of Regulation (EEC) No 867/77, producer Member States shall notify the Commission: 1. during the second month following that of the final date for lodging the application for aid: (a) of the number of applications for aid submitted during the current marketing year,</p>
      <p n="12">(b) of the number of boxes of eggs for which the applications referred to under (a) have been made,</p>
      <p n="13">(c) of the quantity of cocoons produced from these eggs;</p>
      <p n="14">2. during the month following that during which final payment of the aid for the marketing year is made, the number of boxes for which:</p>
      <p n="15">(a) the entitlement to aid has been established,</p>
      <p n="16">(b) the entitlement to aid has not been recognized,</p>
      <p n="17">(c) where appropriate, the entitlement to aid has not yet been established.</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 4 July 1977.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Finn GUNDELACH</p>
      <p n="24">Vice-President (1)OJ No L 100, 27.4.1972, p. 1. (2)OJ No L 106, 29.4.1977, p. 3.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
