<TEI.2 id="jrc31977D0527-en" n="31977D0527" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31977D0527 English</title>
        <title>77/527/EEC: Commission Decision of 29 July 1977 establishing the list of maritime shipping lanes for the application of Council Directive 76/135/EEC</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>75 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31977D0527:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31977D0527:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31977D0527-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">77/527/EEC: Commission Decision of 29 July 1977 establishing the list of maritime shipping lanes for the application of Council Directive 76/135/EEC</head>
      <p n="2">COMMISSION DECISION of 29 July 1977 establishing the list of maritime shipping lanes for the application of Council Directive 76/135/EEC (77/527/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="4">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="5">Having regard to Council Directive 76/135/EEC of 20 January 1976 on the reciprocal recognition of navigability licences for inland waterway vessels (1), and in particular Article 3 (6) thereof,</p>
      <p n="6">Having regard to the communications of the Member States,</p>
      <p n="7">Whereas it is the duty of the Commission to establish the list of maritime shipping lanes on the basis of the information supplied by the Member States,</p>
      <p n="8">HAS ADOPTED THIS DECISION:</p>
      <p n="9">Article 1</p>
      <p n="10">The list of maritime shipping lanes referred to in Article 3 (6) of Directive 76/135/EEC is hereby established as set out in the Annex hereto.</p>
      <p n="11">Article 2</p>
      <p n="12">This Decision is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="13">Done at Brussels, 29 July 1977.</p>
      <p n="14">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="15">Richard BURKE</p>
      <p n="16">Member of the Commission (1)OJ No L 21, 19.1.1976, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="17">BILAG - ANHANG - ANNEX - ANNEXE - ALLEGATO - BIJLAGE</p>
      <p n="18">Fortegnelse over indre vandveje af maritim karakter i henhold til artikel 3, stk. 6, i direktiv 76/135/EØF</p>
      <p n="19">Liste der Seeschiffahrtsstraßen gemäß Artikel 3 Absatz 6 der Richtlinie Nr. 76/135/EWG</p>
      <p n="20">List of maritime shipping lanes established under Article 3 (6) of Directive 76/135/EEC</p>
      <p n="21">Liste des voies navigables à caractère maritime au titre de l'article 3 paragraphe 6 de la directive 76/135/CEE</p>
      <p n="22">Lista delle vie navigabili a carattere marittimo stabilita ai sensi dell'articolo 3 paragrafo 6 della Direttiva 76/135/CEE</p>
      <p n="23">Lijst van de waterwegen waar maritieme omstandigheden kunnen heersen, overeenkomstig artikel 3, lid 6, van Richtlijn 76/135/EEG</p>
      <p n="24">ROYAUME DE BELGIQUE - Les canaux maritimes:</p>
      <p n="25">- de Bruxelles au Rupel - de Gand à Terneuzen</p>
      <p n="26">- de Bruges à Zeebrugge</p>
      <p n="27">- l'Escaut maritime inférieur du sud d'Anvers à la frontière néerlandaise</p>
      <p n="28">- l'Escaut maritime supérieur en amont du sud d'Anvers jusqu'à l'aval du pont de Tamise</p>
      <p n="29">BUNDESREPUBLIK DEUTSCHLAND - Ems von Delfzyl/Knock bis Umschlagplatz Mövensteert</p>
      <p n="30">- Ems bis Delfzyl/Knock</p>
      <p n="31">- Jade</p>
      <p n="32">- Weser unterhalb von Brake</p>
      <p n="33">- Elbe unterhalb des Hamburger Hafens</p>
      <p n="34">- Meldorfer Bucht</p>
      <p n="35">- Flensburger Förde</p>
      <p n="36">- Eckernförder Bucht</p>
      <p n="37">- Kieler Förde seewärts des Nord-Ostsee-Kanals</p>
      <p n="38">- Ems von Papenburg bis Emden</p>
      <p n="39">- Weser von der Eisenbahnbrücke in Bremen bis Brake</p>
      <p n="40">- Leda</p>
      <p n="41">- Hunte</p>
      <p n="42">- Lesum</p>
      <p n="43">- Este</p>
      <p n="44">- Lühe</p>
      <p n="45">- Schwinge</p>
      <p n="46">- Freiburger Hafenpriel</p>
      <p n="47">- Oste</p>
      <p n="48">- Pinnau</p>
      <p n="49">- Krückau</p>
      <p n="50">- Stör</p>
      <p n="51">- Eider</p>
      <p n="52">- Nord-Ostsee-Kanal</p>
      <p n="53">- Kieler Förde binnenwärts Einfahrt Nord-Ostsee-Kanal</p>
      <p n="54">- Trave</p>
      <p n="55">- Schlei</p>
      <p n="56">RÉPUBLIQUE FRANÇAISE - Seine : à l'aval du pont Jeanne d'Arc à Rouen</p>
      <p n="57">- Garonne et Gironde : à l'aval du pont de pierre à Bordeaux</p>
      <p n="58">- Rhône : à l'aval du pont Trinquetaille à Arles au-delà vers Marseille</p>
      <p n="59">KONINKRIJK DER NEDERLANDEN - Dollard</p>
      <p n="60">- Eems</p>
      <p n="61">- Waddenzee met inbegrip van de verbindingen naar de Noordzee</p>
      <p n="62">- IJsselmeer met inbegrip van het Markermeer en het IJmeer, met uitzondering evenwel van de Gouwzee</p>
      <p n="63">- Hollandsch Diep</p>
      <p n="64">- Haringvliet en Vuile Gat met inbegrip van alle vaarwateren tussen Goeree-Overflakkee enerzijds en Voorne-Putten en de Hoekse Waard anderzijds</p>
      <p n="65">- Hellegat</p>
      <p n="66">- Volkerak</p>
      <p n="67">- Kramer</p>
      <p n="68">- Grevelingen en Brouwershavensche Gat met inbegrip van alle vaarwateren tussen Schouwen-Duiveland enerzijds en Goeree-Overflakkee anderzijds</p>
      <p n="69">- Keten</p>
      <p n="70">- Mastgat</p>
      <p n="71">- Zijpe</p>
      <p n="72">- Krabbekreek</p>
      <p n="73">- Oosterschelde en Roompot met inbegrip van alle vaarwateren tussen Walcheren, Noord- en Zuid-Beveland enerzijds en Schouwen-Duiveland en Tholen anderzijds</p>
      <p n="74">- Schelde</p>
      <p n="75">- Westerschelde en zijn uitmonding naar zee met inbegrip van alle vaarwateren tussen Zeeuws-Vlaanderen enerzijds en Walcheren en Zuid-Beveland anderzijds.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
