<TEI.2 id="jrc31985L0584-en" n="31985L0584" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985L0584 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 85/584/EEC of 20 December 1985 amending, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal, Directive 85/433/EEC concerning the mutual recognition of diplomas, certificates and other evidence of formal qualifications in pharmacy, including measures to facilitate the effective exercise of the right of establishment relating to certain activities in the field of pharmacy</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>11 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985L0584:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985L0584:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985L0584-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 85/584/EEC of 20 December 1985 amending, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal, Directive 85/433/EEC concerning the mutual recognition of diplomas, certificates and other evidence of formal qualifications in pharmacy, including measures to facilitate the effective exercise of the right of establishment relating to certain activities in the field of pharmacy</head>
      <p n="2">COUNCIL DIRECTIVE of 20 December 1985 amending, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal, Directive 85/433/EEC concerning the mutual recognition of diplomas, certificates and other evidence of formal qualifications in pharmacy, including measures to facilitate the effective exercise of the right of establishment relating to certain activities in the field of pharmacy (85/584/EEC)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES, Having regard to the Act of Accession of Spain and Portugal, and in particular Article 396 thereof, Whereas, on account of the accession of Spain and Portugal, it is necessary to make certain amendments to Directive 85/433/EEC (1) to ensure its equal application by the Kingdom of Spain and the Portuguese Republic and the other Member States; Whereas pursuant to Article 2 (3), of the Treaty of Accession of Spain and Portugal the institutions of the Community can adopt before accession the measures referred to in Article 396 of the Act of Accession, the measures entering into force subject to and on the date of entry into force of the said Treaty, HAD ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="4">Article 1</p>
      <p n="5">As from 1 January 1986, subject to the entry into force of the Treaty of Accession of Spain and Portugal, the following shall be added to Article 4 of Directive 85/433/EEC: '(k) in Spain: título de licenciado en farmacia (university degree in pharmacy awarded by the Ministry of Education and Science or by the universities) (l)in Portugal: Carta de curso de licenciatura em Ciências Farmacêuticas (the certificate in pharmaceutical sciences awarded by the universities).'</p>
      <p n="6">Article 2</p>
      <p n="7">The Member States shall bring into force the measures necessary to comply with this Directive within the time limit specified in Article 19 (1) of Directive 85/433/EEC.</p>
      <p n="8">Article 3</p>
      <p n="9">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="10">Done at Brussels, 20 December 1985. For the Council The President R. KRIEPS</p>
      <p n="11">(1) OJ No L 253, 24. 9. 1985, p. 37.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
