<TEI.2 id="jrc31985R2039-en" n="31985R2039" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985R2039 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 2039/85 of 23 July 1985 amending Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77 concerning the certification of hops</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>26 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985R2039:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985R2039:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985R2039-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 2039/85 of 23 July 1985 amending Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77 concerning the certification of hops</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 2039/85</p>
      <p n="4">of 23 July 1985</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77 concerning the certification of hops</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 1696/71 of 26 July 1971 on the common organization of the market in hops (1), as last amended by the 1979 Act of Accession, and in particular Article 2 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77 (2), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3041/79 (3), lays down general rules relating to certification; whereas Articles 4 and 5 of that Regulation provide that each package and certificate shall bear particulars of the variety or varieties of hop; whereas this requirement cannot be met in the case of experimental strains which must occasionally be marketed where those products are being tested on a large scale in the brewing industry; whereas there should be added to the abovementioned Regulation special provisions relating to the description of the said hops on packages and certificates,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The following Article is inserted in Regulation (EEC) No 1784/77:</p>
      <p n="15">'Article 5a</p>
      <p n="16">In the case of hops from experimental strains in the course of development and produced by a research institute on its own premises or by a producer on behalf of such an institute, particulars of the variety or varieties referred to in Article 4 (b) and Article 5 (1) (f) may be replaced by a name or number identifying the strain in question.'</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="20">Done at Brussels, 23 July 1985.</p>
      <p n="21">For the Council</p>
      <p n="22">The President</p>
      <p n="23">J. POOS</p>
      <p n="24">(1) OJ No L 175, 4. 8. 1971, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="25">(2) OJ No L 200, 8. 8. 1977, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="26">(3) OJ No L 343, 31. 12. 1979, p. 4.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
