<TEI.2 id="jrc31985L0298-en" n="31985L0298" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985L0298 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 85/298/EEC of 22 May 1985 amending for the second time the Annex to Council Directive 79/117/EEC prohibiting the placing on the market and use of plant protection products containing certain active substances</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985L0298:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985L0298:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985L0298-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 85/298/EEC of 22 May 1985 amending for the second time the Annex to Council Directive 79/117/EEC prohibiting the placing on the market and use of plant protection products containing certain active substances</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE</p>
      <p n="4">of 22 May 1985</p>
      <p n="5">amending for the second time the Annex to Council Directive 79/117/EEC prohibiting the placing on the market and use of plant protection products containing certain active substances</p>
      <p n="6">(85/298/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 79/117/EEC of 21 December 1978 prohibiting the placing on the market and use of plant protection products containing certain active substances (1), as last amended by Directive 83/131/EEC (2), and in particular Article 6 thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the development of scientific and technical knowledge makes necessary certain amendments to the Annex to Directive 79/117/EEC;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas it seems desirable to delete a certain number of temporary derogations from the prohibitions laid down in the Directive since less hazardous treatment are now available;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas all Member States have informed the Commission that they do not intend or no longer intend to avail themselves of these derogations;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plant Health,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">The Annex to Directive 79/117/EEC is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="18">1. In Part A, 'Mercury compounds':</p>
      <p n="19">(a) under item 2, 'Mercurous chloride (calomel)', the text of item (c) is deleted:</p>
      <p n="20">(b) under item 5, 'Alkoxyalkyl and aryl mercury compounds', the texts of items (a) and (b) are deleted.</p>
      <p n="21">2. In Part B, 'Persistent organo-chlorine compounds':</p>
      <p n="22">(a) under item 1, 'Aldrin', the text of item (a) is replaced by the following: 'Treatment of growing media of container-grown ornamentals against Otiorrynchus';</p>
      <p n="23">(b) under item 4, 'DDT', the text in column 2 is deleted;</p>
      <p n="24">(c) under item 5, 'Endrin':</p>
      <p n="25">(aa) the text of item (a) is replaced by the following: 'As an acaricide on cyclamen';</p>
      <p n="26">(bb) item (b) is deleted.</p>
      <p n="27">Article 2</p>
      <p n="28">Member States shall, not later than 1 January 1986, bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with this Directive. They shall immediately inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="29">Article 3</p>
      <p n="30">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="31">Done at Brussels, 22 May 1985.</p>
      <p n="32">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="33">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="34">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="35">(1) OJ No L 33, 8. 2. 1979, p. 36.</p>
      <p n="36">(2) OJ No L 91, 9. 4. 1983, p. 35.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
