<TEI.2 id="jrc31985L0326-en" n="31985L0326" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985L0326 English</title>
        <title>Council Directive 85/326/EEC of 12 June 1985 amending Directive 71/118/EEC on health problems affecting trade in fresh poultrymeat</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>36 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985L0326:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985L0326:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985L0326-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Directive 85/326/EEC of 12 June 1985 amending Directive 71/118/EEC on health problems affecting trade in fresh poultrymeat</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DIRECTIVE</p>
      <p n="4">of 12 June 1985</p>
      <p n="5">amending Directive 71/118/EEC on health problems affecting trade in fresh poultrymeat</p>
      <p n="6">(85/326/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 43 and 100 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="11">Having regard to opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="12">Having regard to the opinion of the Economic and Social Committee (3),</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas experience has shown the need to simplify Chapter III (11) of Annex I to Directive 71/118/EEC (4), as last amended by Directive 85/324/EEC (5);</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas Chapter III (12) of Annex I to Directive 71/118/EEC lays down, in particular, that a medical certificate must be required of every person working on fresh poultrymeat and that this certificate must be renewed annually;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas it appears necessary to adapt the provision in question in the light of experience,</p>
      <p n="16">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="17">Article 1</p>
      <p n="18">Directive 71/118/EEC is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="19">1. The first indent of Article 16a (b) is deleted.</p>
      <p n="20">2. Chapter III (11) and (12) of Annex I are replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="21">'11. Any person who is a possible source of contamination, in particular through pathogenic agents, shall be prohibited from working with or handling fresh poultrymeat.</p>
      <p n="22">12. Any person employed to work with or handle fresh poultrymeat shall be required to show, by a medical certificate, that there is no impediment to such employment. The medical certificate shall be renewed every year, unless another staff medical check-up scheme offering equivalent guarantees is recognized in accordance with the procedure laid down in Article 12a.'</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">The Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with this Directive not later than 1 January 1986.</p>
      <p n="25">They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="26">Article 3</p>
      <p n="27">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Luxembourg, 12 June 1985.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Council</p>
      <p n="30">The President</p>
      <p n="31">C. DEGAN</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ No C 179, 7. 7. 1984, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="33">(2) OJ No C 46, 18. 2. 1985, p. 94.</p>
      <p n="34">(3) OJ No C 44, 15. 2. 1985, p. 7.</p>
      <p n="35">(4) OJ No L 55, 8. 3. 1971, p. 23.</p>
      <p n="36">(5) See page 45 of this Official Journal.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
