<TEI.2 id="jrc31985R1554-en" n="31985R1554" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985R1554 English</title>
        <title>Council Regulation (EEC) No 1554/85 of 4 June 1985 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Government of the Republic of Seychelles on fishing off Seychelles</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>50 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985R1554:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985R1554:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985R1554-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Council Regulation (EEC) No 1554/85 of 4 June 1985 on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Government of the Republic of Seychelles on fishing off Seychelles</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL REGULATION (EEC) No 1554/85</p>
      <p n="4">of 4 June 1985</p>
      <p n="5">on the conclusion of the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Government of the Republic of Seychelles on fishing off Seychelles</p>
      <p n="6">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 43 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (1),</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas it is in the Community's interests to approve the Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Government of the Republic of Seychelles on fishing off Seychelles, signed in Brussels on 23 May 1985,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Government of the Republic of Seychelles on fishing off Seychelles is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The President of the Council shall give the notification provided for in Article 14 of the Agreement (2).</p>
      <p n="18">Article 3</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Luxembourg, 4 June 1985.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Council</p>
      <p n="23">The President</p>
      <p n="24">L. GRANELLI</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ No C 172, 2. 7. 1984, p. 144.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) The date of the entry into force of the Agreement will be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities by the General Secretariat of the Council.</p>
      <p n="27">COUNCIL REGULATION ( EEC ) NO 1554/85</p>
      <p n="28">OF 4 JUNE 1985</p>
      <p n="29">ON THE CONCLUSION OF THE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY AND THE GOVERNMENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF SEYCHELLES ON FISHING OFF SEYCHELLES</p>
      <p n="30">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="31">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="32">HAVING REGARD TO THE TREATY ESTABLISHING THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY, AND IN PARTICULAR ARTICLE 43 THEREOF,</p>
      <p n="33">HAVING REGARD TO THE PROPOSAL FROM THE COMMISSION,</p>
      <p n="34">HAVING REGARD TO THE OPINION OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT ( 1 ),</p>
      <p n="35">WHEREAS IT IS IN THE COMMUNITY'S INTERESTS TO APPROVE THE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY AND THE GOVERNMENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF SEYCHELLES ON FISHING OFF SEYCHELLES, SIGNED IN BRUSSELS ON 23 MAY 1985,</p>
      <p n="36">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION :</p>
      <p n="37">ARTICLE 1</p>
      <p n="38">THE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY AND THE GOVERNMENT OF THE REPUBLIC OF SEYCHELLES ON FISHING OFF SEYCHELLES IS HEREBY APPROVED ON BEHALF OF THE COMMUNITY .</p>
      <p n="39">THE TEXT OF THE AGREEMENT IS ATTACHED TO THIS REGULATION .</p>
      <p n="40">ARTICLE 2</p>
      <p n="41">THE PRESIDENT OF THE COUNCIL SHALL GIVE THE NOTIFICATION PROVIDED FOR IN ARTICLE 14 OF THE AGREEMENT ( 2 ).</p>
      <p n="42">ARTICLE 3</p>
      <p n="43">THIS REGULATION SHALL ENTER INTO FORCE ON THE THIRD DAY FOLLOWING ITS PUBLICATION IN THE OFFICIAL JOURNAL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES .</p>
      <p n="44">THIS REGULATION SHALL BE BINDING IN ITS ENTIRETY AND DIRECTLY APPLICABLE IN ALL MEMBER STATES .</p>
      <p n="45">DONE AT LUXEMBOURG, 4 JUNE 1985 .</p>
      <p n="46">FOR THE COUNCIL</p>
      <p n="47">THE PRESIDENT</p>
      <p n="48">L . GRANELLI</p>
      <p n="49">( 1 ) OJ NO C 172, 2 . 7 . 1984, P . 144 .</p>
      <p n="50">( 2 ) THE DATE OF THE ENTRY INTO FORCE OF THE AGREEMENT WILL BE PUBLISHED IN THE OFFICIAL JOURNAL OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES BY THE GENERAL SECRETARIAT OF THE COUNCIL .</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
