<TEI.2 id="jrc31985R3589-en" n="31985R3589" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985R3589 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3589/85 of 17 December 1985 amending certain Regulations on hops by reason of the accession of Spain and Portugal</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>35 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985R3589:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985R3589:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985R3589-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3589/85 of 17 December 1985 amending certain Regulations on hops by reason of the accession of Spain and Portugal</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 3589/85</p>
      <p n="4">of 17 December 1985</p>
      <p n="5">amending certain Regulations on hops by reason of the accession of Spain and Portugal</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Act of Accession of Spain and Portugal, and in particular Article 396 thereof,</p>
      <p n="9">Whereas, by reason of the accession of Spain and Portugal and in accordance with Article 396 of the Act of Accession, amendments should be made to the following Regulations:</p>
      <p n="10">- Regulation (EEC) No 890/78 of 28 April 1978 laying down detailed rules for the certification of hops (1), as last amended by the 1979 Act of Accession (2);</p>
      <p n="11">- Regulation (EEC) No 3077/78 of 21 December 1978 on the equivalence with Community certificates of attestations accompanying hops imported from non-member countries (3), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 541/85 (4);</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas, pursuant to Article 2 (3) of the Treaty of Accession, the institutions of the Community may adopt before accession the measures referred to in Article 396 of the Act; whereas these measures will enter into force only subject to and on the date of the entry into force of the Treaty,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 2</p>
      <p n="15">1. Regulation (EEC) No 890/78 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">- The following is added to Article 5a:</p>
      <p n="17">'- Producto certificado - Reglamento (CEE) no 890/78</p>
      <p n="18">- Producto certificado - Regulamento (CEE) no 890/78';</p>
      <p n="19">- The following is added, after the word 'Greece', to the second subparagraph of Article 6 (3): 'Spain and Portugal';</p>
      <p n="20">- The following is added, after the word 'Greece', to the second paragraph of Article 11: 'Spain and Portugal';</p>
      <p n="21">- The following are added to section 2 of Annex III:</p>
      <p n="22">'ESP for Spain'</p>
      <p n="23">'P for Portugal'.</p>
      <p n="24">2. The references to Portugal and Spain are deleted from the Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 3077/78.</p>
      <p n="25">Article 2</p>
      <p n="26">This Regulation shall enter into force on 1 March 1986, subject to the entry into force of the Treaty of Accession of Spain and Portugal.</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 17 December 1985.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">Frans ANDRIESSEN</p>
      <p n="31">Vice-President</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ No L 117, 29. 4. 1978, p. 43.</p>
      <p n="33">(2) OJ No L 291, 19. 11. 1979, p. 77.</p>
      <p n="34">(3) OJ No L 367, 28. 12. 1978, p. 28.</p>
      <p n="35">(4) OJ No L 62, 1. 3. 1985, p. 57.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
