<TEI.2 id="jrc31985D0375-en" n="31985D0375" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985D0375 English</title>
        <title>85/375/EEC: Council Decision of 25 July 1985 laying down the procedure for appointing those members of the European Foundation to be chosen by the Community</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>30 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985D0375:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985D0375:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985D0375-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">85/375/EEC: Council Decision of 25 July 1985 laying down the procedure for appointing those members of the European Foundation to be chosen by the Community</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 25 July 1985</p>
      <p n="5">laying down the procedure for appointing those members of the European Foundation to be chosen by the Community</p>
      <p n="6">(85/375/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 235 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the proposal from the Commission (1),</p>
      <p n="11">Having regard to the opinion of the European Parliament (2),</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the representatives of the Governments of the Member States, meeting within the Council, established, by an Agreement of 29 March 1982, a European Foundation;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas that Agreement provides that 10 members of the Foundation's Board may be appointed by the Community;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas a procedure should be laid down to enable this right to be exercised;</p>
      <p n="15">Whereas provision should be made for appropriate participation in the Foundation's Board by Members of the European Parliament;</p>
      <p n="16">Whereas the Treaty has not provided the specific necessary powers for this purpose,</p>
      <p n="17">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="18">Article 1</p>
      <p n="19">The members of the Board of the European Foundation for whose appointment the Community is responsible shall be appointed by the Council acting by a qualified majority, on a proposal from the Commission after consulting the European Parliament.</p>
      <p n="20">Article 2</p>
      <p n="21">In preparing its proposal, the Commission shall choose persons eminent by reason of their competence and experience. It shall ensure that the independence of the persons proposed is beyond doubt.</p>
      <p n="22">The list of names proposed shall include those of Members of the European Parliament.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 3</p>
      <p n="24">This Decision shall take effect on the date on which the Agreement establishing the European Foundation enters into force.</p>
      <p n="25">Done at Brussels, 25 July 1985.</p>
      <p n="26">For the Council</p>
      <p n="27">The President</p>
      <p n="28">J. POOS</p>
      <p n="29">(1) OJ No C 112, 7. 5. 1985, p. 4.</p>
      <p n="30">(2) Opinion delivered on 12 July 1985 (not yet published in the Official Journal).</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
