<TEI.2 id="jrc31985D0424-en" n="31985D0424" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31985D0424 English</title>
        <title>85/424/EEC: Council Decision of 26 March 1985 on the application of the International Agreement on Tropical Timber 1983</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>24 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985D0424:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31985D0424:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31985D0424-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">85/424/EEC: Council Decision of 26 March 1985 on the application of the International Agreement on Tropical Timber 1983</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 26 March 1985</p>
      <p n="5">on the application of the International Agreement on Tropical Timber 1983</p>
      <p n="6">(85/424/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Articles 113 and 116 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the International Agreement on Tropical Timber 1983 was signed by the Community and its Member States on 29 June 1984;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas application of the Agreement presupposes both measures by the Community and joint measures by its Member States,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Community and its Member States hereby state that they intend to apply the International Agreement on Tropical Timber 1983, in accordance with Articles 34 or 36 thereof, when the Agreement comes into force pursuant to Article 37 thereof.</p>
      <p n="16">The Community will apply the Agreement provisionally.</p>
      <p n="17">Article 2</p>
      <p n="18">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to deposit this notification of provisional application on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="19">Article 3</p>
      <p n="20">This Decision shall be published in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 26 March 1985.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Council</p>
      <p n="23">The President</p>
      <p n="24">F. M. PANDOLFI</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
