<TEI.2 id="jrc21982A0607_01-en" n="21982A0607(01)" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 21982A0607(01) English</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21982A0607(01):en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:21982A0607(01):en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc21982A0607_01-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <p n="2">COOPERATION AGREEMENT between the Council of Arab Economic Unity (CAEU) and the European Communities (82/726/ECSC, EEC, Euratom)</p>
      <p n="3">THE COUNCIL OF ARAB ECONOMIC UNITY,</p>
      <p n="4">(hereinafter referred to as the Council) represented by its Secretary-General,</p>
      <p n="5">and</p>
      <p n="6">THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="7">represented by the President of their Commission,</p>
      <p n="8">AWARE of the need for effective and positive participation in developing and improving the relations among organizations which have competence in the field of economic development,</p>
      <p n="9">DESIROUS of making every effort to coordinate their activities to serve the common interests of the two Parties,</p>
      <p n="10">HAVE AGREED UPON THE FOLLOWING:</p>
      <p n="11">Article I</p>
      <p n="12">The General Secretariat of the Council and the Commission of the European Communities will provide each other with such studies, documents and information as are available for distribution within the framework of their cooperation on matters of common interest.</p>
      <p n="13">Article II</p>
      <p n="14">The General Secretariat of the Council and the Commission of the European Communities will send experts, at appropriate intervals, to provide their expertise and experience, and to participate in seminars of common interest in order to share the benefits of their respective experience in practical fields.</p>
      <p n="15">Article III</p>
      <p n="16">The General Secretariat of the Council and the Commission of the European Communities will invite each other to attend meetings which may be of special interest.</p>
      <p n="17">Article IV</p>
      <p n="18">The General Secretariat of the Council and the Commission of the European Communities will keep each other informed of on-going and planned programmes on matters of common interest.</p>
      <p n="19">Article V</p>
      <p n="20">This Agreement is valid for five years from the date of the signature, and will be renewed automatically for a similar period of time, unless either Party expresses, by written notice, its decision to terminate it six months before its expiry.</p>
      <p n="21">Article VI</p>
      <p n="22">The provisions of the Agreement may be amended and revised as a whole or in detail by common agreement between the two Parties.</p>
      <p n="23">Article VII</p>
      <p n="24">This Agreement shall enter into force upon signature by the Secretary-General of the Council of Arab Economic Unity, and by the President of the Commission of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="25">Article VIII</p>
      <p n="26">This Agreement is done in two originals, in Arabic and English, both texts being equally authentic.</p>
      <p n="27">Done at Brussels, 7 June 1982. &gt;PIC FILE= "T0022651"&gt;</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
