<TEI.2 id="jrc31982L0331-en" n="31982L0331" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31982L0331 English</title>
        <title>Commission Directive 82/331/EEC of 6 May 1982 amending Council Directive 68/193/EEC on the marketing of material for the vegetative propagation of the vine</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982L0331:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982L0331:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31982L0331-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Directive 82/331/EEC of 6 May 1982 amending Council Directive 68/193/EEC on the marketing of material for the vegetative propagation of the vine</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION DIRECTIVE</p>
      <p n="4">of 6 May 1982</p>
      <p n="5">amending Council Directive 68/193/EEC on the marketing of material for the vegetative propagation of the vine</p>
      <p n="6">(82/331/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to Council Directive 68/193/EEC of 9 April 1968 on the marketing of material for the vegetative propagation of the vine (1), as last amended by Directive 78/692/EEC (2), and in particular Article 17a thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the abovementioned Directive lays down conditions concerning the packaging of propagating material;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the appearance on the market of new types of packaging permits a relaxation of the said conditions while at the same time maintaining the requisite guarantees of identity;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the conditions in question should therefore be adapted to the new situation;</p>
      <p n="14">Whereas the measures provided for in this Directive are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Seeds and Propagating Material for Agriculture, Horticulture and Forestry,</p>
      <p n="15">HAS ADOPTED THIS DIRECTIVE:</p>
      <p n="16">Article 1</p>
      <p n="17">Directive 68/193/EEC is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="18">1. In point 1 of the table at Annex III, the following words shall be added:</p>
      <p n="19">'or, where plastic bags of equivalent packages are used, 50 or 100, it being understood that the provisions of Article 10 (1a) do not apply thereto'.</p>
      <p n="20">2. In point 2 of the table at Annex III, the following words shall be added:</p>
      <p n="21">'or, where plastic bags of equivalent packages are used, 100, it being understood that the provisions of Article 10 (1a) do not apply thereto'.</p>
      <p n="22">Article 2</p>
      <p n="23">Member States shall bring into force the laws, regulations and administrative provisions necessary to comply with this Directive on 1 July 1982. They shall forthwith inform the Commission thereof.</p>
      <p n="24">Article 3</p>
      <p n="25">This Directive is addressed to the Member States.</p>
      <p n="26">Done at Brussels, 6 May 1982.</p>
      <p n="27">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="28">Poul DALSAGER</p>
      <p n="29">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">(1) OJ No L 93, 17. 4. 1968, p. 15.</p>
      <p n="31">(2) OJ No L 236, 26. 8. 1978, p. 13.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
