<TEI.2 id="jrc31982D0495-en" n="31982D0495" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31982D0495 English</title>
        <title>82/495/EEC: Council Decision of 19 July 1982 on the conclusion of a Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>21 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982D0495:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982D0495:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31982D0495-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">82/495/EEC: Council Decision of 19 July 1982 on the conclusion of a Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COUNCIL DECISION</p>
      <p n="4">of 19 July 1982</p>
      <p n="5">on the conclusion of a Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade</p>
      <p n="6">(82/495/EEC)</p>
      <p n="7">THE COUNCIL OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="8">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community, and in particular Article 113 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Having regard to the recommendation from the Commission,</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the conclusion of a Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade is in their mutual interest,</p>
      <p n="12">HAS DECIDED AS FOLLOWS:</p>
      <p n="13">Article 1</p>
      <p n="14">The Cooperation Agreement between the European Economic Community and the Kingdom of Thailand on manioc production, marketing and trade is hereby approved on behalf of the Community.</p>
      <p n="15">The text of the Agreement is attached to this Decision.</p>
      <p n="16">Article 2</p>
      <p n="17">The President of the Council is hereby authorized to designate the person empowered to sign the Agreement in order to bind the Community.</p>
      <p n="18">Done at Brussels, 19 July 1982.</p>
      <p n="19">For the Council</p>
      <p n="20">The President</p>
      <p n="21">K. OLESEN</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
