<TEI.2 id="jrc31982R0752-en" n="31982R0752" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31982R0752 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 752/82 of 31 March 1982 amending Regulation (EEC) No 32/82 laying down the conditions for granting special export refunds for beef and vealt</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>31 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R0752:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R0752:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31982R0752-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 752/82 of 31 March 1982 amending Regulation (EEC) No 32/82 laying down the conditions for granting special export refunds for beef and vealt</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 752/82</p>
      <p n="4">of 31 March 1982</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 32/82 laying down the conditions for granting special export refunds for beef and veal</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 805/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in beef and veal (1), as last amended by the Act of Accession of Greece, and in particular Article 18 (6) thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 32/82 (2) defined the conditions for granting special export refunds for beef and veal;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas some errors in the German version of the abovementioned Regulation, and in the Annex thereto, should be corrected;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the procedure whereby Member States are to inform the Commission of the quantities of products for which special export refunds have been granted should be laid down;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Beef and Veal,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">Regulation (EEC) No 32/82 is hereby amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="17">1. The German version of Article 2 (2) shall be replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="18">'(2) Dieser Nachweis wird durch eine Bescheinigung gemaess dem im Anhang beigefuegten Muster erbracht, die auf Antrag des Beteiligten von der Interventionsstelle oder einer anderen Stelle ausgestellt wird, welche von dem Mitgliedstaat, in dem die Tiere geschlachtet wurden und in dem die Ausfuhrzollfoermlichkeiten erfuellt werden, hierfuer bestimmt wird. Diese Bescheinigung ist den Zollbehoerden bei der Erfuellung der Ausfuhrzollfoermlichkeiten zu uebergeben.'</p>
      <p n="19">2. The following Article 4a shall be inserted:</p>
      <p n="20">'Article 4a</p>
      <p n="21">The Member States shall communicate to the Commission by telex before the 25th day of each month the quantities and, as far as possible, the descriptions of the products for which either a special refund was paid or advance payment thereof was made under Article 25 of Regulation (EEC) No 2730/79 during the previous month on the basis of the certificates.'</p>
      <p n="22">3. The Annex shall be replaced by the Annex to this Regulation.</p>
      <p n="23">Article 2</p>
      <p n="24">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="26">Done at Brussels, 31 March 1982.</p>
      <p n="27">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="28">Poul DALSAGER</p>
      <p n="29">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 24.</p>
      <p n="31">(2) OJ No L 4. 8. 1. 1982, p. 11.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
