<TEI.2 id="jrc31982R3397-en" n="31982R3397" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31982R3397 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3397/82 of 17 December 1982 altering the procedure for the submission of applications for aid from the Guidance Section of the EAGGF for projects or special programmes</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>51 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R3397:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R3397:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31982R3397-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3397/82 of 17 December 1982 altering the procedure for the submission of applications for aid from the Guidance Section of the EAGGF for projects or special programmes</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 3397/82</p>
      <p n="4">of 17 December 1982</p>
      <p n="5">altering the procedure for the submission of applications for aid from the Guidance Section of the EAGGF for projects or special programmes</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulations:</p>
      <p n="10">- (EEC) No 355/77 of 15 February 1977 on common measures to improve the conditions under which agricultural products are processed and marketed (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3509/80 (2), and in particular Article 13 (5) thereof,</p>
      <p n="11">- (EEC) No 1362/78 of 19 June 1978 on the programme for the acceleration and guidance of collective irrigation works in the Mezzogiorno (3), and in particular Article 8 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="12">- (EEC) No 1760/78 of 25 July 1978 on a common measure to improve public amenities in certain rural areas (4), and in particular Article 8 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="13">- (EEC) No 269/79 of 6 February 1979 establishing a common measure for forestry in certain Mediterranean zones of the Community (5), and in particular Article 8 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="14">- (EEC) No 458/80 of 18 February 1980 on collective projects for the restructuring of vineyards (6), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2991/81 (7), and in particular Article 6 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="15">- (EEC) No 1938/81 of 30 June 1981 on a common measure to improve public amenities in certain less-favoured agricultural areas of the Federal Republic of Germany (8), and in particular Article 8 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="16">Whereas the procedure laid down by the Commission for the submission of applications for aid from the EAGGF Guidance Section:</p>
      <p n="17">- in Regulation (EEC) No 219/78 (9) in respect of projects to improve the conditions under which agricultural products are processed and marketed,</p>
      <p n="18">- in Regulation (EEC) No 692/80 (10) in respect of special collective irrigation programmes in the Mezzogiorno,</p>
      <p n="19">- in Regulation (EEC) No 2467/79 (11) in respect of projects to improve infrastructure in certain rural areas,</p>
      <p n="20">- in Regulation (EEC) No 2468/79 (12) in respect of special forestry programmes in certain Mediterranean zones of the Community,</p>
      <p n="21">- in Regulation (EEC) No 1679/81 (13) in respect of collective projects for the restructuring of vineyards,</p>
      <p n="22">- in Regulation (EEC) No 289/82 (14) in respect of projects to improve infrastructure in certain less-favoured agricultural areas of the Federal Republic of Germany,</p>
      <p n="23">provides for applications to be submitted in triplicate and in the form indicated in Annexes A and B to the said Regulations;</p>
      <p n="24">Whereas, as a result of the reorganization of the departments responsible, two complete copies and a third copy of Annex A are henceforth sufficient to enable the cases to be examined; whereas the procedure should be altered accordingly;</p>
      <p n="25">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Agricultural Structure;</p>
      <p n="26">Whereas the EAGGF Committee has been consulted on the financial aspects of these measures,</p>
      <p n="27">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="28">Article 1</p>
      <p n="29">In Regulations (EEC) No 219/78, (EEC) No 2467/79, (EEC) No 2468/79, (EEC) No 692/80, (EEC) No 1679/81 and (EEC) No 289/82 Article 2 (2) is hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="30">'2. Applications shall be submitted in the form indicated in the Annexes. Two full copies must be submitted, together with an extra copy of Annex A.'</p>
      <p n="31">Article 2</p>
      <p n="32">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="33">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="34">Done at Brussels, 17 December 1982.</p>
      <p n="35">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="36">Poul DALSAGER</p>
      <p n="37">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="38">(1) OJ No L 51, 23. 2. 1977, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="39">(2) OJ No L 367, 31. 12. 1980, p. 87.</p>
      <p n="40">(3) OJ No L 166, 19. 6. 1978, p. 11.</p>
      <p n="41">(4) OJ No L 204, 28. 7. 1978, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="42">(5) OJ No L 38, 14. 2. 1979, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="43">(6) OJ No L 57, 29. 2. 1980, p. 27.</p>
      <p n="44">(7) OJ No L 299, 20. 10. 1981, p. 21.</p>
      <p n="45">(8) OJ No L 197, 20. 7. 1981, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="46">(9) OJ No L 35, 4. 2. 1978, p. 10.</p>
      <p n="47">(10) OJ No L 80, 26. 3. 1980, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="48">(11) OJ No L 286, 14. 11. 1979, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="49">(12) OJ No L 286, 14. 11. 1979, p. 14.</p>
      <p n="50">(13) OJ No L 171, 27. 6. 1981, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="51">(14) OJ No L 36, 9. 2. 1982, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
