<TEI.2 id="jrc31982R3272-en" n="31982R3272" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31982R3272 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3272/82 of 6 December 1982 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2237/77 on the form of farm return to be used for the purpose of determining incomes of agricultural holdings</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>35 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R3272:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R3272:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31982R3272-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 3272/82 of 6 December 1982 amending Regulation (EEC) No 2237/77 on the form of farm return to be used for the purpose of determining incomes of agricultural holdings</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 3272/82</p>
      <p n="4">of 6 December 1982</p>
      <p n="5">amending Regulation (EEC) No 2237/77 on the form of farm return to be used for the purpose of determining incomes of agricultural holdings</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation No 79/65/EEC of 15 June 1965 setting up a network for the collection of accountancy data on the incomes and business operation of agricultural holdings in the European Economic Community (1), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 2143/81 (2), and in particular Article 7 thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2237/77 (3) specified the items to be included in the farm return to be used in determining the incomes of agricultural holdings;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas the data collected by means of the farm return must correspond to the definition given in the Community rules, and in particular those given in Council Directive 75/268/EEC of 28 April 1975 on mountain and hill farming and farming in certain less-favoured areas (4);</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas no changes should be made to the form of the farm return;</p>
      <p n="13">Whereas the measures provides for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Community Committee for the Farm Accountancy Data Network,</p>
      <p n="14">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="15">Article 1</p>
      <p n="16">The definitions and instructions relating to the farm return which figure in heading '6. Less-favoured area' in Annex II, Chapter II, Part A of Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2237/77 are hereby replaced by the following:</p>
      <p n="17">'6. Less-favoured area</p>
      <p n="18">An indication is to be given of whether the majority of the agricultural area of the holding is situated in an area covered by Council Directive 75/268/EEC on mountain and hill farming and farming in certain less-favoured areas (1).</p>
      <p n="19">1 = the majority of the agricultural area of the holding is not situated in the areas in question,</p>
      <p n="20">2 = the majority of the agricultural area of the holding is situated in less-favoured areas within the meaning of Article 3 (4) and (5) of Directive 75/268/EEC,</p>
      <p n="21">3 = the majority of the agricultural area of the holding is situated in mountain areas within the meaning of Article 3 (3) of Directive 75/268/EEC,</p>
      <p n="22">4 = Code 4 is to be used in Member States where such areas are so small and numerous that the information is not significant.</p>
      <p n="23">(1) OJ No L 128, 19. 5. 1975, p. 1.'</p>
      <p n="24">Article 2</p>
      <p n="25">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="26">It shall apply with effect from the 1983/84 accounting year.</p>
      <p n="27">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="28">Done at Brussels, 6 December 1982.</p>
      <p n="29">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="30">Poul DALSAGER</p>
      <p n="31">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="32">(1) OJ No 109, 23. 6. 1965, p. 1859/65.</p>
      <p n="33">(2) OJ No L 210, 30. 7. 1981, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="34">(3) OJ No L 263, 17. 10. 1977, p. 1.</p>
      <p n="35">(4) OJ No L 128, 19. 5. 1975, p. 1.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
