<TEI.2 id="jrc31982R0384-en" n="31982R0384" lang="en">
  <teiHeader lang="en" date.created="2006-05-14">
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>JRC-ACQUIS 31982R0384 English</title>
        <title>Commission Regulation (EEC) No 384/82 of 17 February 1982 amending for the third time Regulation (EEC) No 2730/81 establishing a list of agencies in non-member importing countries entitled to issue invitations to tender in the milk and milk products sector</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>27 paragraph segments</extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>
          <xref url="http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/">http://wt.jrc.it/lt/acquis/</xref>
        </distributor>
      </publicationStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>Only European Community legislation printed in the paper
            edition of the Official Journal of the European Union is deemed authentic.</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Downloaded from <xref url="http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R0384:en:HTML">http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31982R0384:en:HTML</xref> on <date>2006-02-22</date></bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text id="jrc31982R0384-en." lang="en">
    <body>
      <head n="1">Commission Regulation (EEC) No 384/82 of 17 February 1982 amending for the third time Regulation (EEC) No 2730/81 establishing a list of agencies in non-member importing countries entitled to issue invitations to tender in the milk and milk products sector</head>
      <p n="2">*****</p>
      <p n="3">COMMISSION REGULATION (EEC) No 384/82</p>
      <p n="4">of 17 February 1982</p>
      <p n="5">amending for the third time Regulation (EEC) No 2730/81 establishing a list of agencies in non-member importing countries entitled to issue invitations to tender in the milk and milk products sector</p>
      <p n="6">THE COMMISSION OF THE EUROPEAN</p>
      <p n="7">COMMUNITIES,</p>
      <p n="8">Having regard to the Treaty establishing the European Economic Community,</p>
      <p n="9">Having regard to Council Regulation (EEC) No 804/68 of 27 June 1968 on the common organization of the market in milk and milk products (1), as last amended by the Act of Accession of Greece, and in particular Articles 13 (3) and 17 (4) thereof,</p>
      <p n="10">Whereas Commission Regulation (EEC) No 2730/81 (2), as last amended by Regulation (EEC) No 3756/81 (3), established a list of agencies in non-member importing countries entitled to issue invitations to tender in the milk and milk products sector;</p>
      <p n="11">Whereas in the light of the most recent information available to the Commission on the trade practices followed by the importing countries concerned and the official nature of the agencies in question, this Regulation should be amended;</p>
      <p n="12">Whereas the measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Management Committee for Milk and Milk Products,</p>
      <p n="13">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</p>
      <p n="14">Article 1</p>
      <p n="15">The Annex to Regulation (EEC) No 2730/81 is amended as follows:</p>
      <p n="16">The list of issuing organizations should be completed by addition of the following organizations, insertion being made in the alphabetical order of the importing country:</p>
      <p n="17">1.2 // Importing country // Issuing organization // Taiwan // Taiwan Supply Bureau 46 Kuan-Chien Road, 6th and 7th floor Taipei Taiwan // Iran // Food Procurement and Distribution Centre (FPDC) 169 West Apadana Avenue Teheran Iranian Pharmaceuticals Inc. (IPI) 32 Tohid Avenue Teheran</p>
      <p n="18">Article 2</p>
      <p n="19">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following its publication in the Official Journal of the European Communities.</p>
      <p n="20">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</p>
      <p n="21">Done at Brussels, 17 February 1982.</p>
      <p n="22">For the Commission</p>
      <p n="23">Poul DALSAGER</p>
      <p n="24">Member of the Commission</p>
      <p n="25">(1) OJ No L 148, 28. 6. 1968, p. 13.</p>
      <p n="26">(2) OJ No L 272, 26. 9. 1981, p. 25.</p>
      <p n="27">(3) OJ No L 374, 22. 12. 1981, p. 20.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>
